<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Adam Israel</title>
    <link>http://adamisrael.com/categories/personal/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Adam Israel</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© 2016 Adam Israel</copyright>
    <atom:link href="http://adamisrael.com/categories/personal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>the authenticity of grief</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/2016/10/24/the-authenticity-of-grief/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2016 08:18:33 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/2016/10/24/the-authenticity-of-grief/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I still hear his voice, almost a decade since we last spoke. Sometimes, I imagine it&amp;rsquo;s over the airwaves of amateur radio, an interest he rekindled and mentored me in. We come across each other by chance, calling out into the darkness for another soul to connect with, and pick up the pieces of what we once had, one tiny hurt at a time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reality sets in, and I remember the hard lesson: time does not heal all wounds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a truth I&amp;rsquo;ve learned, on more than one occasion, that never gets easier to bear. Two people entwined can grow apart and not realize &amp;ndash; or accept &amp;ndash; it until near the very end. When that schism rips them apart, there is unavoidable and certain collateral damage to all around them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mutual friends choose sides more often than striking a balance. Inherited family members revoke the bond that once made you kin. Words and actions are cutting, brutal, and without remorse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What follows is a kind of grief that can last a lifetime. You nurse that pain along, indulging in it once in a while if only to quell its discontent for a time. Occasionally you reach out, via email to minimize the risk of hearing the anger in their voice, but the tone of their response is enough: you are not one of us, you were never one of us, you are no one to us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually word comes, through word of mouth or printed in the black and white text of the local newspaper, that there is no chance of reconciliation nor hope for forgiveness. Death is final.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The grief I feel for the man who was once a father to me is harsh. It brings with it a pain I wasn&amp;rsquo;t prepared for. And yet, I feel guilt for experiencing it. I am an outsider; a blemish of history. Their grief is real and immediate while mine is an echo of the past that was; a timeline in which I no longer exist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would love to tell them I&amp;rsquo;m sorry, and that I share in their pain, but much like the theories of relativity and quantum mechanics, both griefs are true but diminish each other. Nothing I can do or say can express the sorrow that I feel; to do so would be to sow anger in the fields in which they now reap their grief. Instead, I&amp;rsquo;ll find a way to celebrate and honor that life, making sure that the memories of him that I cherish carry forward.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>American Serenade</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2015/07/06/american-serenade/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2015/07/06/american-serenade/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Back in 2009, we were winding down our life in the U.S.. We drastically culled things we didn&amp;#8217;t want or need, and put the rest into storage for the eventual move to Canada.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Andrea was home in August 2009; I was there on and off, until I was officially issued a visitor record in November 2010 and filed for permanent resident status. On that day, I entered the country with one large suitcase and a backpack containing some notebooks and my laptop. That&amp;#8217;s it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This weekend, my brother-in-law and I had an epic 30 hour adventure: driving a U-Haul cargo van on a round-trip from Ontario to Aurora, IL and back. Our choice of weekend was suspect from the start; most people thought it was crazy to do this on a weekend when terror alerts were escalated and traffic was sure to be horrible, but I had a plan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We crossed the border Friday night around 9:30. It was John&amp;#8217;s first time in the states, and he was greeted almost immediately by fireworks, like a dignitary being being greeted with festivities. After a minor detour that almost put us in Toledo, OH, we were back on schedule, driving across Michigan. Traffic was light, only hindered by various police-directed road closures. We got to my mom&amp;#8217;s place around 4AM, and were back out the door around 9:30.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;d done some research on bringing our stuff back to Canada. By all accounts, a straightforward task. We unpacked almost everything in the storage unit, numbering the boxes and documenting their contents in a notebook. It was a lot of work on a sunny July day. I wore a tube sock as a bandana, to keep the sweat from my eyes, and we drank so much water that I had to run for refills at one point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Andrea was pretty skeptical that we&amp;#8217;d be able to fit everything into the cargo van, but it was exponentially more expensive to rent and drive a larger truck that far. Sure enough, we fit everything in the truck, minus bed linens that didn&amp;#8217;t fit any bed we own and a few other things that had long since been replaced.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was about 4pm by the time we left the storage unit. I did what any good host would do and continued giving John a tour of the things Andrea and I were used to. A trip to the massive warehouse that is Woodman Food (part of the side-quest to find Vanilla Coke), and then a winding trek through downtown Aurora and the suburbs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our wanderings were accompanied by fireworks in every direction, from Aurora to the Indiana border. A good and proper showing for anyone&amp;#8217;s first visit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another side-quest was to introduce him to as many different foods as possible, and specifically from places we couldn&amp;#8217;t find in Ontario. Considering the short time we had, we focused on smaller meals. A Steak &amp;#8216;n Shake at midnight, so busy that we had to wait for a table. IHOP, which despite international being in its name is far from it. Portillo&amp;#8217;s for lunch; nothing beats a hot dog and cheese fries. Sonic for a drink and tater tot snack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So it comes to the accounting of things; the detritus of a life lived in privilege.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of the boxes we hauled were full of books. Reference books, text books, hard cover and paperback books, some of which I acquired in my early teens. Books by my instructors at Clarion 2010, and a few spoils from Comic Con San Diego that same year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All sorts of miscellanea; ham radios to tools to crochet and quilted blankets. Cookware. Clothes. LEGO, Star Trek models, my childhood (and not so childhood) Transformer toys, and more nerdy/geeky knickknacks than anyone has a right to. Also, sixteen short boxes of comic books.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I even found a 20+ year old model of a Klingon &lt;em&gt;Bird of Prey&lt;/em&gt;, which we put on the dashboard as a sort of mascot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clearly, we are adult-sized children with a love for the fantastic. Which saved our asses when we reached the Canadian border.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apparently, I was supposed to have filed a B-4 form when I landed in Canada in late 2010, documenting what I was bringing with me and what I would be bringing over at some future date. No one informed me of this, and as a result, we faced paying import duties on everything brought with us, as if it were new.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We pulled in for secondary inspection around 3:30AM. Four officers approach, one to my open window. He reiterates the issue of not having filed a B-4, and the potentially heavy penalty. And then things got interesting. At mention of the comic books, he asked which series we had. And then what series of fantasy novel. And which generation of Transformers toys, and US or Japanese issue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This went on for ten minutes, an exploration of genre cornucopia. And then the strangest thing happened. The guard that initially met us in secondary exception says, &amp;#8220;Ok, that&amp;#8217;s enough. You win,&amp;#8221; and we were sent on our way. No duties. No fines. Just relief that this adventure was coming to a close.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;#8217;re home now, with boxes filling our dining and living room. We&amp;#8217;ll be spending the rest of the month unpacking and figuring out where to put all this stuff. A minor collection of the best of our childhood (and later) memorabilia. Forgotten memories of good and bad times. And another to-read pile to add to the existing one. &lt;strong&gt;Shit&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All kidding aside, this was one of the best experiences. A road trip, with all of that entails (including a minor brush with the police in Michigan because I forgot to use a turn signal on an otherwise empty street), with someone I genuinely consider to be a friend. A massive item removed from the TODO list and the erasure of a constant stress of &amp;#8220;what if&amp;#8221; with most of our worldly belongings a country and three states away.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The doppelgänger effect</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2015/03/29/the-doppelganger-effect/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2015/03/29/the-doppelganger-effect/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday was a travel day, coming home from a week in Breckenridge, CO for a work sprint. These are usually uneventful days, riding trains or shuttles to and from airports. Yesterday was different, though. Yesterday, I ran into my doppelgänger.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first indication that something was off was when I checked my bag curbside. The porter asked me if I&amp;#8217;d already checked a bag. I said no, and he gestured me to come around the counter and see what he was seeing. Sure enough, there was my name, showing one back checked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I assumed it was because I&amp;#8217;d checked-in online and paid the baggage fee, and said as much. We figured it was just some kind of oddity and carried on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Grabbing a bite to eat inside the terminal, I noticed the second oddity. The boarding pass the porter handed me listed seat 6C, but the Delta app showed me in seat 18F. I thought maybe it was just a lag in my information being updated since arriving at the airport, but no. The app updated to show my gate information, but I was still in 18F.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point, I was pretty convinced that, despite the odds, there was another Adam Israel was on the flight; I had his bordering pass and he had my luggage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fast forward a couple hours (because we were there way early), I talk to the agent at the gate. She becomes apologetic very quickly, mentioning that this happened to her with a passenger last week as well, and confirms that I did have the wrong bordering pass. She makes sure that the other me&amp;#8217;s final destination is the same as mine, and it is, so no luggage juggling has to be done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;#8217;s the thing: I cleared security with someone else&amp;#8217;s boarding pass. I had identification with my photo on it, but the boarding pass I presented wasn&amp;#8217;t mine. Think about that. It&amp;#8217;s a potentially serious lapse in security.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everything worked out fine in the end. I saw (but didn&amp;#8217;t get a chance to talk to) another Adam Israel. I got my luggage, and even caught a shuttle home three hours earlier than scheduled. I can&amp;#8217;t help but wonder, though, what could happen if someone not as honest, with not so good intentions, could clear security at an airport simply by sharing a name with another passenger.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New job!</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2014/08/25/new-job/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2014/08/25/new-job/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am delighted &amp;#8212; tickled, in fact &amp;#8212; to report that as of last Monday I am employed by &lt;a href=&#34;1&#34;&gt;Canonical&lt;/a&gt;, the company behind &lt;a href=&#34;2&#34;&gt;Ubuntu&lt;/a&gt; Linux.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve joined the Ecosystem Engineering team, part of Cloud Development and Operations, as a software engineer. More specifically, I&amp;#8217;m working on &lt;a href=&#34;3&#34;&gt;Juju&lt;/a&gt;, the cloud orchestration tool chain. I&amp;#8217;ll be writing &lt;a href=&#34;4&#34;&gt;charms&lt;/a&gt; and documentation, working on optimizations, and helping to make a cool product even cooler.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>111 Weeks</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2013/09/19/111-weeks/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2013/09/19/111-weeks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;To be exact, it&amp;#8217;s been 783 days since we filed for my Canadian Permanent Residence and I am happy to announce that it is official done. We have just walked out of the Immigration Centre in Windsor, Ontario, Social Insurance Number in hand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess this makes me an expatriate; an American Citizen permanently living abroad, which is kind of cool. I&amp;#8217;ve been thinking a lot about getting a tattoo to commemorate the experience. More on that later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;#8217;s been a lot of stress involved around this process, most notably the difficulty traveling back to the US. In a few weeks, when I have the official card in hand, I&amp;#8217;ll be free to cross the border without fear of being turned away and having to restart the immigration process. That&amp;#8217;s going to be a cathartic experience, finally going back to visit my family and friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that I&amp;#8217;m all official, we can start thinking about normal, grown-up things like buying a house, and getting all of our stuff out of storage back in Illinois.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Month of Letters</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2013/01/29/a-month-of-letters/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2013/01/29/a-month-of-letters/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;1&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34; wp-image-867 alignright&#34; alt=&#34;LetterMo2013square-300x300&#34; src=&#34;http://www.adamisrael.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/01/LetterMo2013square-300x300.jpg&#34; width=&#34;210&#34; height=&#34;210&#34; srcset=&#34;//www.adamisrael.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/01/LetterMo2013square-300x300-150x150.jpg 150w, //www.adamisrael.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/01/LetterMo2013square-300x300.jpg 300w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 210px) 100vw, 210px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;2&#34;&gt;Mary Robinette Kowal&lt;/a&gt; started a delightful challenge, in 2010, to go correspond via letter for an entire month. That has grown to become &lt;a href=&#34;3&#34;&gt;A Month of Letters&lt;/a&gt;, which runs for the whole of February. During the next month, I and the other 6,000 people who&amp;#8217;ve signed up to participate will be writing letters, post cards, and doing other creative things and dropping them into the mail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love to write longhand, and this gives me a wonderful reason to do so. That&amp;#8217;s where you come in. I&amp;#8217;m looking for more people to write to &amp;#8212; the more the merrier. If you would like to receive a genuine, hand-written letter from yours truly, send me your address. Email me, message me on &lt;a href=&#34;4&#34;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;5&#34;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;, or use my &lt;a href=&#34;6&#34;&gt;contact form&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is an opportunity to rekindle friendships and make new ones, without the limitations of Twitter or the haste of email. Let&amp;#8217;s write!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two years and pocket change</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2012/11/26/two-years-and-pocket-change/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2012/11/26/two-years-and-pocket-change/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Two years and two days ago, I started a journey from Santa Monica, California by foot, bus, train, and plane. Many hours later, I reached Detroit and was met by my friend Katni, who drove me through the Detroit-Windsor tunnel where, six months after being kicked out, I re-entered Canada and was reunited with Andrea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being home still feels really good.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Independence</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2012/07/05/independence/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2012/07/05/independence/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday was Independence Day back in the states. We already had our fireworks over the weekend, and I worked through Canada Day on Monday and had yesterday off instead. Among the joys of American/Canada relations are mixed holidays.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our plans were a little more focused. Yesterday we saw an apartment, and made a deposit, and transfered utilities to our name. This was kind of a big deal, because for the first time in more than three years, we&amp;#8217;re in a position to start a new chapter in our lives. We left our house in May 2009 to stay with my Dad and help him recover with his surgery. We came to Ontario the following August and moved in with Andrea&amp;#8217;s Mom. Then there was that six month&amp;#8217;s being kicked out of the country thing. All told, we haven&amp;#8217;t lived together and alone for over three years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s about damn time. We pick up the keys today and I can&amp;#8217;t wait to feel the weight of them in my pocket. It&amp;#8217;s a burden of responsibility I&amp;#8217;ve been missing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;#8217;re going to be close enough to still help out Andrea&amp;#8217;s mom. We&amp;#8217;re in an even smaller town then we&amp;#8217;ve been in, but we still have a 24 hour coffee shop and the library, while tiny, is right across the street. It&amp;#8217;s a three bedroom downstairs apartment with a small fenced-in back yard for the dogs. Internet&amp;#8217;s already ordered. Now we need to get ourselves appliances and furniture. Priorities, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Andrea has some pretty cool ideas about how to arrange things and I can&amp;#8217;t wait to show off the place once we get it all furnished. It&amp;#8217;s going to be an awesome creative space.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>