<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Personal on Adam Israel</title>
    <link>http://adamisrael.com/categories/personal/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Personal on Adam Israel</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© 2016 Adam Israel</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 May 2017 10:14:18 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://adamisrael.com/categories/personal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>ubuntu</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/tech/ubuntu/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2017 10:14:18 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/tech/ubuntu/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>juju</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/tech/juju/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2017 10:14:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/tech/juju/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>snap</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/tech/snap/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2017 10:14:01 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/tech/snap/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>lxd</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/tech/lxd/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2017 10:13:57 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/tech/lxd/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>index</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/tech/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2017 10:13:54 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/tech/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>rpi</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/tech/rpi/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2017 10:13:50 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/tech/rpi/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>American Serenade</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2015/07/06/american-serenade/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2015/07/06/american-serenade/</guid>
      <description>Back in 2009, we were winding down our life in the U.S.. We drastically culled things we didn&amp;#8217;t want or need, and put the rest into storage for the eventual move to Canada.
Andrea was home in August 2009; I was there on and off, until I was officially issued a visitor record in November 2010 and filed for permanent resident status. On that day, I entered the country with one large suitcase and a backpack containing some notebooks and my laptop.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The doppelgänger effect</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2015/03/29/the-doppelganger-effect/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2015/03/29/the-doppelganger-effect/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday was a travel day, coming home from a week in Breckenridge, CO for a work sprint. These are usually uneventful days, riding trains or shuttles to and from airports. Yesterday was different, though. Yesterday, I ran into my doppelgänger.
The first indication that something was off was when I checked my bag curbside. The porter asked me if I&amp;#8217;d already checked a bag. I said no, and he gestured me to come around the counter and see what he was seeing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New job!</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2014/08/25/new-job/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2014/08/25/new-job/</guid>
      <description>I am delighted &amp;#8212; tickled, in fact &amp;#8212; to report that as of last Monday I am employed by Canonical, the company behind Ubuntu Linux.
I&amp;#8217;ve joined the Ecosystem Engineering team, part of Cloud Development and Operations, as a software engineer. More specifically, I&amp;#8217;m working on Juju, the cloud orchestration tool chain. I&amp;#8217;ll be writing charms and documentation, working on optimizations, and helping to make a cool product even cooler.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>111 Weeks</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2013/09/19/111-weeks/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2013/09/19/111-weeks/</guid>
      <description>To be exact, it&amp;#8217;s been 783 days since we filed for my Canadian Permanent Residence and I am happy to announce that it is official done. We have just walked out of the Immigration Centre in Windsor, Ontario, Social Insurance Number in hand.
I guess this makes me an expatriate; an American Citizen permanently living abroad, which is kind of cool. I&amp;#8217;ve been thinking a lot about getting a tattoo to commemorate the experience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Month of Letters</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2013/01/29/a-month-of-letters/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2013/01/29/a-month-of-letters/</guid>
      <description>Mary Robinette Kowal started a delightful challenge, in 2010, to go correspond via letter for an entire month. That has grown to become A Month of Letters, which runs for the whole of February. During the next month, I and the other 6,000 people who&amp;#8217;ve signed up to participate will be writing letters, post cards, and doing other creative things and dropping them into the mail.
I love to write longhand, and this gives me a wonderful reason to do so.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two years and pocket change</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2012/11/26/two-years-and-pocket-change/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2012/11/26/two-years-and-pocket-change/</guid>
      <description>Two years and two days ago, I started a journey from Santa Monica, California by foot, bus, train, and plane. Many hours later, I reached Detroit and was met by my friend Katni, who drove me through the Detroit-Windsor tunnel where, six months after being kicked out, I re-entered Canada and was reunited with Andrea.
Being home still feels really good.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Independence</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2012/07/05/independence/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2012/07/05/independence/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday was Independence Day back in the states. We already had our fireworks over the weekend, and I worked through Canada Day on Monday and had yesterday off instead. Among the joys of American/Canada relations are mixed holidays.
Our plans were a little more focused. Yesterday we saw an apartment, and made a deposit, and transfered utilities to our name. This was kind of a big deal, because for the first time in more than three years, we&amp;#8217;re in a position to start a new chapter in our lives.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>