<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Writing on Adam Israel</title>
    <link>http://adamisrael.com/categories/writing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Writing on Adam Israel</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© 2016 Adam Israel</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 May 2017 10:14:18 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://adamisrael.com/categories/writing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>ubuntu</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/tech/ubuntu/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2017 10:14:18 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/tech/ubuntu/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>juju</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/tech/juju/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2017 10:14:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/tech/juju/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>snap</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/tech/snap/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2017 10:14:01 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/tech/snap/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>lxd</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/tech/lxd/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2017 10:13:57 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/tech/lxd/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>index</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/tech/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2017 10:13:54 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/tech/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>rpi</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/tech/rpi/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2017 10:13:50 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/tech/rpi/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finding my footing</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2013/01/16/finding-my-footing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2013/01/16/finding-my-footing/</guid>
      <description>As writers, we fill our toolbox with things that help us in our craft. I&amp;#8217;ve been experimenting with a few new things of late, trying to boost my productivity. Two of them in particular are making a difference.
I haven&amp;#8217;t been involved in many word wars &amp;#8212; timed writing sessions with one or more other writers. Set a short time limit, say 15 or 30 minutes, and write until it&amp;#8217;s over.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Back in the saddle, week 1</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2013/01/07/back-in-the-saddle-week-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2013/01/07/back-in-the-saddle-week-1/</guid>
      <description>Part of my new and improved resolve to Finish Things is accountability, and to that end I&amp;#8217;ve created a master spreadsheet for the year where I&amp;#8217;m tracking my daily writing, good things that happen (h/t Christie Yant), projects I want to work on, and deadlines I&amp;#8217;m working towards. It&amp;#8217;s not perfect, but it&amp;#8217;s a start.
I&amp;#8217;m trying to work every day while I&amp;#8217;m involved in a project. Writing is, or should be, what I spend the most time on, at least at this stage in my current WIP.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clarion Write-a-Thon</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2012/06/13/clarion-write-a-thon/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2012/06/13/clarion-write-a-thon/</guid>
      <description>The Clarion Write-a-thon starts on June 24th, running parallel to the six week workshop I attended in 2010. While this summers workshop students toil away in San Diego, I’ll be one of many writers helping to raise awareness and solicit donations to a cause we believe in.
 What is a write-a-thon, anyway? It&amp;#8217;s just like a walk-a-thon. But instead of walking, we&amp;#8217;re writing, and instead of making pledges per mile, we&amp;#8217;re making pledges per word, chapter, or story.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ad Astra Wrapup</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2012/04/16/ad-astra-wrapup/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2012/04/16/ad-astra-wrapup/</guid>
      <description>My first Ad Astra is over, and I didn&amp;#8217;t completely embarrass myself. Huzzah!
I&amp;#8217;ll admit to being intimidated at first, not knowing anyone. It&amp;#8217;s a good-sized local convention with a lot of history and people know already each other. What I finally realized, though, is that I just needed to _politely_ join in the conversation. Everyone was welcoming and, even better, assumed I was Canadian. I swear, I am in all but name.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Loneliness of the Long Distance Runner</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2012/02/27/the-loneliness-of-the-long-distance-runner/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2012/02/27/the-loneliness-of-the-long-distance-runner/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes, when I sit down and stare at a white blank page, my heart races. I fear the mistakes I’m about to make, at the same time I’m in awe of the creation about to spring forth the tip of my pen. I’ve done it before. I’ll do it again. I am not a fast writer, but I am a sprinter.
Sprinting is this — pen to paper, writing around 500 words/day until a story is done.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Storylife — A process of wrangling submissions</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2011/10/28/storylife-a-process-of-wrangling-submissions/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2011/10/28/storylife-a-process-of-wrangling-submissions/</guid>
      <description>I just mailed off my first story submission since 2009. Most of my submissions are electronic but, dating back to my first submissions circa 2007, I think I&amp;#8217;ve mailed off 5 or 6 stories or about 5% of my total submissions.
Some writers don&amp;#8217;t even own printers (John Scalzi comes to mind). Markets are evolving &amp;#8212; not quite matching pace, but at least trailing the pack. Analog and Asimov both use the electronic submissions system developed by Neil Clarke.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brainjuice</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2011/08/23/brainjuice/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2011/08/23/brainjuice/</guid>
      <description>Can you believe I managed to blog three whole days in a row last week two weeks ago? Yeah.
Apparently I&amp;#8217;m running in low power mode right now. New meds, a heavy work schedule, and two short story deadlines. Oh, and I&amp;#8217;m outlining NOVEL.
I&amp;#8217;ve got around twenty unfinished short stories in inventory. My plan is to revise a short story every month or so while drafting novel. I don&amp;#8217;t plan to draft any new short stories until I&amp;#8217;ve finished this novel draft, unless something new like Shanghai Steam comes along or a specific invite comes along that catches my interest.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Less talk, more word count</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2011/08/10/less-talk-more-word-count/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2011/08/10/less-talk-more-word-count/</guid>
      <description>I need to post a full recap of my Clarion write-a-thon efforts and a thank you to the donors. In the meantime, a little bit about accountability.
I&amp;#8217;ve been bad about writing consistently lately (blogging seems to be a chronic problem). I&amp;#8217;d write sporadically, finishing stories here and there, revising and evening submitting a few of them with some success. Mostly, though, I&amp;#8217;ve been draft stories and that&amp;#8217;s it. I still have some sitting in my moleskines waiting to be typed up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speaking with Authority</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2011/07/16/speaking-with-authority/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2011/07/16/speaking-with-authority/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;#8217;s a funny thing. When I wrote tech news and my Linux column, I felt pretty confident about what I was doing. I could debate policy and technology without hesitation. I&amp;#8217;ve been on panels, given demonstrations and was, frankly, highly opinionated and usually right.
It&amp;#8217;s different when it comes to fiction, though. I&amp;#8217;ve made sales and gone to Clarion. I&amp;#8217;m comfortable with what I do and don&amp;#8217;t know but I don&amp;#8217;t usually feel like I&amp;#8217;m speaking with authority.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Draft Zero</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2011/04/28/draft-zero/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2011/04/28/draft-zero/</guid>
      <description>I didn&amp;#8217;t reach my original estimate of 5,000 words but this draft is done.
Project: Motown Blues (tentative)
New words written: 811
Reason for stopping: End of story
No matter how much I outline and plan, these stories tend to take on a life of their own once I get started. The voice fluctuates until it finds its pace and pitch. Tangents emerge, sidetrack, and must be wrestled into submission. I like what this is shaping up to be.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What do you mean, fifteen minutes *each*?</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2011/04/24/what-do-you-mean-fifteen-minutes-each/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2011/04/24/what-do-you-mean-fifteen-minutes-each/</guid>
      <description>I missed a couple days of writing last week, which included a day spent trying to get fingerprints taken for immigration and ended up with an appointment one week out. Who knew that fingerprint technology had advanced beyond ink pads? One set for Ontario, and a set each for the FBI and State of Illinois to request my records. The saga, she continues.
My Illinois driving records have been received by Mom and will soon be on their way here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extinct Doesn’t Mean Forever</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2011/04/06/extinct-doesnt-mean-forever/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2011/04/06/extinct-doesnt-mean-forever/</guid>
      <description>&amp;nbsp;

I realize that I neglected to mention that the anthology Extinct Doesn&amp;#8217;t Mean Forever, containing my story Indigo&amp;#8217;s Gambit, is now available on Amazon.
 Three, two, one, bang — the Drifting Star skipped on the wave of a collapsing micro-sun, soaring through the void between the stars. The astronautical library contained surveys and charts on hundreds of thousands of star systems within the alliance of civilized worlds the Fringe called Sing Xu.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rainforest Writers Village</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2011/03/17/rainforest-writers-village/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2011/03/17/rainforest-writers-village/</guid>
      <description>Last weekend, Andrea and I attended the Rainforest Writers Village at Lake Quinalt in western Washington state. It was our first trip together in more than two years, the first time either of us had been to the Pacific Northwest, and our first to the states since my return to Canada last year.
My hat goes off to Patrick Swenson, who puts heart and soul into making the retreat an awesome event.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SALE: Dog Days, to Crossed Genres</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2011/02/10/sale-dog-days-to-crossed-genres/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2011/02/10/sale-dog-days-to-crossed-genres/</guid>
      <description>I am pleased to announce that I&amp;#8217;ve sold my story, Dog Days, to Crossed Genres for their March issue, Superheroes. This is the story I referenced in my latest Inkpunks post, Writer’s Toolkit: Tarot Cards.
I&amp;#8217;m particularly tickled by this sale. It&amp;#8217;s my first acceptance post-Clarion, of a story I&amp;#8217;m particularly enamored with, to one of my favorite markets. Happy writer is happy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SALE: Indigo’s Gambit, to the EXTINCT anthology</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2011/02/10/sale-indigos-gambit-to-the-extinct-anthology/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2011/02/10/sale-indigos-gambit-to-the-extinct-anthology/</guid>
      <description>Coming on the heels of my sale to Crossed Genres, I can also announce that I&amp;#8217;ve sold the story, Indigo&amp;#8217;s Gambit, to the EXTINCT anthology, to be published as an eBook later this year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finishing Things Weekend</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2011/01/21/finishing-things-weekend/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2011/01/21/finishing-things-weekend/</guid>
      <description>This weekend has been declared crunch time, and as it turns out there&amp;#8217;s also a Finishing Things Weekend (#FTW) happening on Twitter this weekend. Rockin&amp;#8217;. I love peer pressure.
The things that I want/need to get done:
 Revise last weekend&amp;#8217;s flash story (flutters eyelashes at critiquers) and submit it Draft another Tesla&amp;#8217;s Daughter Super Hero story (yes, it&amp;#8217;s apparently turning into a series) Write new flash fiction for this weekend&amp;#8217;s Codex Weekend Warriors contest  That&amp;#8217;s kind of a lot, but I think I can pull it off.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I have a &lt;3 for words</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2011/01/13/i-have-a/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2011/01/13/i-have-a/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#8217;m planning a submissions party this weekend and you are all welcome to join me on Twitter. I have at least one story that that I should be sending out for reprints and a second that I&amp;#8217;m not sure when, offhand, the reprint rights revert. I need to do market research, update my spreadsheets, and get submitting. I&amp;#8217;ve also got some stories that have been sitting gathering dust and that&amp;#8217;s a crying shame.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hard days</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2010/12/28/hard-days/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2010/12/28/hard-days/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#8217;ve been slogging away, the last few weeks, trying to string together words that make sense. It&amp;#8217;s been rough. A nameless ennui that I blame on not having a place to personalize yet. That&amp;#8217;s something Andrea and I will be working towards in the new year. Meanwhile, life goes on and the writing must continue so I had to find a way. Deadlines usually help, but I&amp;#8217;ve been staring two or three, maybe four, up the ugly side so much lately that I&amp;#8217;m beginning to go cross-eyed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brief World Fantasy wrap-up</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2010/11/04/brief-world-fantasy-wrap-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2010/11/04/brief-world-fantasy-wrap-up/</guid>
      <description>I went to my first World Fantasy Convention last weekend. I&amp;#8217;ve been to other conventions &amp;#8212; mostly smaller, regional conventions like Penguicon, Windycon, and a one-day stop at WisCon last year. I thought I knew what to expect. Boy was I wrong.
First, the new friends. So many of my friends converged upon Columbus that World Fantasy was, for many of us, our first face-to-face meeting. I met what seemed like half of my rival Clarion class, all but one of the Inkpunks (Wendy, we missed you dearly), and so many others from Facebook, Twitter, and LiveJournal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Travel ahoy</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2010/10/10/travel-ahoy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2010/10/10/travel-ahoy/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;#8217;s a good feeling to put the word END after the last paragraph of a manuscript. This story was born week five of Clarion but I couldn&amp;#8217;t make it work then. A little bit of time away and with four days of sporadic effort, it&amp;#8217;s a story. Rough around the edges like any first draft but I expect those will be caught when I sent it to beta readers later this week.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Back in the saddle, now with statistics</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2010/10/07/back-in-the-saddle-now-with-statistics/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2010/10/07/back-in-the-saddle-now-with-statistics/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#8217;ve been a little slow getting back into the habit of writing new words since I&amp;#8217;ve been back from Clarion. Besides catching up on ye olde day job, I&amp;#8217;ve been working on revisions and submissions, organizing my inventory list, and other life issues.
Most of the stories in my backlog are either trunked, needing rewrites, or massive revision. Unfortunate, but them&amp;#8217;s the breaks. Not including the current work(s) in progress, there are:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aren’t you that guy that went to that writing thing?</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2010/09/08/arent-you-that-guy-that-went-to-that-writing-thing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2010/09/08/arent-you-that-guy-that-went-to-that-writing-thing/</guid>
      <description>By Internet speeds, it&amp;#8217;s been years since Clarion ended and not just a month. And the neglectful blogger I&amp;#8217;ve been, it was six weeks before that since I last posted anything resembling an update. It&amp;#8217;s time I said something, don&amp;#8217;t you think? Well yes, but not exactly what you might expect.
Eighteen people met as strangers in late June, in San Diego, and became a family. Along the way, aunts and uncles and cousins, and a grandfather or two, who guided us through the Clarion process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sale – “A Cup of Tea”</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2010/05/29/sale-a-cup-of-tea/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2010/05/29/sale-a-cup-of-tea/</guid>
      <description>I’m happy to announce that my story, “A Cup of Tea”, has sold to Golden Visions Magazine and will be in their July 2010 print issue. Support a small press and buy a copy (or PDF), won’t you?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2010 Hugo Nom Nom Nominations</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2010/04/04/2010-hugo-nom-nom-nominations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2010/04/04/2010-hugo-nom-nom-nominations/</guid>
      <description>Via The Hugo Awards:
**
 Best Novel (699 Ballots)
  Boneshaker, Cherie Priest (Tor)
 The City &amp;amp; The City, China Miéville (Del Rey; Macmillan UK)
 Julian Comstock: A Story of 22nd-Century America, Robert Charles Wilson (Tor)
 Palimpsest, Catherynne M. Valente (Bantam Spectra)
 Wake, Robert J. Sawyer (Ace; Penguin; Gollancz; Analog)
 The Windup Girl, Paolo Bacigalupi (Night Shade)
  Both Boneshaker and Palimpsest are in my to-read pile and I can’t wait to get my hands on The Windup Girl.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clarion 2010</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2010/03/07/clarion-2010/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2010/03/07/clarion-2010/</guid>
      <description>Believe it or not, I’m still a little under the weather. I’m beginning to suspect I had the hamthrax. Five weeks out and I’m just now starting to feel like myself again. All it really means is that I’m sleeping way more than usual, drinking a gallon of water a day, and a bit behind in my correspondence.
So better late than never, I’m happy to announce that I’ve applied to Clarion and Clarion West.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deadlines cometh</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2010/02/24/deadlines-cometh/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2010/02/24/deadlines-cometh/</guid>
      <description>February is coming to a close and I&amp;#8217;m scrambling like mad. Clarion closes to applications on March 1st. One application story is done. I have a second one more or less ready, but I&amp;#8217;m debating a last minute replacement.
I&amp;#8217;m putting the grind wheel and polish to my as yet untitled story for the Scheherazade&amp;#8217;s Facade anthology, due February 28th. It&amp;#8217;s shaping up into something that makes me happy. I pushed myself when writing this and for that reason I&amp;#8217;m also considering using it as my second Clarion story.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 3: Practice Stories</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2010/01/22/week-3-practice-stories/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2010/01/22/week-3-practice-stories/</guid>
      <description>Another kind of successful week &amp;#8212; 3,237 new words, bringing the years total to 10,404.
I&amp;#8217;m still struggling with revisions. I got critiques back on two of my stories this week. The crits were brutally honest, the way I like them, and resonated with things I&amp;#8217;d been trying to figure out myself. One thing I&amp;#8217;m uncovering is that I don&amp;#8217;t read critically enough. Having a third party point out an issue is great.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 2: A step slightly staggered</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2010/01/16/week-2-a-step-slightly-staggered/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2010/01/16/week-2-a-step-slightly-staggered/</guid>
      <description>A new short story and a flash fiction drafted, and a second short story underway. Over 7,500 new words this year, with my average rising to 509 words/day. The Honorable Mention nod and a personal rejection also came in. The year is off to a good start.
I&amp;#8217;m still struggling with revisions. I failed my weekly goals this week, getting almost no editing done nor my outline for the Dollhouse essay.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writers of the Future: Honorable Mention</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2010/01/14/writers-of-the-future-honorable-mention/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2010/01/14/writers-of-the-future-honorable-mention/</guid>
      <description>I felt a little blue this week, grousing over revisions and my sometimes fragile ego. I distracted myself by patiently refreshing the Writers of the Future blog and checking the mail every few minutes, hoping to see some word of the 2009 Q4 results. Well, the list of Honorable Mentions was released before they had a chance to update the blog.
 &amp;#8220;Out of the thousands of stories that get submitted to the contest, a small percentage make it this far,&amp;#8221; Wentworth continued.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The best laid intentions, felled by a lack of 3×5″ notecards</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2010/01/11/the-best-laid-intentions-felled-by-a-lack-of-3x5-notecards/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2010/01/11/the-best-laid-intentions-felled-by-a-lack-of-3x5-notecards/</guid>
      <description>When I kicked off the year writing 250 new words a day, I had a plan. A story. An outline, man. I finished that story yesterday. Plus an impromptu flash fiction piece. Today? I have no plan.
I have a theme (thank you, upcoming anthology). I have the kernel of a plot and main character. Tonight, I write without my safety net. I&amp;#8217;m curious to see what this change in process produces.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 1: Knock on wood</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2010/01/08/week-1-knock-on-wood/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2010/01/08/week-1-knock-on-wood/</guid>
      <description>When I started out following Booklife and documenting my writing progress, I suspected the first few weeks would either be really easy or really hard. Establishing a habit takes times and it&amp;#8217;s easy to make excuses to skip writing. We all hear or use them &amp;#8212; I&amp;#8217;m too busy, too much day job work, kids/family, etc. Then there&amp;#8217;s the Resolutionists, who make a bunch of goals at the beginning of the year and waver after a few weeks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Miscellanea</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2010/01/06/miscellanea/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2010/01/06/miscellanea/</guid>
      <description>Writing It&amp;#8217;s really too early to tell how things are going to work out long-term but so far I feel good. Not overwhelmed by keeping my spreadsheets updated or gut checking my short-term goals. I&amp;#8217;m right where I want to be. I hope I can say the same thing a week and a month from now.

I&amp;#8217;m writing a little bit every day. I&amp;#8217;ve surpassed my 250 words/day goal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Achievements and goals</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2010/01/03/achievements-and-goals/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2010/01/03/achievements-and-goals/</guid>
      <description>On the heels of yesterdays post about Booklife and my personal mission statement, I have added My Booklife to the sidebar. From here, I have posted and will keep updated my public weekly, monthly, 1 year and 5 year goals. I&amp;#8217;ve also included my list of career achievements.
I&amp;#8217;m feeling pretty good about how things are shaping. I&amp;#8217;m starting the year with a more or less clean slate; new domain, new blog, and new goals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In the beginning, there was the Mission Statement</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2010/01/03/in-the-beginning-there-was-the-mission-statement/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2010/01/03/in-the-beginning-there-was-the-mission-statement/</guid>
      <description>I am horrible with deadlines. In high school I was forced to take a special class on time management because I never turned anything in on time. It&amp;#8217;s one of those things that I struggle with on a daily basis. Occasionally I discover something useful that helps, like Things, that help me keep track of the things I need to be doing. The most recent one was Jeff VanderMeer&amp;#8216;s Booklife.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2009 Submission Statistics</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2010/01/01/2009-submission-statistics/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2010/01/01/2009-submission-statistics/</guid>
      <description>It wasn&amp;#8217;t the best year writing-wise. Eight new stories, one of which was flash and four were &amp;#8220;hint fiction&amp;#8221;. Two stories from 2008 were edited repeatedly and eventually submitted, both to Writers of the Future. Fifteen submissions, thirteen rejections, and one rewrite request. If my Duotope statistics are accurate, nine were personal rejections (one from a pro market).
Could be worse. 2010 will be much better, though.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>