<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Writing on Adam Israel</title>
    <link>http://dev.adamisrael.com/categories/writing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Writing on Adam Israel</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://dev.adamisrael.com/categories/writing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Finding my footing</title>
      <link>http://dev.adamisrael.com/blog/2013/01/16/finding-my-footing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://dev.adamisrael.com/blog/2013/01/16/finding-my-footing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As writers, we fill our toolbox with things that help us in our craft. I&amp;#8217;ve been experimenting with a few new things of late, trying to boost my productivity. Two of them in particular are making a difference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I haven&amp;#8217;t been involved in many word wars &amp;#8212; timed writing sessions with one or more other writers. Set a short time limit, say 15 or 30 minutes, and write until it&amp;#8217;s over. I started doing that last week, with my online writers group, and had one of my most productive days. These sprints are like a mini-deadline and it&amp;#8217;s easier at times to shut out distraction in small increments. To that end, I&amp;#8217;m taking carving out small small blocks of time throughout the day to write, especially on days when I might not be able to dedicate an hour or two contiguously. I&amp;#8217;m going to get an egg timer to give me an external countdown to the process as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I ordered a cute egg timer from the states, but it was broken and I discovered the hard way how expensive custom and duty fees can be when something is shipped via UPS cross-border. I may just find a decent kitchen timer that can do double-duty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second trick is an organizational one. I&amp;#8217;ve seen it &lt;a href=&#34;http://lifehacker.com/5968978/use-the-dash-method-to-become-a-better-writer-developer-or-tackle-any-other-creative-task&#34;&gt;referred to&lt;/a&gt; as the DASH method &amp;#8212; Direction, Acceleration, Strength, and Health.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Direction is knowing what I&amp;#8217;m going to write before I start. I make short lists of every chapter, broken down by scene, of what that writing needs to accomplish, usually no more than four or five bullet points. That mini-outline forces me to think through every chapter before I put down a single word. When I do sit down to write, I know what my end goal is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Acceleration is getting started and finishing things. I&amp;#8217;ve been pretty slow, plodding along and being frustrated with my progress. I would take so long, writing and rewriting, that I made almost no progress. Now, almost as a mantra, I remind myself that the point of a first draft is getting the ideas down on the page. Making the grammar fluid and pretty can wait for revision.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Strength refers to bolstering your mental clarify and physical strength through a better working environment. I am all about that. It&amp;#8217;s been a slow process to make my office a comfortable space but we&amp;#8217;re almost there. We have our bookshelves up and my cork board, filled with quotes that inspire, hands next to my desk. When I do need a change of pace, I switch to the coffee shop up the road.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Health is a reminder to take care of myself. Figuring out what doesn&amp;#8217;t work (and drives up anxiety) and fix it. Get enough sleep. Realize that if I&amp;#8217;m stuck on something, I probably just need to work it through to figure out what I&amp;#8217;m missing &amp;#8212; brainstorming, doodling, talking it through with someone else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last week wasn&amp;#8217;t the most productive, with a funeral, doctors visit, and other distractions, but I had two great days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Project: Black Mirror&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;New words written since last week: 1,980&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Average words/day: 248&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;![][2]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m working through some existing scenes that need at least some work vs. writing new words. It&amp;#8217;s slowed me down a little but it needs doing. I&amp;#8217;m printing off each chapter as it&amp;#8217;s finished and putting it into a binder. When I do finish, I&amp;#8217;ll take that binder and a red pen and go sit somewhere for an afternoon and begin the revision process. Until then, the printed manuscript goes and is another reminder of what I&amp;#8217;ve finished so far.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[2]: &lt;a href=&#34;http://picometer.writertopia.com/words=38371&amp;amp;target=100000&#34;&gt;http://picometer.writertopia.com/words=38371&amp;amp;target=100000&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Back in the saddle, week 1</title>
      <link>http://dev.adamisrael.com/blog/2013/01/07/back-in-the-saddle-week-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://dev.adamisrael.com/blog/2013/01/07/back-in-the-saddle-week-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Part of my new and improved resolve to Finish Things is accountability, and to that end I&amp;#8217;ve created a master spreadsheet for the year where I&amp;#8217;m tracking my daily writing, good things that happen (h/t Christie Yant), projects I want to work on, and deadlines I&amp;#8217;m working towards. It&amp;#8217;s not perfect, but it&amp;#8217;s a start.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m trying to work every day while I&amp;#8217;m involved in a project. Writing is, or should be, what I spend the most time on, at least at this stage in my current WIP. The non-writing tasks, like research, outlining, etc, are limited to what&amp;#8217;s necessary to finish the draft. Research is my way to procrastinate. I did a ton before I started writing, I&amp;#8217;ll do more after the first draft is finished, but at some point I actually have to write this thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;#8217;t want to take away time from writing, so I&amp;#8217;m allowing myself to spam the world with statistics once a week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Project: Black Mirror&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;New words written this week: 2,031&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Average words/day: 338&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[&lt;img alt=&#34;Project Targets&#34; src=&#34;http://www.adamisrael.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/01/project_targets-2013-01-07.jpg&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;][1]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s too soon since I started tracking daily stats to say if I&amp;#8217;m going to hit my deadline or not. This first week has sort of been the warm-up, shaking off the rust of not writing at all for a couple months. I started at 364 days, no words one day (but outlining a new chapter), and ended today at 845. I think I&amp;#8217;ll settle at a comfortable, consistent pace. There&amp;#8217;s wiggle room in my deadline, but not much. My end goal, as soon as the first draft is done, is to revise and have a draft ready for submission by my birthday in late July.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[1]: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.adamisrael.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/01/project_targets-2013-01-07.jpg&#34;&gt;http://www.adamisrael.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/01/project_targets-2013-01-07.jpg&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clarion Write-a-Thon</title>
      <link>http://dev.adamisrael.com/blog/2012/06/13/clarion-write-a-thon/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://dev.adamisrael.com/blog/2012/06/13/clarion-write-a-thon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Clarion Write-a-thon starts on June 24&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt;, running parallel to the six week workshop I attended in 2010. While this summers workshop students toil away in San Diego, I’ll be one of many writers helping to raise awareness and solicit donations to a cause we believe in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is a write-a-thon, anyway? It&amp;#8217;s just like a walk-a-thon. But instead of walking, we&amp;#8217;re writing, and instead of making pledges per mile, we&amp;#8217;re making pledges per word, chapter, or story. Writers get support, encouragement and motivation, and the option of joining a team with a writing mentor! Those who care about the writers in their life get a way to show their support. And money is raised for a literally fantastic cause &amp;#8212; the Clarion Science Fiction &amp;amp; Fantasy Writers&amp;#8217; Workshop. All donations are made through The Clarion Foundation, a 501&amp;copy;(3) non-profit organization, EIN #20-3114945.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll also be one of the aforementioned mentors this year, as part of Team Weaveworld. The teams are a new thing with the write-a-thon this year, as a way to provide support and motivation for those who want it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During this years write-a-thon, I’ll be continuing work on my novel-in-progress. My challenge is to write at least 1,000 words/day, 5 days/week, with an ultimate goal of 30,0000 words over the six weeks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;d love to raise tons and tons of money for Clarion, because I passionately believe in what they do (and did for me). This is a no pressure pitch on my part, though. [Pledge][1] what you feel comfortable with, knowing that you have my utmost thanks and appreciation for donating to something dear to my heart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[1]: &lt;a href=&#34;http://clarionwriteathon.org/members/profile.php?writerid=348271&#34;&gt;http://clarionwriteathon.org/members/profile.php?writerid=348271&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ad Astra Wrapup</title>
      <link>http://dev.adamisrael.com/blog/2012/04/16/ad-astra-wrapup/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://dev.adamisrael.com/blog/2012/04/16/ad-astra-wrapup/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My first Ad Astra is over, and I didn&amp;#8217;t completely embarrass myself. Huzzah!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ll admit to being intimidated at first, not knowing anyone. It&amp;#8217;s a good-sized local convention with a lot of history and people know already each other. What I finally realized, though, is that I just needed to _politely_ join in the conversation. Everyone was welcoming and, even better, assumed I was Canadian. I swear, I am in all but name.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I saw there was a writing contest &amp;#8212; 250 words based on a handful of prompts &amp;#8212; and I pounced on that. It let me meet a nice group of writers and editors that I wouldn&amp;#8217;t have had the opportunity to interact with at that level otherwise. I wrote the story Friday night (longhand first, then transcribed and edited), printed it out Saturday, and we received the results on Sunday. As these things happen, as I was sitting in the room waiting to talk to one of the judges, I had a breakthrough regarding flash that was soon confirmed by more than one of the judges. Flash fiction is like a single breath of air, and I&amp;#8217;d forced the reader to stop and gulp in the middle of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Harry Turtledove was one of the Guests of Honor. I sat in one of his panels, on creating viable cultures in world-building. Fascinating stuff. It evolved into conversation about historical research and alternate history between him and Ed Greenwood, which was awesome and worth the price of admission alone. My two favorite quotes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;That feeling of depth, that the world keeps going when the author stops looking.&amp;#8221; Harry Turtledove, talking about Lord of the Rings&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;The harder you make your reader work, the smaller your audience.&amp;#8221; Ed Greenwood&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s always great to meet people I&amp;#8217;ve only known online. After a previous near-miss, I finally got to spend a few minutes chatting with &lt;a href=&#34;http://shaydchara.dreamwidth.org/&#34;&gt;Shay Darrach&lt;/a&gt;. I also got to spend some time with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gabrielle-edits.com/&#34;&gt;Gabrielle Harbowy&lt;/a&gt;, who I met through a mutual friend. That lead me to the launch party for Dragon Moon Press, which was a blast. Debut author &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.leahpetersen.com/&#34;&gt;Leah Petersen&lt;/a&gt; read from her novel and did a fabulous job, as did &lt;a href=&#34;http://mariebilodeau.blogspot.ca/&#34;&gt;Marie Bilodeau&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sunday, I went to a panel on &amp;#8216;Revising and The Pitch&amp;#8217;. At least, I thought it was a panel but it was really an interactive two-hour workshop led by [Julie Czerneda][5] and it was awesome. In groups of three, we were given prompts and created &amp;#8212; and then revised &amp;#8212; a pitch for a story. Again, some good quotes came out of the panel, these regarding revision:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;As perfect as time permits.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;You have to learn to write to deadline; you may as well start by giving yourself one.&amp;#8221; Julie Czerneda&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Conventions have always left me with renewed spirits. Now, as I&amp;#8217;m gearing up to finish this novel, I feel like I have even more clarity. Not necessarily about the writing itself, but about in believing it can be done. It&amp;#8217;s easy to escape into short stories, because I&amp;#8217;ve written those, had those published. They&amp;#8217;re my safe place. A novel is a big, scary thing. That unknown feels less scary and more manageable right now, though, and that makes me very happy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[5]: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.czerneda.com/&#34;&gt;http://www.czerneda.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Loneliness of the Long Distance Runner</title>
      <link>http://dev.adamisrael.com/blog/2012/02/27/the-loneliness-of-the-long-distance-runner/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://dev.adamisrael.com/blog/2012/02/27/the-loneliness-of-the-long-distance-runner/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, when I sit down and stare at a white blank page, my heart races. I fear the mistakes I’m about to make, at the same time I’m in awe of the creation about to spring forth the tip of my pen. I’ve done it before. I’ll do it again. I am not a fast writer, but I am a sprinter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sprinting is this — pen to paper, writing around 500 words/day until a story is done. What you’re holding at the end is a complete story, but is it finished?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve heard conflicting schools of thought from various writers. Some revise as they write and submit when they hit the end. Others write a draft, revise, repeating as necessary, and submit. Everyone’s process is different, and probably varies by story. It does for me, at least.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right now, my process is a little like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write draft 0 longhand, offline, ignoring typos and grammatical errors. Use TK for placeholders.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Type up draft 1.0, correcting for most typos and minor grammatical issues. Most placeholders stay, but this also serves as my first read-through. Make detailed editorial notes in Scrivener.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Revise draft 1.1, fixing all typos, grammatical errors and replacing placeholders. Address editorial notes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point, if I’m trying to submit to an anthology with a looming submission deadline, I’ve read the story a few times and have a gut feeling as to whether it’s working the way I intended or not. Otherwise, the story is grounded, along with all of the other bad little drafts who live in my basement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing Clarion taught me was to write less shitty first drafts, so in many cases draft 1.1 of stories I’ve written since aren’t embarrassingly bad. I can do better, though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sprinting is easy, because at the end of that race I can wave my arms around and say, “Look at me, I finished a story!” The truth, though, is it’s not finished. The real finish line is looming ahead and I’ve just stopped short because that’s a longer, lonely road that seems so futile at times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rewards are worth the effort.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve got a story coming out on Thursday, at [Goldfish Grimm’s Spicy Fiction Sushi][1]. With “Control”, I was a long distance runner. I wrote the first draft during Clarion 2010. It was revised several times, including after a rewrite request, where I added 1,000 words. It saw three title changes. It took a while for this little story to find the right home, but it did and I knew it would. I didn’t just write that story; I finished it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have ADHD-like tendencies. When I’ve finished a draft, I tend to move on to the next shiny idea. That’s why I have so many 1.0 and 1.1’s lounging around, begging to see sunlight. I’ve proven, to myself at least, that I can sprint. Now it’s time to stay the course see these other stories finished.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[1]: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.goldfishgrimm.com/&#34;&gt;http://www.goldfishgrimm.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Storylife — A process of wrangling submissions</title>
      <link>http://dev.adamisrael.com/blog/2011/10/28/storylife-a-process-of-wrangling-submissions/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://dev.adamisrael.com/blog/2011/10/28/storylife-a-process-of-wrangling-submissions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I just mailed off my first story submission since 2009. Most of my submissions are electronic but, dating back to my first submissions circa 2007, I think I&amp;#8217;ve mailed off 5 or 6 stories or about 5% of my total submissions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some writers don&amp;#8217;t even own printers ([John Scalzi][1] comes to mind). Markets are evolving &amp;#8212; not quite matching pace, but at least trailing the pack. Analog and Asimov both use the electronic submissions system developed by Neil Clarke. I&amp;#8217;ve always had a printer &amp;#8212; usually one, a trusty laser dedicated to printing manuscripts &amp;#8212; because I like marking up hard copy but I&amp;#8217;m economical when it comes to submissions and response time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every story has a life. Literally, in my case. Recently, I built a spreadsheet called Storylife where every story has a sheet of its own. In it, I track the where the story is gone and where the story is going next. Every new sheet is seeded with a list of pro markets that I&amp;#8217;ve created based on an analysis of my own submission records, SFWA qualifying markets, and my own reading. It&amp;#8217;s a who&amp;#8217;s who of where I&amp;#8217;d like to be published. That initial list gets culled of markets that don&amp;#8217;t fit the story and sorted by best fit and response time. Non-pro markets get added to that list as I near the end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of the markets take electronic subs, but there are a few that don&amp;#8217;t. Fantasy &amp;amp; Science Fiction. Interzone. Black Static. Black Gate. Lady Churchill&amp;#8217;s Rosebud Wristlet. With Storylife, I&amp;#8217;m making myself submit to those markets even though it&amp;#8217;s a little less convenient than usual. F&amp;amp;SF is the outlier in terms of response time; they&amp;#8217;re faster than most of their electronic counterparts. With the rest, factoring in transit time, you&amp;#8217;re looking at maybe two or three months, if you&amp;#8217;re lucky.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me, the decision to submit by mail comes down to measuring the odds, which involves a little bit of rejectomancy. I don&amp;#8217;t submit a story until I&amp;#8217;m reasonably confident in it and the first few markets I send it out to are electronic with a quick turnaround time. If I get straight up form rejections in the average response time, I might take another look to see what might be keeping me in the slush pile before sending it back out. If I get a string of &amp;#8220;close, but not quite&amp;#8221; rejections then I feel as reasonably sure as any doubting writer can that the story just needs to find the right editor and I&amp;#8217;ll make the investment to submit by mail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are financial logistics involved in deciding to submit by mail. Mailing from Canada to the US cost me $8.57 today, just in postage. It would have been cheaper if I&amp;#8217;d had US postage &amp;#8212; $0.88 for two stamps vs. $4.50 for an International Relay Coupon &amp;#8212; but getting stamps takes a little maneuvering. Add in the cost of the 9&amp;#215;12 and business size envelope, printing, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaking of story life, I also need to make a decision about shelf life. I&amp;#8217;m considering following Ferrett&amp;#8217;s lead where he called a mulligan on his pre-Clarion writing life. I still have some of those stories in circulation and while they&amp;#8217;re good stories, I am running out of places to send them despite mostly positive feedback. Maybe harvest the ideas in future stories, because when you compare that to what I&amp;#8217;ve written since Clarion, nine first drafts, five polished stories sent out on submission and three sold (60%), all on their first date, that tells me I should be expending my energy on the new things. I have a feeling that there&amp;#8217;s a diminishing point of return on old stories, where they might do more harm than good in the eyes of an editor. I&amp;#8217;m just not sure where to draw that line.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[1]: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.scalzi.com/whatever/005165.html&#34;&gt;http://www.scalzi.com/whatever/005165.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brainjuice</title>
      <link>http://dev.adamisrael.com/blog/2011/08/23/brainjuice/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://dev.adamisrael.com/blog/2011/08/23/brainjuice/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Can you believe I managed to blog three whole days in a row &lt;del&gt;last week&lt;/del&gt; two weeks ago? Yeah.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apparently I&amp;#8217;m running in low power mode right now. New meds, a heavy work schedule, and two short story deadlines. Oh, and I&amp;#8217;m outlining NOVEL.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve got around twenty unfinished short stories in inventory. My plan is to revise a short story every month or so while drafting novel. I don&amp;#8217;t plan to draft any new short stories until I&amp;#8217;ve finished this novel draft, unless something new like &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.shanghai-steam.com/&#34;&gt;Shanghai Steam&lt;/a&gt; comes along or a specific invite comes along that catches my interest. Shiny is shiny, after all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How long will this take? Fuck if I know. I&amp;#8217;ve never finished a novel before. When I&amp;#8217;m drafting short stories I average 500 words/day with relative ease. I suspect I can double that but I&amp;#8217;ll be conservative and give myself until my birthday next summer &amp;#8212; almost exactly 11 months away. If I don&amp;#8217;t have a complete draft by then, something is seriously wrong and the [Inkpunks][2] are formally invited to visit a beatdown on my ass.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Expect regular status updates complete with word widget and maybe even tiny extracts of out of context words that I&amp;#8217;m not totally horrified by.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[2]: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.inkpunks.com/&#34;&gt;http://www.inkpunks.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Less talk, more word count</title>
      <link>http://dev.adamisrael.com/blog/2011/08/10/less-talk-more-word-count/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://dev.adamisrael.com/blog/2011/08/10/less-talk-more-word-count/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I need to post a full recap of my Clarion write-a-thon efforts and a thank you to the donors. In the meantime, a little bit about accountability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve been bad about writing consistently lately (blogging seems to be a chronic problem). I&amp;#8217;d write sporadically, finishing stories here and there, revising and evening submitting a few of them with some success.  Mostly, though, I&amp;#8217;ve been draft stories and that&amp;#8217;s it. I still have some sitting in my moleskines waiting to be typed up. I&amp;#8217;ve been really, really bad about revising and submitting. I only have four stories in circulation, with another twenty or so waiting to be edited. Not to mention the two novel ideas floating in my head and various states of outline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I could make excuses, but really, it comes down to sitting down and doing it. Butt in chair.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, I started neglecting twitter and the like to some degree, which gives me an easy excuse to talk about writing without actually doing. The big change I made was lifestyle &amp;#8212; going to bed at roughly the same time every day and getting up around the same time in the morning. Now, I roll out of bed, get dressed, and go write for an hour or two.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://spreadsheets.google.com/spreadsheet/oimg?key=0Agx3xVyVfvr1dEJGcHJjX3pMYzVZeHVwT2t1UWQ5YUE&amp;amp;oid=1&amp;amp;zx=ke1gnudr4wx&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have two projects I&amp;#8217;m working on this month, a new short story, &lt;em&gt;Aye of the Hagfish&lt;/em&gt;, that I&amp;#8217;ll be sending on to &lt;a href=&#34;http://daganbooks.com/&#34;&gt;Dagan Books&lt;/a&gt; Fish Anthology and an as yet untitled post-partial ice age apocalyptic recovery w/mech story that I&amp;#8217;m finally getting around to revising for [Timid Pirate][3]&amp;#8216;s Benevolent Apocalypse anthology, both due at month&amp;#8217;s end. After that, who knows. I&amp;#8217;ve got plenty of existing material to work from, but I fully intend to flood the market with new, original fiction by yours truly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyone who I&amp;#8217;ve worked with on deadline knows that I&amp;#8217;m bad for them. I&amp;#8217;m trying to fix that. Part of that is organizational (and damn my office is starting to look spiffy) and part of it is productivity. I could just cram the last week of the month and submit with minutes to spare, or miss the deadline and be morose for a week or two for another lost opportunity but fuck that. That&amp;#8217;s no way to run a career.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I finished draft 0.5 (a longhand first draft, a reverse outline and a draft of what was missing) of &lt;em&gt;Aye of the Hagfish&lt;/em&gt;. Tonight I&amp;#8217;ll type that up and hand off that very rough draft to my lovely, patient, and wise wife for a first read and turn my attention to the mech story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Life isn&amp;#8217;t all or nothing but that&amp;#8217;s how I&amp;#8217;ve been trying to tackle fiction. It doesn&amp;#8217;t work, at least for me, not in a way I can sustain. There&amp;#8217;s a place for line editing but it&amp;#8217;s not on the first edit. I&amp;#8217;ll make a revision pass to fixing major issues and hand it off for comment. Pick up the next project and repeat, and so on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;#8217;s no substitution for action. If you want to write, sit and do it. There is no other alternative.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[3]: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.timidpirate.com/&#34;&gt;http://www.timidpirate.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speaking with Authority</title>
      <link>http://dev.adamisrael.com/blog/2011/07/16/speaking-with-authority/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://dev.adamisrael.com/blog/2011/07/16/speaking-with-authority/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s a funny thing. When I wrote tech news and my Linux column, I felt pretty confident about what I was doing. I could debate policy and technology without hesitation. I&amp;#8217;ve been on panels, given demonstrations and was, frankly, highly opinionated and usually right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s different when it comes to fiction, though. I&amp;#8217;ve made sales and gone to Clarion. I&amp;#8217;m comfortable with what I do and don&amp;#8217;t know but I don&amp;#8217;t usually feel like I&amp;#8217;m speaking with authority. Oddly, when I first started out I could sit and write a couple thousand words in a sitting. Now, I am more methodical, carefully choosing my words and writing much, much slower. The results are much better but there are times I wish I could reclaim some of that speed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve heard, on a few occasions, that it takes a year or so to fully recover or internalize the lessons of Clarion. Maybe I&amp;#8217;m still in that phase and on the other side I&amp;#8217;ll gain some newfound confidence in my work that will allow me to stop second-guessing myself. I&amp;#8217;m happy with the end result of my work. I believe it&amp;#8217;s of professional quality even if I haven&amp;#8217;t made that first pro sale yet. I should be happy with what I have but I guess I wouldn&amp;#8217;t be me if I didn&amp;#8217;t push myself to the next level.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Draft Zero</title>
      <link>http://dev.adamisrael.com/blog/2011/04/28/draft-zero/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://dev.adamisrael.com/blog/2011/04/28/draft-zero/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I didn&amp;#8217;t reach my original estimate of 5,000 words but this draft is done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Project: Motown Blues (tentative)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;New words written: 811&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reason for stopping: End of story&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;![][1]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No matter how much I outline and plan, these stories tend to take on a life of their own once I get started. The voice fluctuates until it finds its pace and pitch. Tangents emerge, sidetrack, and must be wrestled into submission. I like what this is shaping up to be. Like painting, the next steps are to refine the edges, fix the flaws, and add depth to bring it to life. 18 days til deadline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[1]: &lt;a href=&#34;http://picometer.writertopia.com/words=4064&amp;amp;target=5000&#34;&gt;http://picometer.writertopia.com/words=4064&amp;amp;target=5000&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What do you mean, fifteen minutes *each*?</title>
      <link>http://dev.adamisrael.com/blog/2011/04/24/what-do-you-mean-fifteen-minutes-each/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://dev.adamisrael.com/blog/2011/04/24/what-do-you-mean-fifteen-minutes-each/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I missed a couple days of writing last week, which included a day spent trying to get fingerprints taken for immigration and ended up with an appointment one week out. Who knew that fingerprint technology had advanced beyond ink pads? One set for Ontario, and a set each for the FBI and State of Illinois to request my records. The saga, she continues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My Illinois driving records have been received by Mom and will soon be on their way here. Soon, I&amp;#8217;ll be able to get an Ontario drivers license and then we can start the car shopping. I&amp;#8217;m researching the Ford Focus, Mazda 3 hatchback, and the Dodge Caliber. A nice compact with good gas milage should do us well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Project: Motown Blues&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;New words written: 599&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reason for stopping: family obligations&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;![][1]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two and a half scenes to go. I&amp;#8217;ll wrap this draft in a few days and get hustling on the first revision. Between now and May 15th, when it&amp;#8217;s due, I&amp;#8217;ll end up with three or four revised drafts. There&amp;#8217;s good guts in this here story. I just need to tease them out and make them pretty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[1]: &lt;a href=&#34;http://picometer.writertopia.com/words=3253&amp;amp;target=5000&#34;&gt;http://picometer.writertopia.com/words=3253&amp;amp;target=5000&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extinct Doesn’t Mean Forever</title>
      <link>http://dev.adamisrael.com/blog/2011/04/06/extinct-doesnt-mean-forever/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://dev.adamisrael.com/blog/2011/04/06/extinct-doesnt-mean-forever/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.adamisrael.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/04/Exinct-cover.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-396 alignright&#34; title=&#34;Exinct-cover&#34; src=&#34;http://www.adamisrael.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/04/Exinct-cover-300x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; srcset=&#34;//www.adamisrael.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/04/Exinct-cover-150x150.jpg 150w, //www.adamisrael.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/04/Exinct-cover-300x300.jpg 300w, //www.adamisrael.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/04/Exinct-cover.jpg 500w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I realize that I neglected to mention that the anthology [Extinct Doesn&amp;#8217;t Mean Forever][2], containing my story Indigo&amp;#8217;s Gambit, is now available on Amazon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Three, two, one, bang — the &lt;em&gt;Drifting Star&lt;/em&gt; skipped on the wave of a collapsing micro-sun, soaring through the void between the stars. The astronautical library contained surveys and charts on hundreds of thousands of star systems within the alliance of civilized worlds the Fringe called Sing Xu. This would be the thirty-eighth Indigo had visited since his journey toward the core planets began. So far none contained a world suitable to revive the Oshen race.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m happy that this story found a home. I wrote it several years ago for a different anthology but didn&amp;#8217;t get accepted. Themed anthologies can be tricky beasts &amp;#8212; the market is flooded with stories that didn&amp;#8217;t make the cut. Patience paid off, though, and this anthology came along.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[2]: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Extinct-Doesnt-Mean-Forever-ebook/dp/B004SUOWMU/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1302110125&amp;amp;sr=8-1&#34;&gt;http://www.amazon.com/Extinct-Doesnt-Mean-Forever-ebook/dp/B004SUOWMU/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1302110125&amp;amp;sr=8-1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rainforest Writers Village</title>
      <link>http://dev.adamisrael.com/blog/2011/03/17/rainforest-writers-village/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://dev.adamisrael.com/blog/2011/03/17/rainforest-writers-village/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last weekend, Andrea and I attended the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rainforestwritersvillage.com/&#34;&gt;Rainforest Writers Village&lt;/a&gt; at Lake Quinalt in western Washington state. It was our first trip together in more than two years, the first time either of us had been to the Pacific Northwest, and our first to the states since my return to Canada last year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My hat goes off to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.fairwoodpress.com/index.html&#34;&gt;Patrick Swenson&lt;/a&gt;, who puts heart and soul into making the retreat an awesome event. 30+ writers from across North America gathered in one place for a long weekend of writing, eating, and drinking. People compare managing writers to herding cats, and the observation isn&amp;#8217;t far off from the truth. Andrea wrote a bunch of new words. I revised and plotted, finally completing and resubmitting a rewrite request of a story very dear to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We met some great new people that I&amp;#8217;m looking forward to keeping in contact with. We also got to visit with many of my fellow &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.inkpunks.com/&#34;&gt;Inkpunks&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#8211; &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/winnie3k&#34;&gt;Wendy&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/johnremy&#34;&gt;John&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/sandrawickham&#34;&gt;Sandra&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I made it a few talks, including Mary Robinette Kowal&amp;#8217;s on giving an effective reading (the second time I&amp;#8217;ve seen it). It was &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.twitter.com/jenniferbrozek&#34;&gt;Jennifer Brozek&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.twitter.com/erinmevans&#34;&gt;Erin Evans&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#8216; discussion of freelancing and multi-tasking that really tickled me, giving me some ideas on how I can manage my workload a bit more efficiently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The environs around the retreat were spectacular. It rained every day while we were there, as you&amp;#8217;d expect from a rainforest. Green moss covered tree limbs and roofs alike.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/stonetable/5530293285/&#34; title=&#34;DSC_7568 by Adam Israel, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5178/5530293285_a6e61ee085.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;333&#34; alt=&#34;DSC_7568&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/stonetable/5530882492/&#34; title=&#34;DSC_7584 by StoneTable, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5014/5530882492_67a8f76d04.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;333&#34; alt=&#34;DSC_7584&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/stonetable/5530878098/&#34; title=&#34;DSC_7567 by StoneTable, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5138/5530878098_4beecfd1b8.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;333&#34; alt=&#34;DSC_7567&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Worlds Largest Spruce tree was, indeed, huge. The pictures don&amp;#8217;t come close to showing just how epic it is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/stonetable/5530288341/&#34; title=&#34;DSC_7549 by StoneTable, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5099/5530288341_96a0224363.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;333&#34; alt=&#34;DSC_7549&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/stonetable/5530874446/&#34; title=&#34;DSC_7553 by StoneTable, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5058/5530874446_8ef0200f2a.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;333&#34; alt=&#34;DSC_7553&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We found the roaming herd of Elk on our first day I&amp;#8217;d forgotten to bring my camera. We found them grazing in a pasture the next afternoon. Judging by how calm they were towards us, I suspect a lot of people stop to stare at them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/stonetable/5530271147/&#34; title=&#34;DSC_7479 by StoneTable, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5015/5530271147_d1cf18b7ce.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;333&#34; alt=&#34;DSC_7479&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/stonetable/5530268267/&#34; title=&#34;DSC_7468 by StoneTable, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5014/5530268267_176a697324.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;333&#34; alt=&#34;DSC_7468&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The waterfalls were brilliant. I wish I&amp;#8217;d had my camera adjusted better to photograph them. As it was, the spray coated me and the lenses, making things a challenge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/stonetable/5530278193/&#34; title=&#34;DSC_7504 by StoneTable, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5179/5530278193_6c5e9e354e.jpg&#34; width=&#34;333&#34; height=&#34;500&#34; alt=&#34;DSC_7504&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We saw these odd structures built into the river some miles north of the retreat. Giant tree trunks hammered into the riverbed, and criss-crossed with more timber added to form what looked like a funeral pyre. It turns out that the local Indian tribe went to great lengths to build these as salmon breeding grounds a few years back. Judging by the bald eagles feeding nearby, I would say they were successful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/stonetable/5530282961/&#34; title=&#34;DSC_7526 by StoneTable, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5214/5530282961_7d23892548.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;333&#34; alt=&#34;DSC_7526&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/stonetable/5530867138/&#34; title=&#34;DSC_7523 by StoneTable, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5256/5530867138_11f8efbca4.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;333&#34; alt=&#34;DSC_7523&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/stonetable/sets/72157626150858561/&#34;&gt;More photos&lt;/a&gt; can be found on Flickr.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the retreat ended, we drove back to Portland. Along the way, we stopped for lunch and discovered that our flight that night was delayed and we were being offered a rebooking, which we hastily accepted. A day to explore Portland wasn&amp;#8217;t nearly enough but we did visit [Powell&amp;#8217;s Books][20], which caused me to exclaim, &amp;#8220;I need to quit my job so we can move here. Wait, scratch that. I need to apply for a job here and then move.&amp;#8221; We managed to survive the dinner involving an invasion of a hundred or more 8-12 year old girls from a national dance troupe, and capped off our visit with a yummy lunch with Wendy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The people we met in Portland were friendly and everyone we spoke to loved being there. It&amp;#8217;s somewhere we could see ourselves living down the road a bit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[20]: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.powells.com/&#34;&gt;http://www.powells.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SALE: Dog Days, to Crossed Genres</title>
      <link>http://dev.adamisrael.com/blog/2011/02/10/sale-dog-days-to-crossed-genres/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://dev.adamisrael.com/blog/2011/02/10/sale-dog-days-to-crossed-genres/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am pleased to announce that I&amp;#8217;ve sold my story, Dog Days, to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.crossedgenres.com/&#34;&gt;Crossed Genres&lt;/a&gt; for their March issue, Superheroes. This is the story I referenced in my latest &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.inkpunks.com&#34;&gt;Inkpunks&lt;/a&gt; post, [Writer’s Toolkit: Tarot Cards][3].&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m particularly tickled by this sale. It&amp;#8217;s my first acceptance post-Clarion, of a story I&amp;#8217;m particularly enamored with, to one of my favorite markets. Happy writer is happy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[3]: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.inkpunks.com/2011/02/07/writers-toolkit-tarot-cards/#content&#34;&gt;http://www.inkpunks.com/2011/02/07/writers-toolkit-tarot-cards/#content&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SALE: Indigo’s Gambit, to the EXTINCT anthology</title>
      <link>http://dev.adamisrael.com/blog/2011/02/10/sale-indigos-gambit-to-the-extinct-anthology/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://dev.adamisrael.com/blog/2011/02/10/sale-indigos-gambit-to-the-extinct-anthology/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.adamisrael.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/02/Extinct_Cover2.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-full wp-image-364 alignright&#34; title=&#34;Extinct Anthology&#34; src=&#34;http://www.adamisrael.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/02/Extinct_Cover2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coming on the heels of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.adamisrael.com/blog/2011/02/10/sale-dog-days-to-crossed-genres/&#34;&gt;my sale&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.crossedgenres.com/&#34;&gt;Crossed Genres&lt;/a&gt;, I can also announce that I&amp;#8217;ve sold the story, Indigo&amp;#8217;s Gambit, to the [EXTINCT anthology][4], to be published as an eBook later this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[4]: &lt;a href=&#34;http://phoenixsullivan.blogspot.com/p/extinct-call-for-submissions.html&#34;&gt;http://phoenixsullivan.blogspot.com/p/extinct-call-for-submissions.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>