<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Adam Israel</title>
    <link>http://adamisrael.com/tags/clarion/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Adam Israel</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© 2016 Adam Israel</copyright>
    <atom:link href="http://adamisrael.com/tags/clarion/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Clarion Write-a-thon</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2013/06/21/clarion-write-a-thon-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2013/06/21/clarion-write-a-thon-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It should be no surprise to anyone who knows me that the Clarion Writers Workshop is a thing near and dear to me. Attending the six-week workshop in 2010 was a milestone in my writing career. The annual &lt;a href=&#34;1&#34;&gt;write-a-thon&lt;/a&gt;, where writers commit to writing goals and ask friends, family,and strangers to pledge money to go towards funding the workshop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Saying &amp;#8220;please give money&amp;#8221; is something I do on very rare occasion, but this is something worthwhile. The Clarion Workshop is one of very few programs in the world for writers of genre fiction. Hundreds of students apply every year but only a handful get in. The instructors are among the most experienced authors in the field. Donations go to keeping the workshop running and supplying scholarships for students in need.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The write-a-thon runs for six weeks, along side the workshop in San Diego. It&amp;#8217;s an act of solidarity with this years class of writers and, as extra motivation, a public accountability of my goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year, I will spend the write-a-thon finishing my first novel. I&amp;#8217;ll be writing, by hand, 30,000 or so words, and transcribing the results into Scrivener along with the first 50,000. By the end, I will have a complete draft ready to be ripped apart, revised and rewritten. I&amp;#8217;ll even blog regular progress updates, which is more than I normally manage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you can &lt;a href=&#34;2&#34;&gt;sponsor me&lt;/a&gt;, one dollar or ten, you will have my gratitude and the satisfaction of knowing you&amp;#8217;re making a difference in the life of up and coming writers of science fiction and fantasy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publication – “Man Out of Time”</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2012/07/09/publication-man-out-of-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2012/07/09/publication-man-out-of-time/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I may burst with glee. Tomorrow is &lt;a href=&#34;1&#34;&gt;Nikola Tesla day&lt;/a&gt;. Today, the &lt;a href=&#34;2&#34;&gt;Mad Scientist Journal&lt;/a&gt; published my secret history of Tesla, &amp;#8220;&lt;a href=&#34;3&#34;&gt;Man Out of Time&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#8220;. I even have word that someone on Facebook commented that they thought the story was a &amp;#8220;great idea to run a game/one-shot on&amp;#8221;. &lt;a href=&#34;4&#34;&gt;Katie Nyborg&lt;/a&gt; did the fabulous illustration for the interior.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How much does this mean to me? Well, Tesla is my hero more so than any other historical figure ever. While other kids my age were dreaming of cars and getting lucky, I spent my high school years in the electronics lab building things and wishing one of them were a Tesla Coil. To research this particular story, I bought both poetry that Tesla had translated and his transcribed journals from the time periods covered at Colorado Springs, where part of this story takes place. It was important to try to place the events as close to historical fact as possible before veering off, as well as understanding how Tesla might have handled himself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This story was also one of my Clarion application stories, if you&amp;#8217;re curious about that sort of thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clarion Write-a-thon Week 1</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2012/07/02/clarion-write-a-thon-week-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2012/07/02/clarion-write-a-thon-week-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;table width=&#34;95%&#34; cellspacing=&#34;0&#34; cellpadding=&#34;0&#34;&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td valign=&#34;top&#34;&gt;
      &lt;strong&gt;Sun&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;

    &lt;td valign=&#34;top&#34;&gt;
      &lt;strong&gt;Mon&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;

    &lt;td valign=&#34;top&#34;&gt;
      &lt;strong&gt;Tue&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;

    &lt;td valign=&#34;middle&#34;&gt;
      &lt;strong&gt;Wed&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;

    &lt;td valign=&#34;middle&#34;&gt;
      &lt;strong&gt;Thu&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;

    &lt;td valign=&#34;middle&#34;&gt;
      &lt;strong&gt;Fri&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;

    &lt;td valign=&#34;middle&#34;&gt;
      &lt;strong&gt;Sat&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;

    &lt;td valign=&#34;middle&#34;&gt;
      &lt;strong&gt;Total&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;

    &lt;td valign=&#34;middle&#34;&gt;
      &lt;strong&gt;Avg&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;

  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td valign=&#34;top&#34;&gt;
      582
    &lt;/td&gt;

    &lt;td valign=&#34;top&#34;&gt;
      171
    &lt;/td&gt;

    &lt;td valign=&#34;top&#34;&gt;
      309
    &lt;/td&gt;

    &lt;td valign=&#34;middle&#34;&gt;
      473
    &lt;/td&gt;

    &lt;td valign=&#34;middle&#34;&gt;
      91
    &lt;/td&gt;

    &lt;td valign=&#34;middle&#34;&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;

    &lt;td valign=&#34;middle&#34;&gt;
      783
    &lt;/td&gt;

    &lt;td valign=&#34;middle&#34;&gt;
      2,409
    &lt;/td&gt;

    &lt;td valign=&#34;middle&#34;&gt;
      344
    &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A little bit of a rocky week, especially Friday. Ideally, I&amp;#8217;d like to average 1,000 words/day. That&amp;#8217;d be awesome. Life creeps up, with unavoidable things like responsibility and sleep but I have a secret that I&amp;#8217;ll share with you. Lean a little close. That&amp;#8217;s it, just a little closer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s a little maddening to miss your goals. I live by my TODO list and I hate leaving things unfinished at the end of the day. You can&amp;#8217;t beat yourself up over it, though. Make adjustments, if it&amp;#8217;s a chronic problem (like overcommitment). In the end, though, it comes down to one thing:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#39;embed-youtube&#39; style=&#39;text-align:center; display: block;&#39;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sponsors&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you, thank you, thank you. Several of you have made &lt;a href=&#34;1&#34;&gt;donations&lt;/a&gt; totaling $175 dollars, blowing away my personal expectations for fundraising for Clarion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Statistics&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know Scrivener Fu. And I use Project Targets like a boss. I fell short on my word count last week but I know exactly what I need to do to stay on target. Week two is already ahead of schedule:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table border=&#34;0&#34;&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      Yesterday
    &lt;/td&gt;

    &lt;td&gt;
      Today
    &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;

  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.adamisrael.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/07/Scrivener-07012012.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-807&#34; title=&#34;Scrivener-07012012&#34; src=&#34;http://www.adamisrael.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/07/Scrivener-07012012.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;314&#34; height=&#34;260&#34; srcset=&#34;//www.adamisrael.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/07/Scrivener-07012012-300x248.jpg 300w, //www.adamisrael.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/07/Scrivener-07012012.jpg 314w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 314px) 100vw, 314px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;

    &lt;td&gt;
      &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.adamisrael.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/07/Scrivener-annotated.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-812&#34; title=&#34;Scrivener-annotated&#34; src=&#34;http://www.adamisrael.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/07/Scrivener-annotated.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;314&#34; height=&#34;260&#34; srcset=&#34;//www.adamisrael.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/07/Scrivener-annotated-300x248.jpg 300w, //www.adamisrael.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/07/Scrivener-annotated.jpg 314w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 314px) 100vw, 314px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;

  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td colspan=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
      Resetting my Session Target each morning, I know the minimum I need to write to maintain my pace, and any overage will work in my favor the next day.
    &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, I&amp;#8217;m quite happy with the way things are going. I&amp;#8217;ve been doing a fair amount of revising, which is slowing things down a little bit but it needs to be done, especially if I want to start tormenting beta readers with a draft of this monster later this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;text-decoration: underline;&#34;&gt;Write-a-thon goal:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img title=&#34;Clarion Write-a-thon goal&#34; src=&#34;http://picometer.writertopia.com/words=3354&amp;target=30000&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;162&#34; height=&#34;35&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clarion Write-a-thon: Day 1</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2012/06/25/clarion-write-a-thon-day-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2012/06/25/clarion-write-a-thon-day-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;1&#34;&gt;Clarion Write-a-thon&lt;/a&gt; began yesterday. I got some decent writing time in, despite a late start to the day and having to confront a would-be pervert attempting to flash his private bits at my favorite writing spot. I expect the first several days of writing to go slow as I revise the first chapter of the novel, trying to set the right tone and pace. The 25k words I wrote during last year&amp;#8217;s Nanowrimo are, I realize, mostly outline but do span the length of the novel. My task now is to fill in the gaps where I rush through sections I was unsure of and take my time getting through the rest. Also, sub-plot. I have it and now I need to make it work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My pre write-a-thon novel stats:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;2&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the first day&amp;#8217;s session, which saw me revise most of chapter one, scene one:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;3&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A good start. I don&amp;#8217;t feel at all nervous about my goals like I did during Nanowrimo. 30k words over six weeks is a little more reasonable for me, yes, but I&amp;#8217;ve also spent more time thinking through this story and figuring out its structure. I&amp;#8217;m definitely more of an outliner when it comes to novels, and the extra time I&amp;#8217;ve spent in planning is paying off now.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clarion Write-a-Thon</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2012/06/13/clarion-write-a-thon/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2012/06/13/clarion-write-a-thon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Clarion Write-a-thon starts on June 24&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt;, running parallel to the six week workshop I attended in 2010. While this summers workshop students toil away in San Diego, I’ll be one of many writers helping to raise awareness and solicit donations to a cause we believe in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is a write-a-thon, anyway? It&amp;#8217;s just like a walk-a-thon. But instead of walking, we&amp;#8217;re writing, and instead of making pledges per mile, we&amp;#8217;re making pledges per word, chapter, or story. Writers get support, encouragement and motivation, and the option of joining a team with a writing mentor! Those who care about the writers in their life get a way to show their support. And money is raised for a literally fantastic cause &amp;#8212; the Clarion Science Fiction &amp;amp; Fantasy Writers&amp;#8217; Workshop. All donations are made through The Clarion Foundation, a 501&amp;copy;(3) non-profit organization, EIN #20-3114945.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll also be one of the aforementioned mentors this year, as part of Team Weaveworld. The teams are a new thing with the write-a-thon this year, as a way to provide support and motivation for those who want it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During this years write-a-thon, I’ll be continuing work on my novel-in-progress. My challenge is to write at least 1,000 words/day, 5 days/week, with an ultimate goal of 30,0000 words over the six weeks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;d love to raise tons and tons of money for Clarion, because I passionately believe in what they do (and did for me). This is a no pressure pitch on my part, though. &lt;a href=&#34;1&#34;&gt;Pledge&lt;/a&gt; what you feel comfortable with, knowing that you have my utmost thanks and appreciation for donating to something dear to my heart.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clarion Diego Write-a-thon</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2011/06/25/clarion-diego-write-a-thon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2011/06/25/clarion-diego-write-a-thon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Two things make this upcoming Monday special: it marks the beginning of the &lt;a href=&#34;1&#34;&gt;Clarion (San Diego) Write-a-thon&lt;/a&gt;, and my one year anniversary of attending the Clarion Workshop. Clarion was a significant event in my life. One way I can give back is by participating in the write-a-thon and raising money to help the program that helped me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For six weeks, we learned to write better (but still shitty!) first drafts. I wrote three new stories at Clarion, and revised two previously written ones. I think it only appropriate that, for my inaugural write-a-thon, I rewrite and/or revise those stories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“Longwalkers”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“A Murder of Crows”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“Control”, was “I Love You, Good Bye, I’ll See You Soon” *****&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“Recycled Dreams”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“Cradle of Hope”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One or two additional stories TBD&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everyone who donates, if they so choose, will receive a postcard with story bits, doodles, or whatever I feel like adding to it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your name will also be listed in the acknowledgements of a limited edition ebook (see below).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;$10&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For ten dollars or more, you’ll receive the above, plus a limited edition ebook containing:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My application essay&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My application stories&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The handwritten, first and revised versions of my Clarion stories&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A one year retrospective, post-Clarion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Extra bonus material&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;$25&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyone who pledges $25 or more will receive, in addition to the ebook, &lt;a href=&#34;2&#34;&gt;tuckerization&lt;/a&gt; in a future story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;$50&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For $50 or more, donors will receive the ebook, tuckerization, and I will give you a detailed critique of a story, up to 7,500 words.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;$100&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are able to donate $100 or more dollars, you&amp;#8217;ll receive all of the above, my never-ending gratitude, and I will write a story based on prompts that you provide.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not only am I dedicating the next six weeks to raising money for Clarion, I will also put matching funds towards a scholarship for a 2012 Clarion student of my choosing. Please visit my &lt;a href=&#34;3&#34;&gt;write-a-thon&lt;/a&gt; page to make your pledge and drop a note &lt;a href=&#34;4&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; to let me know where to send your postcard. I&amp;#8217;ll be in touch for any other details for your reward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Already rewritten and in circulation, but you&amp;#8217;ll still get both versions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Five things I learned at Clarion</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2011/01/22/five-things-i-learned-at-clarion/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2011/01/22/five-things-i-learned-at-clarion/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Via &lt;a href=&#34;1&#34;&gt;Jim Kelly&lt;/a&gt;, by way of &lt;a href=&#34;2&#34;&gt;Tim Pratt&lt;/a&gt;, and because I am desperately avoiding the writing I need to do tonight, here are a few things I learned (or confirmed) while at Clarion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I write stories about the human condition. It&amp;#8217;s the people that interest me, their struggles that move me, and their pain that moves my pen. So, I guess that explains my fascination with people-watching.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Find what works for and stick with it. I&amp;#8217;m a slow writer and writing my first drafts (and sometimes second) longhand doesn&amp;#8217;t help, but it&amp;#8217;s how I get things done. It&amp;#8217;s hard, sometimes, seeing my peers whip out short stories in an evening, but everyone is unique and I&amp;#8217;d like to think that it shows in the end product.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Trusting myself. That&amp;#8217;s an ongoing process, but Clarion was a milestone in my self-confidence. Consider the odds when you apply: the competition is fierce (I think my class had 170+ applications) and only 17 are chosen. To be accepted means you beat out some very tough competition (and if you didn&amp;#8217;t get in, apply again!).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sleep. At times, Clarion is paced like a convention, only six weeks long. Writers, when clustered together, like to talk and drink, and tend to repeat themselves. You find ways to squeeze in extra shut eye, like skipping breakfast in the cafeteria and eating a quick bite in your kitchenette.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read quickly, read critically. There are more stories to critique and you have a story due this week. I still think I suck at time management, but I&amp;#8217;m way better now.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once there, you&amp;#8217;re living and breathing the craft for six weeks. Find out if you have what it takes to be a writer full-time, aside from the whole being able to support yourself nuisance. You learn from some of the best writers and editors in our field. Meet and bond with a group of up and coming writers like yourself. &lt;a href=&#34;3&#34;&gt;Clarion&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;4&#34;&gt;Clarion West&lt;/a&gt; are open for applications right now. What are you waiting for?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Travel ahoy</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2010/10/10/travel-ahoy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2010/10/10/travel-ahoy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s a good feeling to put the word END after the last paragraph of a manuscript. This story was born week five of Clarion but I couldn&amp;#8217;t make it work then. A little bit of time away and with four days of sporadic effort, it&amp;#8217;s a story. Rough around the edges like any first draft but I expect those will be caught when I sent it to beta readers later this week. Shitty first draft or not, I&amp;#8217;m pleased with how it&amp;#8217;s turned out so far.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Project: Sex/magic story, now with more poly love, a plump dominatrix, a Chicago swinger&amp;#8217;s club, and one pissed off magician, tentatively titled &lt;span style=&#34;text-decoration: underline;&#34;&gt;The Way Out is Through&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;New words written: 484&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reason for stopping: End of story&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;1&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tomorrow is a travel day for me. Back to Santa Monica for a week of work and, with luck, more success in finding a room or apartment for rent. While I&amp;#8217;m galavanting across the country, I&amp;#8217;ll be outlining my story for the &lt;a href=&#34;2&#34;&gt;20Spec anthology&lt;/a&gt;, which is open for submissions on October 11th. The plan is to get &lt;span style=&#34;text-decoration: underline;&#34;&gt;The Way Out is Through&lt;/span&gt; sent off to a couple of beta readers and then work on the first draft of my tale of Romani revenge, Eye of the People.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aren’t you that guy that went to that writing thing?</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2010/09/08/arent-you-that-guy-that-went-to-that-writing-thing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2010/09/08/arent-you-that-guy-that-went-to-that-writing-thing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;By Internet speeds, it&amp;#8217;s been years since Clarion ended and not just a month. And the neglectful blogger I&amp;#8217;ve been, it was six weeks before that since I last posted anything resembling an update. It&amp;#8217;s time I said &lt;em&gt;something&lt;/em&gt;, don&amp;#8217;t you think? Well yes, but not exactly what you might expect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eighteen people met as strangers in late June, in San Diego, and became a family. Along the way, aunts and uncles and cousins, and a grandfather or two, who guided us through the Clarion process. Perhaps the hardest part about Clarion wasn&amp;#8217;t the coming but the going and the saying of goodbyes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know some of you will find this post while searching for words of wisdom from past Clarion students. Maybe I&amp;#8217;ll have something more profound to say between now and then. Right now the experience is still too near to me to properly put it into the kind of meaningful words that I would use to inspire you. Six weeks of doing any one thing in concentration is intense, and internalizing all that knowledge can take years. I&amp;#8217;m reading, writing, and editing. I&amp;#8217;m not rushing the process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the month since the workshop ended, I&amp;#8217;ve only been home for a few days. My day job underwent some major restructuring over the summer, which included setting up a new office near Los Angeles and I&amp;#8217;ve been commuting from Chicago on a near-weekly basis since my return. That&amp;#8217;s given me time to contemplate, but not enough time to overthink. What I&amp;#8217;ve come here to say is, yeah, I&amp;#8217;m that guy that went to that writing thing. Some day, I&amp;#8217;ll have something smarter to say about the experience.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It begins</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2010/06/28/it-begins/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2010/06/28/it-begins/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This will be my last communique for six weeks. Despite some weather delays in Chicago, I made it to San Diego and am ensconced on the UCSD campus. I&amp;#8217;m as prepared as I can be for a very intense experience and that means throwing myself into it completely. No blogging, no LiveJournal or Facebook, nor Twitter. I will be in the dark until my return, so keep the joint in good shape until I&amp;#8217;m back.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clarion 2010</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2010/03/15/clarion-2010-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2010/03/15/clarion-2010-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve been sent word that I can publicly announce the news I&amp;#8217;ve been sitting on since last week: I have been accepted into the 2010 &lt;a href=&#34;1&#34;&gt;Clarion Workshop&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More later, after the celebration has ended.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clarion 2010</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2010/03/07/clarion-2010/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2010/03/07/clarion-2010/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Believe it or not, I’m still a little under the weather. I’m beginning to suspect I had the hamthrax. Five weeks out and I’m just now starting to feel like myself again. All it really means is that I’m sleeping way more than usual, drinking a gallon of water a day, and a bit behind in my correspondence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So better late than never, I’m happy to announce that I’ve applied to &lt;a href=&#34;1&#34;&gt;Clarion&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;2&#34;&gt;Clarion West&lt;/a&gt;. These are kind of a big deal as far as writing workshops go. They receive hundreds of applicants every year and only a handful are accepted. The odds are not in my favor but I’m keeping my fingers crossed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even if I do get accepted, there are a lot of obstacles standing in my way. There’s the house for sale in Illinois and a few lingering divorce debts that must be paid before anything else. I’m working hard at that and things are moving in the right direction. Then there’s taking six weeks off of work. I think I can pull that off, but it means I’m going to be pulling a lot of long hours in the months beforehand to make up for it. A worthy sacrifice, if I get the call.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I only have one hard deadline coming up in March. The next quarter of Writers of the Future closes at the end of the month and I plan to have a third consecutive story ready for them. Aside from that I’ll be doing lots and lots of editing. I’m calling a moratorium on new stories until I get some of these drafts revised and into a submission-worthy state.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good luck shout outs to my tribe mates, &lt;a href=&#34;3&#34;&gt;Christie&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;4&#34;&gt;John&lt;/a&gt;, who also applied to Clarion. I’m keeping my fingers crossed for all of us.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deadlines cometh</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2010/02/24/deadlines-cometh/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2010/02/24/deadlines-cometh/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;February is coming to a close and I&amp;#8217;m scrambling like mad. Clarion closes to applications on March 1st. One application story is done. I have a second one more or less ready, but I&amp;#8217;m debating a last minute replacement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m putting the grind wheel and polish to my as yet untitled story for the &lt;a href=&#34;1&#34;&gt;Scheherazade&amp;#8217;s Facade&lt;/a&gt; anthology, due February 28th.  It&amp;#8217;s shaping up into something that makes me happy. I pushed myself when writing this and for that reason I&amp;#8217;m also considering using it as my second Clarion story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ll be getting back to schedule after these deadlines have passed. I&amp;#8217;m behind on updating my goals and schedule but the progress I&amp;#8217;ve made, despite being knocked on my ass for a few weeks, is satisfying.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>