<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Clarion on Adam Israel</title>
    <link>http://adamisrael.com/tags/clarion/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Clarion on Adam Israel</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© 2016 Adam Israel</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://adamisrael.com/tags/clarion/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Clarion Write-a-thon</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2013/06/21/clarion-write-a-thon-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2013/06/21/clarion-write-a-thon-2/</guid>
      <description>It should be no surprise to anyone who knows me that the Clarion Writers Workshop is a thing near and dear to me. Attending the six-week workshop in 2010 was a milestone in my writing career. The annual write-a-thon, where writers commit to writing goals and ask friends, family,and strangers to pledge money to go towards funding the workshop.
Saying &amp;#8220;please give money&amp;#8221; is something I do on very rare occasion, but this is something worthwhile.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publication – “Man Out of Time”</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2012/07/09/publication-man-out-of-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2012/07/09/publication-man-out-of-time/</guid>
      <description>I may burst with glee. Tomorrow is Nikola Tesla day. Today, the Mad Scientist Journal published my secret history of Tesla, &amp;#8220;Man Out of Time&amp;#8220;. I even have word that someone on Facebook commented that they thought the story was a &amp;#8220;great idea to run a game/one-shot on&amp;#8221;. Katie Nyborg did the fabulous illustration for the interior.
How much does this mean to me? Well, Tesla is my hero more so than any other historical figure ever.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clarion Write-a-thon Week 1</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2012/07/02/clarion-write-a-thon-week-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2012/07/02/clarion-write-a-thon-week-1/</guid>
      <description>Sun  Mon  Tue  Wed  Thu  Fri  Sat  Total  Avg    582  171  309  473  91   783  2,409  344    A little bit of a rocky week, especially Friday. Ideally, I&amp;#8217;d like to average 1,000 words/day. That&amp;#8217;d be awesome. Life creeps up, with unavoidable things like responsibility and sleep but I have a secret that I&amp;#8217;ll share with you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clarion Write-a-thon: Day 1</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2012/06/25/clarion-write-a-thon-day-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2012/06/25/clarion-write-a-thon-day-1/</guid>
      <description>The Clarion Write-a-thon began yesterday. I got some decent writing time in, despite a late start to the day and having to confront a would-be pervert attempting to flash his private bits at my favorite writing spot. I expect the first several days of writing to go slow as I revise the first chapter of the novel, trying to set the right tone and pace. The 25k words I wrote during last year&amp;#8217;s Nanowrimo are, I realize, mostly outline but do span the length of the novel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clarion Write-a-Thon</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2012/06/13/clarion-write-a-thon/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2012/06/13/clarion-write-a-thon/</guid>
      <description>The Clarion Write-a-thon starts on June 24th, running parallel to the six week workshop I attended in 2010. While this summers workshop students toil away in San Diego, I’ll be one of many writers helping to raise awareness and solicit donations to a cause we believe in.
 What is a write-a-thon, anyway? It&amp;#8217;s just like a walk-a-thon. But instead of walking, we&amp;#8217;re writing, and instead of making pledges per mile, we&amp;#8217;re making pledges per word, chapter, or story.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clarion Diego Write-a-thon</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2011/06/25/clarion-diego-write-a-thon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2011/06/25/clarion-diego-write-a-thon/</guid>
      <description>Two things make this upcoming Monday special: it marks the beginning of the Clarion (San Diego) Write-a-thon, and my one year anniversary of attending the Clarion Workshop. Clarion was a significant event in my life. One way I can give back is by participating in the write-a-thon and raising money to help the program that helped me.
For six weeks, we learned to write better (but still shitty!) first drafts. I wrote three new stories at Clarion, and revised two previously written ones.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Five things I learned at Clarion</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2011/01/22/five-things-i-learned-at-clarion/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2011/01/22/five-things-i-learned-at-clarion/</guid>
      <description>Via Jim Kelly, by way of Tim Pratt, and because I am desperately avoiding the writing I need to do tonight, here are a few things I learned (or confirmed) while at Clarion.
 I write stories about the human condition. It&amp;#8217;s the people that interest me, their struggles that move me, and their pain that moves my pen. So, I guess that explains my fascination with people-watching. Find what works for and stick with it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Travel ahoy</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2010/10/10/travel-ahoy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2010/10/10/travel-ahoy/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;#8217;s a good feeling to put the word END after the last paragraph of a manuscript. This story was born week five of Clarion but I couldn&amp;#8217;t make it work then. A little bit of time away and with four days of sporadic effort, it&amp;#8217;s a story. Rough around the edges like any first draft but I expect those will be caught when I sent it to beta readers later this week.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aren’t you that guy that went to that writing thing?</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2010/09/08/arent-you-that-guy-that-went-to-that-writing-thing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2010/09/08/arent-you-that-guy-that-went-to-that-writing-thing/</guid>
      <description>By Internet speeds, it&amp;#8217;s been years since Clarion ended and not just a month. And the neglectful blogger I&amp;#8217;ve been, it was six weeks before that since I last posted anything resembling an update. It&amp;#8217;s time I said something, don&amp;#8217;t you think? Well yes, but not exactly what you might expect.
Eighteen people met as strangers in late June, in San Diego, and became a family. Along the way, aunts and uncles and cousins, and a grandfather or two, who guided us through the Clarion process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It begins</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2010/06/28/it-begins/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2010/06/28/it-begins/</guid>
      <description>This will be my last communique for six weeks. Despite some weather delays in Chicago, I made it to San Diego and am ensconced on the UCSD campus. I&amp;#8217;m as prepared as I can be for a very intense experience and that means throwing myself into it completely. No blogging, no LiveJournal or Facebook, nor Twitter. I will be in the dark until my return, so keep the joint in good shape until I&amp;#8217;m back.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clarion 2010</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2010/03/15/clarion-2010-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2010/03/15/clarion-2010-2/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#8217;ve been sent word that I can publicly announce the news I&amp;#8217;ve been sitting on since last week: I have been accepted into the 2010 Clarion Workshop.
More later, after the celebration has ended.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clarion 2010</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2010/03/07/clarion-2010/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2010/03/07/clarion-2010/</guid>
      <description>Believe it or not, I’m still a little under the weather. I’m beginning to suspect I had the hamthrax. Five weeks out and I’m just now starting to feel like myself again. All it really means is that I’m sleeping way more than usual, drinking a gallon of water a day, and a bit behind in my correspondence.
So better late than never, I’m happy to announce that I’ve applied to Clarion and Clarion West.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deadlines cometh</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2010/02/24/deadlines-cometh/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2010/02/24/deadlines-cometh/</guid>
      <description>February is coming to a close and I&amp;#8217;m scrambling like mad. Clarion closes to applications on March 1st. One application story is done. I have a second one more or less ready, but I&amp;#8217;m debating a last minute replacement.
I&amp;#8217;m putting the grind wheel and polish to my as yet untitled story for the Scheherazade&amp;#8217;s Facade anthology, due February 28th. It&amp;#8217;s shaping up into something that makes me happy. I pushed myself when writing this and for that reason I&amp;#8217;m also considering using it as my second Clarion story.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>