<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Booklife on Adam Israel</title>
    <link>http://adamisrael.com/tags/booklife/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Booklife on Adam Israel</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© 2016 Adam Israel</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://adamisrael.com/tags/booklife/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 3: Practice Stories</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2010/01/22/week-3-practice-stories/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2010/01/22/week-3-practice-stories/</guid>
      <description>Another kind of successful week &amp;#8212; 3,237 new words, bringing the years total to 10,404.
I&amp;#8217;m still struggling with revisions. I got critiques back on two of my stories this week. The crits were brutally honest, the way I like them, and resonated with things I&amp;#8217;d been trying to figure out myself. One thing I&amp;#8217;m uncovering is that I don&amp;#8217;t read critically enough. Having a third party point out an issue is great.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 2: A step slightly staggered</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2010/01/16/week-2-a-step-slightly-staggered/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2010/01/16/week-2-a-step-slightly-staggered/</guid>
      <description>A new short story and a flash fiction drafted, and a second short story underway. Over 7,500 new words this year, with my average rising to 509 words/day. The Honorable Mention nod and a personal rejection also came in. The year is off to a good start.
I&amp;#8217;m still struggling with revisions. I failed my weekly goals this week, getting almost no editing done nor my outline for the Dollhouse essay.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 1: Knock on wood</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2010/01/08/week-1-knock-on-wood/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2010/01/08/week-1-knock-on-wood/</guid>
      <description>When I started out following Booklife and documenting my writing progress, I suspected the first few weeks would either be really easy or really hard. Establishing a habit takes times and it&amp;#8217;s easy to make excuses to skip writing. We all hear or use them &amp;#8212; I&amp;#8217;m too busy, too much day job work, kids/family, etc. Then there&amp;#8217;s the Resolutionists, who make a bunch of goals at the beginning of the year and waver after a few weeks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Achievements and goals</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2010/01/03/achievements-and-goals/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2010/01/03/achievements-and-goals/</guid>
      <description>On the heels of yesterdays post about Booklife and my personal mission statement, I have added My Booklife to the sidebar. From here, I have posted and will keep updated my public weekly, monthly, 1 year and 5 year goals. I&amp;#8217;ve also included my list of career achievements.
I&amp;#8217;m feeling pretty good about how things are shaping. I&amp;#8217;m starting the year with a more or less clean slate; new domain, new blog, and new goals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In the beginning, there was the Mission Statement</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2010/01/03/in-the-beginning-there-was-the-mission-statement/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2010/01/03/in-the-beginning-there-was-the-mission-statement/</guid>
      <description>I am horrible with deadlines. In high school I was forced to take a special class on time management because I never turned anything in on time. It&amp;#8217;s one of those things that I struggle with on a daily basis. Occasionally I discover something useful that helps, like Things, that help me keep track of the things I need to be doing. The most recent one was Jeff VanderMeer&amp;#8216;s Booklife.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>