<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Immigration on Adam Israel</title>
    <link>http://adamisrael.com/tags/immigration/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Immigration on Adam Israel</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© 2016 Adam Israel</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://adamisrael.com/tags/immigration/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>111 Weeks</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2013/09/19/111-weeks/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2013/09/19/111-weeks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;To be exact, it&amp;#8217;s been 783 days since we filed for my Canadian Permanent Residence and I am happy to announce that it is official done. We have just walked out of the Immigration Centre in Windsor, Ontario, Social Insurance Number in hand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess this makes me an expatriate; an American Citizen permanently living abroad, which is kind of cool. I&amp;#8217;ve been thinking a lot about getting a tattoo to commemorate the experience. More on that later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;#8217;s been a lot of stress involved around this process, most notably the difficulty traveling back to the US. In a few weeks, when I have the official card in hand, I&amp;#8217;ll be free to cross the border without fear of being turned away and having to restart the immigration process. That&amp;#8217;s going to be a cathartic experience, finally going back to visit my family and friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that I&amp;#8217;m all official, we can start thinking about normal, grown-up things like buying a house, and getting all of our stuff out of storage back in Illinois.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two years and pocket change</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2012/11/26/two-years-and-pocket-change/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2012/11/26/two-years-and-pocket-change/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Two years and two days ago, I started a journey from Santa Monica, California by foot, bus, train, and plane. Many hours later, I reached Detroit and was met by my friend Katni, who drove me through the Detroit-Windsor tunnel where, six months after being kicked out, I re-entered Canada and was reunited with Andrea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being home still feels really good.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dipping into Canadian Immigration/Politics</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2012/03/05/dipping-into-canadian-immigrationpolitics/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2012/03/05/dipping-into-canadian-immigrationpolitics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve been following the news regarding Canadian Immigration pretty closely &amp;#8212; not surprising considering my immigrant status. Last week &lt;a href=&#34;1&#34;&gt;this article in the Globe and Mail&lt;/a&gt; talks about the percentage of immigrants who settle in Ontario vs. other provinces, which kind of bored me. What was interesting, though, were two issues in the continued fight against immigration fraud. When Andrea and I filled out our application, most of our time was spent collecting evidence to prove our relationship &amp;#8212; records of emails, phone calls, meetings between us, friends, and family, etc. It&amp;#8217;s extensive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Citizenship and Immigration Minister Jason Kenney &lt;a href=&#34;2&#34;&gt;announced&lt;/a&gt; Friday a government crackdown on marriage fraudsters: people who marry and enter Canada under spousal sponsorship, only to abandon their partners shortly thereafter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[..]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sponsored spouses will also be restricted from sponsoring others for five years – a change effective immediately. This is meant to put an end to the “revolving door” of serial marriage, sponsorship and divorce, Mr. Kenney said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basically, foreigners have been wooing Canadians into marriage in order to get permanent residence and absconding once they have it. Some unscrupulous folk, in turn, see this as an opportunity and have been marrying for profit, in exchange for legal status. Good that they&amp;#8217;re fixing this loophole. Surprised it&amp;#8217;s taken this long. Saddened that it&amp;#8217;s necessary in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last realization might have led to a discussion of &lt;a href=&#34;3&#34;&gt;Dungeons &amp;amp; Dragons character alignments&lt;/a&gt;. I am totally &lt;a href=&#34;4&#34;&gt;Lawful Good&lt;/a&gt;, btw. If I stop and think about it, I know people can be dicks and do horrible, horrible things but on an individual level its hard for me to fathom this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;#8217;s another pending change to immigration law:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Starting this summer, those who are sponsored by their spouses to come to Canada will only be given temporary resident status for two years before they can gain permanent residency. If, during that period, the government discovers the marriage was one of convenience, the individual will be denied permanent residency. The new policy will include a provision to protect spousal abuse victims, who may be reluctant to end their marriages out of fear of jeopardizing their chances at gaining permanent resident status.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;5&#34;&gt;fine print&lt;/a&gt; clarifies that the temporary resident status would only applies to couples who&amp;#8217;ve been in a relationship less than two years when they file for sponsorship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
  This change wouldn&amp;#8217;t apply to us because we&amp;#8217;d been married for two and a half year when we filed, and as long as there are no complications with our application, I think we&amp;#8217;ll have our approval sometime around May. It does raise some questions, though.
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you&amp;#8217;re going applying for permanent residence in-country, you can&amp;#8217;t help but feel like a non-entity. I was able to get on &lt;a href=&#34;6&#34;&gt;Ontario Reciprocal &lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.drivetest.ca/en/license/exchangeReciprocal.aspx&#34;&gt;Drivers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.drivetest.ca/en/license/exchangeReciprocal.aspx&#34;&gt; License&lt;/a&gt; (eventually), but I can&amp;#8217;t work so I can&amp;#8217;t pay taxes. Without paying taxes here, I get no benefits, like health insurance and I can&amp;#8217;t buy it, either. Supplemental insurance is for visitors with fixed times of entry and exit, and even if I could finagle that, they only a) cover emergency room visits and b) are cost-prohibitive when you&amp;#8217;re on a very tight budget.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My visitor visa doesn&amp;#8217;t cover me going to school, either, so that excludes any formal continued education; I&amp;#8217;m mostly self-taught, but it would be nice to take some classes. You know, maybe something like French to help me better integrate? There isn&amp;#8217;t a huge French population in our part of Ontario, but I have a maybe, possible job offer waiting for me when I do have my permanent residence in Ottawa, a stone&amp;#8217;s throw from Quebec and it would sure be nice to get more of a leg up on top of the other stuff I&amp;#8217;m teaching myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;#8217;s a lot of putting life on hold. We want to find a place of our own. Take some classes together. Have kids. It&amp;#8217;s next to impossible to do any of that, though, until I can do my part.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the time our application is approved, I&amp;#8217;ll have been living in Canada for almost 18 months. I may have to wait another two years before I can apply for citizenship and you can be damn sure I will be as soon as I&amp;#8217;m eligible. Under the new plan, an applicant may have to wait a year to get a temporary residence permit, two years to earn their permanent residence permit, and then another two years to be able to apply for citizenship &amp;#8212; effectively five years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You could argue that having a residence permit is not much different than having citizenship and I&amp;#8217;m not sure all of the differences but it includes the ability to vote, which is kind of a big deal, at least for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;#8217;t think there are any easy solutions. Fraud is fraud and I&amp;#8217;d like to flay the soles of anyone caught red-handed. I would like to see, though, a better solution for those of us who are trying to make a new life here. Make it easier to obtain a work permit &amp;#8212; and pay taxes &amp;#8212; while I&amp;#8217;m waiting. Let me volunteer, or study, and integrate better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I know Immigration-Fu</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2011/07/28/i-know-immigration-fu/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2011/07/28/i-know-immigration-fu/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The inches-thick stack of paper greeting us on Tuesday only needed one thing: signatures. With today&amp;#8217;s batch of packages to Fedex, my application for immigration to Canada is on its way north, where it will sit in processing for the next nine or ten months. Around April or May next year, I will start frantically refreshing the status page to see if it changes from &amp;#8216;in process&amp;#8217; to &amp;#8216;approved&amp;#8217; and we wait for the final paperwork to come in the mail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only downside to the long progress is that travel over the border becomes even more challenging. If I were, and were turned away as I have been before, my application would be considered abandoned and I&amp;#8217;d have to start all over again. For that reason, we have canceled any plans to travel state-side until next spring or so. I&amp;#8217;m very saddened by this, as it means I&amp;#8217;ll miss the wedding of a very dear friend and &lt;a href=&#34;1&#34;&gt;Renovation&lt;/a&gt; but them&amp;#8217;s the breaks.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The good, the bad, and the awesome</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2011/05/11/the-good-the-bad-and-the-awesome/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2011/05/11/the-good-the-bad-and-the-awesome/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The package of mail from the states that I&amp;#8217;ve been anxiously waiting for arrived today. I now have the last of the paperwork I need to continue with my permanent residence application, my &lt;a href=&#34;1&#34;&gt;Square&lt;/a&gt; reader, so I can accept credit card payments, and the sealed letter from the Illinois DMV so I can get my Ontario drivers license.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We drive to the nearest driving center with the sealed letter in hand. It was an ordeal just getting the letter sent; IL required a self-addressed stamped envelope with a money order to pay the paperwork handling fee. Included in what we send them was a Driving Record Abstract Request Form. Basically, a copy of my drivers record to show when I was first licensed and any tickets/accidents/etc on my record. Pretty straightforward stuff, you would think.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The very nice lady opened the letter and scanned it for the information she needed. My heart sunk when she looked back up and shook her head. Illinois, as it turns out, listed the date I was originally licensed as July, 2009, when I last &lt;em&gt;renewed&lt;/em&gt; my license, not July 1992 as I was expecting. Because Illinois showed I was licensed less than two years, no license for me (without having to retake all the tests).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we started this little adventure, I called the Illinois DMV to try to get them to fax the paperwork. No go; it&amp;#8217;s against their policy unless requested by another state&amp;#8217;s DMV, on their letterhead, and Ontario has a policy against that. My choices were given as visit a DMV office in Illinois or mail the requested form, which I did. Tomorrow, I get to start the phone calls all over again to try straightening this out. One day, we&amp;#8217;ll be able to get a car again, but not today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While we were in town, I stopped by the used book stores. There&amp;#8217;s this &lt;a href=&#34;2&#34;&gt;article on NPR&lt;/a&gt; about The Stars My Destination that was mentioned on Twitter yesterday, which reminded me that I&amp;#8217;ve meant to read it. I picked up that and The Demolished Man, both by Alfred Bester, Ten Thousand Light-Years from Home, a short story collection by James Tiptree, Jr., and a prize that I will cherish forever &amp;#8212; a &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;first edition UK printing&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, hard cover with a dustcover jacket, of one of my favorite novels, Weaveworld by Clive Barker, for $2.00.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That almost makes up for the pain of being from the state of corn, corruption and unbalanced budgets.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tears in the Rain</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2010/05/12/tears-in-the-rain/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2010/05/12/tears-in-the-rain/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve spent the last few days in a work and stress-induced fugue state, trying to wrap my head around things. Andrea and family went to meet with our immigration person on Monday. The only sure way that I’ll be allowed back into Canada is for us to file for immigration first. That sounds easier and quicker than it actually is. We’re facing up to a few months before that can happen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The paperwork portion isn’t difficult, just painstaking. Most of it is filled out already. It boils down to money, the main reason why we hadn’t filed sooner. Until the house in Illinois sells, I’m stuck paying it’s mortgage and basic utilities and upkeep. On top of the maintenance I’m paying from the divorce (only 15 or so months to go), that leaves little in the way of extra cash.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s also a criminal background check that I need to order from the FBI, as part of the immigration process. No worries there; I have an unblemished record. The painful part of that is the big bold “please allow thirteen weeks for processing” on their website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The plan:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Send off the request for my background check, since that may take up to three months. Get all of the paperwork filled out, get my fingerprint card, and find a local doctor that can do the immigration exam. Hurry up and wait.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The house here is mostly empty. Most of the furniture was sold to pay bills. I’m going to spend the next couple weekends packing up what remains in the garage and basement, getting the house completely empty, and selling the last few things that I won’t be taking with me or can easily be replaced. That way, the only thing left to do when we get an offer is to sign the papers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the summer coming, anything I can do to make the house look prettier will help. If I need to muck around the lawn on my hands and knees to pluck dandelions and plant flowers, I will. At this point, I’m willing to go door to door and ask if anyone’s interested in buying a house.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not sure what more I can do to sell the house faster, other than lower the price below my break even point. That’s an option I’m looking into, if I can work the logistics. People have been coming to look at it but no one’s been interested enough to make an offer. The high property taxes are not helping, either. I’m open to creative suggestions. A short-sale or going into foreclosure aren’t an option, by court decree.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My weekdays (and nights) are filled with work. It’s the one thing in my control that I can do to bring in more money. It’ll come, but it’ll take a bit of time. Between this and Clarion, the odds of me getting home before August are slim. Possible, but unlikely as much as I wish it so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next couple weeks will be filled with the day job, trips to various doctors appointments and tests (trying to pinpoint what’s wrong with my autoimmune system), house work, and paper pushing. In between I’m scrambling to read for Clarion and keep up with the writing. Hopefully this summer brings the end of the outstanding divorce issues that have been hanging over us like a storm cloud and we can start the process of getting back on our feet.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>To fight the horde, sing and cry: Valhalla, I am coming!</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2010/05/08/to-fight-the-horde-sing-and-cry-valhalla-i-am-coming/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2010/05/08/to-fight-the-horde-sing-and-cry-valhalla-i-am-coming/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There’s so much that’s happened in the last twenty-four hours that I scarcely know where to start. For the uninitiated, I am American and my wife, Andrea, is Canadian. I have a house in Illinois, empty and for sale by court order from a previous marriage. In August of last year, my wife and I moved in with her Mom in Ontario, Canada. Prior that we had been living with my Dad in Wisconsin, in his three bedroom trailer, with our three large dogs and four cats, helping him recover from major back surgery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We went to Ontario with the intention of it being a temporary stay. The company I’ve worked for the past five years is based in California. I’ve worked from home every day of that but there was talk of me moving closer to the office. We’ve debated pros and cons of this over the months, but half of my salary still goes to maintenance to my ex-wife (for another 15 or so months) so the finances to do any kind of move, while still paying mortgage on a house I can’t live in, can’t short sell and can’t let go into foreclosure by court order under threat of imprisonment, limits us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two months ago, we made the decision to stay in Ontario and scraped together enough money to retain an immigration consultant who used to work for the Canadian government, as an Immigration Officer, Area Manager for the Department of Citizenship and Immigration, and later a district Adjudicator with the Government of Canada&amp;#8217;s Immigration and Refugee Board (for over twenty years). The immigration process is kind of a big deal and I did not want to screw up something so important, even if it takes us longer to scrape enough together to have it done this way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had our initial consultation and got copies of all of the paperwork we needed to fill out, and we needed to make an appointment to come back so I could go across the border and back through Immigration, meet my consultant and wife and fill out a visitor record to make things official and travel back and forth without issue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right after that first consultation, I headed to the states for the beginnings of the medical hell I’ve been going through. That took much longer than expected. I came back to Canada for two weeks, with little energy to do much more than work or sleep, and then headed to Dearborn, MI on Tuesday of this week for three days of company meetings. Last night, I headed back to the border, expecting a smooth crossing and looking forward to home cooking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I knew there was trouble when the border guard told me it would be a minute and frowned. He handed me back my passport with a yellow slip of paper and told me I needed to go inside and talk to Immigration. I was nervous, but as far as I was concerned I was doing nothing wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first person (Immigration Agent A) I spoke to took all my information, essentially what I said above, and told me that I have been living and working illegally in Canada. Flabbergast doesn’t begin to describe what I felt. She told me that Andrea needed to come there with the paperwork to prove that we were working on my immigration or she was denying entry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I called home; Andrea doesn’t drive and the family car just lost its muffler so that sparked a minor crisis of car swapping. Two hours, some rude remarks and an eye roll from Agent A, Andrea and family arrived with our documents. At this point I thought it would be a short delay and we’d be on our way, lessons learned. Silly me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By this time, the lobby had filled with people and there was a shift change. We waited a while for turn in line and presented our documents and restated our case to Agent B. B. seemed to share the same opinion as A., that I was an illegal foreign national. Both maintained that I should have filed paperwork shortly after Andrea and I married, not more than a year later. B. tells us that to immigrate to Canada I need a sponsor and that Andrea does not qualify to be my sponsor, which is not what I’ve been lead to believe. We’re then sent out to the lobby, and later called in individually to be interviewed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We don’t know what to think at this point. It’s clear that the border thinks I’m doing things wrong. Heck, maybe I am. That sure wasn’t my intention. Andrea and I are just barely holding it together, running through the what ifs. We think we have sufficient evidence to show that we are working through the process, even if we have been slow about it. Eventually I get called in again and directed to a supervisor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Agent B has written her report against me and the manager makes the final decision. I tell him everything that’s happened, from the beginning. He tells me that there are three options; I can be held over for a hearing, deported and banned from entering Canada for one year, or be allowed to leave of my own accord. Once more back to the waiting room.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the last time, my name is called over the loudspeaker. I’ve now been sitting in the Immigration office for six hours and haven’t eaten for fourteen. I’m tired, scared, and in despair. I was still clinging desperately to a shred of hope but I knew, as I stepped up to the window, that the effort was in vain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fact that we produced paperwork showing that we were working through the immigration process, even if it wasn’t filed, was the only thing that kept me from being held over or outright departed. He gives me paperwork to sign, and print out from their manual that shows why they claim Andrea cannot support me. They say that Andrea must make at least 22k a year in order to be my sponsor, regardless of the fact that I have a full-time job, and will continue to have one when I move to Canada. In fact, I’m told on several occasions that I won’t be allowed to work while I’m being sponsored.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As it stands, I was allowed to voluntarily leave Canada with the clothes on my back and what I had in my truck &amp;#8211; two dirty t-shirts, socks, and sundry. A book, my laptop, fountain pen, and moleskins, and that nights does of medicine. I had to say my goodbyes to Andrea and her mom and drive back over the bridge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re not really sure what’s going on right now. Andrea, like me, is a writer, but doesn’t have a day job. Even if she did, it likely wouldn’t pay that much, especially in the small down we live in. If what I was told at the border is accurate, there is no way I would be able to live with Andrea in Canada.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had a follow-up call with my immigration consultant today and he believes that the border people were wrong on multiple points, both with my legal status and Andrea’s ability to be my sponsor. She’ll meet with him on Monday and see what can be done and what timeframe we’re looking at.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I managed to get my two most critical prescriptions filled today. It’ll be a couple days before I can get a new glucose meter and I’m going to have to do without my newest medication because insurance won’t cover a refill this soon and it’s way too expensive to fill without. I’ll just have to deal with the effects of that. Work put me up in a hotel in Michigan for a few days to deal with some issues undistracted, so that is one less immediate worry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was heading back to Illinois next week where I have someone to stay with, for another round of doctor visits. Those plans will carry on as expected. What I don’t know at this point is when or if I’m going to be able to go back to Canada. Being separated from my family is just about the hardest thing I can imagine. The next couple weeks should tell if we continue the immigration process to Canada or if we reverse course and bring Andrea to the states. We might be apart for a couple of weeks or it could be a couple months. The situation sucks, but I take partial blame for it. Ultimately, we should have been more orderly and prompt with filing paperwork and such. Now we’ll have to wait and see what the damage is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My thanks to everyone who’s been there for us through this ordeal. It means the world to me to know that I have friends like you out there.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>