<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Immigration on Adam Israel</title>
    <link>http://adamisrael.com/tags/immigration/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Immigration on Adam Israel</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© 2016 Adam Israel</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://adamisrael.com/tags/immigration/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>111 Weeks</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2013/09/19/111-weeks/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2013/09/19/111-weeks/</guid>
      <description>To be exact, it&amp;#8217;s been 783 days since we filed for my Canadian Permanent Residence and I am happy to announce that it is official done. We have just walked out of the Immigration Centre in Windsor, Ontario, Social Insurance Number in hand.
I guess this makes me an expatriate; an American Citizen permanently living abroad, which is kind of cool. I&amp;#8217;ve been thinking a lot about getting a tattoo to commemorate the experience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two years and pocket change</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2012/11/26/two-years-and-pocket-change/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2012/11/26/two-years-and-pocket-change/</guid>
      <description>Two years and two days ago, I started a journey from Santa Monica, California by foot, bus, train, and plane. Many hours later, I reached Detroit and was met by my friend Katni, who drove me through the Detroit-Windsor tunnel where, six months after being kicked out, I re-entered Canada and was reunited with Andrea.
Being home still feels really good.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dipping into Canadian Immigration/Politics</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2012/03/05/dipping-into-canadian-immigrationpolitics/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2012/03/05/dipping-into-canadian-immigrationpolitics/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#8217;ve been following the news regarding Canadian Immigration pretty closely &amp;#8212; not surprising considering my immigrant status. Last week this article in the Globe and Mail talks about the percentage of immigrants who settle in Ontario vs. other provinces, which kind of bored me. What was interesting, though, were two issues in the continued fight against immigration fraud. When Andrea and I filled out our application, most of our time was spent collecting evidence to prove our relationship &amp;#8212; records of emails, phone calls, meetings between us, friends, and family, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I know Immigration-Fu</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2011/07/28/i-know-immigration-fu/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2011/07/28/i-know-immigration-fu/</guid>
      <description>The inches-thick stack of paper greeting us on Tuesday only needed one thing: signatures. With today&amp;#8217;s batch of packages to Fedex, my application for immigration to Canada is on its way north, where it will sit in processing for the next nine or ten months. Around April or May next year, I will start frantically refreshing the status page to see if it changes from &amp;#8216;in process&amp;#8217; to &amp;#8216;approved&amp;#8217; and we wait for the final paperwork to come in the mail.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The good, the bad, and the awesome</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2011/05/11/the-good-the-bad-and-the-awesome/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2011/05/11/the-good-the-bad-and-the-awesome/</guid>
      <description>The package of mail from the states that I&amp;#8217;ve been anxiously waiting for arrived today. I now have the last of the paperwork I need to continue with my permanent residence application, my Square reader, so I can accept credit card payments, and the sealed letter from the Illinois DMV so I can get my Ontario drivers license.
We drive to the nearest driving center with the sealed letter in hand.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tears in the Rain</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2010/05/12/tears-in-the-rain/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2010/05/12/tears-in-the-rain/</guid>
      <description>I’ve spent the last few days in a work and stress-induced fugue state, trying to wrap my head around things. Andrea and family went to meet with our immigration person on Monday. The only sure way that I’ll be allowed back into Canada is for us to file for immigration first. That sounds easier and quicker than it actually is. We’re facing up to a few months before that can happen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>To fight the horde, sing and cry: Valhalla, I am coming!</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2010/05/08/to-fight-the-horde-sing-and-cry-valhalla-i-am-coming/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2010/05/08/to-fight-the-horde-sing-and-cry-valhalla-i-am-coming/</guid>
      <description>There’s so much that’s happened in the last twenty-four hours that I scarcely know where to start. For the uninitiated, I am American and my wife, Andrea, is Canadian. I have a house in Illinois, empty and for sale by court order from a previous marriage. In August of last year, my wife and I moved in with her Mom in Ontario, Canada. Prior that we had been living with my Dad in Wisconsin, in his three bedroom trailer, with our three large dogs and four cats, helping him recover from major back surgery.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>