<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Os X on Adam Israel</title>
    <link>http://adamisrael.com/tags/os-x/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Os X on Adam Israel</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© 2016 Adam Israel</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://adamisrael.com/tags/os-x/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>sshuttle workaround for OS X 10.10 (Yosemite), Juju and Vagrant</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2014/12/12/sshuttle-workaround-for-os-x-10-10-yosemite-juju-and-vagrant/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2014/12/12/sshuttle-workaround-for-os-x-10-10-yosemite-juju-and-vagrant/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p class=&#34;p2&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sshuttle/sshuttle&#34;&gt;sshuttle&lt;/a&gt; is a nifty little transparent proxy/vpn that works by tunneling TCP traffic over SSH, or more specifically, tearing down a TCP session and reassembling the data on the other side. I started using it earlier this year, as part of my workflow using &lt;a href=&#34;https://juju.ubuntu.com/&#34;&gt;Juju&lt;/a&gt; and developing under OS X. It&amp;#8217;s like a data center in a box, inside another box. Code locally in my editor of choice (vim, TextMate, and more recently, Atom). Deploy new code. Refresh web browser, thanks to sshuttle. With sshuttle, I could connect to the services running within my virtual machine running Ubuntu natively through OS X.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making OS X, Go, and Brew play happy</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2014/11/13/making-os-x-go-and-brew-play-happy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2014/11/13/making-os-x-go-and-brew-play-happy/</guid>
      <description>GO and OS X I&amp;#8217;m doing a little hacking with juju actions before they land in a stable release but I ran into some hurdles getting Go working with the brew-installed version. Trying to install Go packages failed with a bunch of &amp;#8216;unrecognized import path&amp;#8217; errors. Here&amp;#8217;s how I fixed it.
STOP, GO, STOP Even though you can install Go via brew, there&amp;#8217;s more to be done to get it working.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Q&amp;A: Why is Scrivener using my old contact information?</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2014/07/31/qa-why-is-scrivener-using-my-old-contact-information/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2014/07/31/qa-why-is-scrivener-using-my-old-contact-information/</guid>
      <description>For the past few years, I&amp;#8217;ve had to manually update the contact information in the header of every Scrivener project I&amp;#8217;ve created. It was defaulting to an old email and physical address, but somehow had the correct phone number.
Scrivener can pull your contact information from the OS X application Contacts, if you add the string &amp;#8220;(Scrivener:UseMe)&amp;#8221; to the notes of your contact card. As it turns out, I had done that already but my card has all of my email addresses (work and home) as well as my current and past physical addresses.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>