<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Nanowrimo on Adam Israel</title>
    <link>http://adamisrael.com/tags/nanowrimo/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Nanowrimo on Adam Israel</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© 2016 Adam Israel</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://adamisrael.com/tags/nanowrimo/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Fail. Fail Harder. Fail Better.</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2011/12/01/fail-fail-harder-fail-better/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2011/12/01/fail-fail-harder-fail-better/</guid>
      <description>NaNoWriMo is over. I failed to win. I failed, but there are lessons in failure.
I set out to do a few things aside from writing 50k words. I wanted to learn to turn off my internal editor when I needed to, so that I could write first drafts on the computer. I wanted to write something longer than I&amp;#8217;d written before, previously around 6,000 words. I wanted to get a better understanding of novel structure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#NaNoWriMo day 20: Struggling against the event horizon</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2011/11/21/nanowrimo-day-20-struggling-against-the-event-horizon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2011/11/21/nanowrimo-day-20-struggling-against-the-event-horizon/</guid>
      <description>I feel like I&amp;#8217;ve been at a near standstill the last four days. With one zero day among them, I&amp;#8217;ve barely scratched a thousand words among them. To make up for the shortfall, I need to write roughly 2,400 words/day though the rest of the month in order to hit the Nano goal of 50k. I&amp;#8217;ve hit that number once this month.
It&amp;#8217;s going to be a nail biter.
—</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#NaNoWriMo day 16</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2011/11/17/nanowrimo-day-16/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2011/11/17/nanowrimo-day-16/</guid>
      <description>I found my stride yesterday, sixteen days in. I didn&amp;#8217;t strictly follow end of day guidelines for Nano, calling it a day somewhere close to 1AM. I drafted a scene and a part of the next and it&amp;#8217;s the best writing I&amp;#8217;ve done all month. It&amp;#8217;s what all others will be held up and compared to, and mocked mercilessly when they fall short.
—
Project: Black Mirror
New words written: 1,803</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#NaNoWriMo day 15: I can see for miles and miles</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2011/11/16/nanowrimo-day-15-i-can-see-for-miles-and-miles/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2011/11/16/nanowrimo-day-15-i-can-see-for-miles-and-miles/</guid>
      <description>Hello, folks, this is your captain speaking. We&amp;#8217;ve reached the halfway mark in our journey to noveldom. There&amp;#8217;s been some minor turbulence along the way but we&amp;#8217;re in blue skies now.
Almost.
—
Project: Black Mirror
New words written: 2,421
Reason for stopping: End of day
—
In this hot mess of first draft spagetti and a generous serving of cheese, I&amp;#8217;m learning a lot. One being that I&amp;#8217;m frighteningly close to the climax of the story and that the later part of the month will see me going back through and filling in things that I skipped over.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#NaNoWriMo day 14: Peeking over the hump</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2011/11/15/nanowrimo-day-14-peeking-over-the-hump/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2011/11/15/nanowrimo-day-14-peeking-over-the-hump/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday was the fourteenth day of Nano and I haven&amp;#8217;t missed a one. I feel pretty good about that, no matter what else happens. I crossed the 20k mark, which feels awesome.
I am beginning to grok this pacing thing. Fires are smoldering inside my cranium. You can read about this, talk about this, but there is no substitute for doing.
—
Project: Black Mirror
New words written: 1,150
Reason for stopping: End of day</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#NaNoWriMo day 13, plus some short story pondering</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2011/11/14/nanowrimo-day-13-plus-some-short-story-pondering/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2011/11/14/nanowrimo-day-13-plus-some-short-story-pondering/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday was another low day, both in mood and writing. My daily target is creeping up slightly, to 1,932 words. Still within reason but I&amp;#8217;m not happy about the lack of progress the last few days.
Mostly, this comes down to November being November, and my inexperience writing at this length. This shake down cruise is not without its bumps.
—
Project: Black Mirror
New words written: 473
Reason for stopping: End of Day</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#NaNoWriMo day 12 – Climbing back up the hill</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2011/11/13/nanowrimo-day-12-climbing-back-up-the-hill/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2011/11/13/nanowrimo-day-12-climbing-back-up-the-hill/</guid>
      <description>Good progress today, making up for last week&amp;#8217;s shortfall. Making bullet point outlines of character/plot has been useful in figuring out some pacing/plot arc issues and giving me things to write that I hadn&amp;#8217;t even realized I needed. I&amp;#8217;ll need to do a massive reverse outline come December, though. Stitching the various plots and subplots together will take some work and much rewriting.
&amp;#8212;
Project: Black Mirror
New words written: 2,044</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#NaNoWriMo day 11: Plotting, and a little Scrivener tip</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2011/11/12/nanowrimo-day-11-plotting-and-a-little-scrivener-tip/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2011/11/12/nanowrimo-day-11-plotting-and-a-little-scrivener-tip/</guid>
      <description>The last few days haven&amp;#8217;t been the most productive ones. If I were to go by the official NaNoWriMo stats, my current estimated finish date is December 4th and I just won&amp;#8217;t accept that. There are weekends, holidays, and writing sprints between now and then. Anything can happen.
I stick to the time zone deadline pretty strictly, so I logged my numbers but kept writing and added another thousand words before bed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#NaNoWriMo day 10</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2011/11/11/nanowrimo-day-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2011/11/11/nanowrimo-day-10/</guid>
      <description>Not a great day all around and I was feeling pretty crummy about it, but as a wise man reminded me, 300 words is still 300 words closer to where I need to be.
&amp;#8212;
Project: Black Mirror
New words written: 300
Reason for stopping: Hit a wall
&amp;#8212;
Back on the saddle today. It&amp;#8217;s the beginning of a long weekend and I intend to mine some words.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#NaNoWriMo day 9: 15k and beyond</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2011/11/10/nanowrimo-day-9-15k-and-beyond/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2011/11/10/nanowrimo-day-9-15k-and-beyond/</guid>
      <description>Winter, as they say, is coming and appropriately enough, I celebrated it with a London Fog Latte (Earl Grey tea, a shot of vanilla, and steamed milk).
Not my best work here, but I laid out the bones of what needs to be done. A hot mess of potential awesome might be the best way to describe it all. I started organizing my notes for a post-Nano reverse outline. In keeping with the spirit of Nano, no words will be deleted no matter how much my inner editor cringes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#NaNoWriMo Day 8: What is this I don’t even</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2011/11/09/nanowrimo-day-8-what-is-this-i-dont-even/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2011/11/09/nanowrimo-day-8-what-is-this-i-dont-even/</guid>
      <description>Not everyone realizes that Nanowrimo, and being a writer in general, is a marathon, not a sprint. As such, I&amp;#8217;ve given myself permission for a skip day, should I need one. I haven&amp;#8217;t needed to call a mulligan yet but today was damn close.
I went to the local coffee shop early this morning and added a third of my words. Head down and hauling ass on the day job (optimizing database queries, woo!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#NaNoWriMo Day 7: Filling in the gaps</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2011/11/08/nanowrimo-day-7-filling-in-the-gaps/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2011/11/08/nanowrimo-day-7-filling-in-the-gaps/</guid>
      <description>Doing nano during the week is the most challenging for me. I work a lot, which means I need to be even more disciplined with my time. Thanks to some work issues, I didn&amp;#8217;t even start to think about writing until close to 7PM and I really didn&amp;#8217;t think I was going to make it. Also, I had a bad case of the don&amp;#8217;t wanna&amp;#8217;s. So, I gave myself an hour break and played XBox before I got to writing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#NaNoWriMo Day 6: Parity!</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2011/11/07/nanowrimo-day-6-parity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2011/11/07/nanowrimo-day-6-parity/</guid>
      <description>Not as much writing as I&amp;#8217;d like today, mostly my own fault. When I actually sit down to write, I can knock out the words but today I procrastinated and was easily distracted. Still, I managed to hit parity with the Nano model of 1,667 words/day.
&amp;#8212;
Project: Black Mirror
New words written: 1,975
Reason for stopping: Midnight
&amp;#8212;
Almost a week in to this draft, I still feel pretty good about it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#NaNoWriMo day 5: milestones</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2011/11/06/nanowrimo-day-5-milestones/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2011/11/06/nanowrimo-day-5-milestones/</guid>
      <description>A mostly solid day of writing. Andrea and I went out to the coffee shop for a morning session. I struggled with the words. Came home and napped.
Woke and procrastinated until the late evening and then&amp;#8230;something broke open. Next thing I knew, I was over 2,000 words and it was almost midnight. I&amp;#8217;m not saying they&amp;#8217;re great words. Hell, some of them ain&amp;#8217;t even good words. They&amp;#8217;re my words, though, and I&amp;#8217;m keeping them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NaNoWriMo Day 4 – Studying structure</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2011/11/05/nanowrimo-day-4-studying-structure/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2011/11/05/nanowrimo-day-4-studying-structure/</guid>
      <description>The bad news is I am now fluent in Fluish, having spent a good chunk of the day sleeping away the sickness.
When I did bother to wake up and shake off the cobwebs, I grabbed 10 books off the shelf and started making notes. A few favorites, a few classics, a few modern contemporaries, SF and F. I looked at point of view and how each was structured. The results were interesting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NaNoWriMo 2011: Day 3</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2011/11/04/nanowrimo-2011-day-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2011/11/04/nanowrimo-2011-day-3/</guid>
      <description>I haven&amp;#8217;t managed to get back to my usual morning schedule of writing yet. Dayjobbery filled most of the day, until I realized that the stack of tissues piling up beside me and the general malaise that I felt was part of a deeper issue. I&amp;#8217;m not sure if it&amp;#8217;s some weird combination of a head cold, flu, a fibro flare, or accidental glutening but I spent a chunk of the afternoon in bed and the first few hours of the evening just trying to focus.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NaNoWriMo 2011: Day 2</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2011/11/03/nanowrimo-2011-day-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2011/11/03/nanowrimo-2011-day-2/</guid>
      <description>Work all day followed by a quick nap and no words before 7:30pm. Andrea kicked me out of the house and I trundled off to the coffee house, was disappointed by the lack of London Fog Tea, and sat to write.
When I&amp;#8217;m working on a project, it takes me a few days to hit my stride. So far, so good. I did a lot better with suppressing the urge to edit and hey, I made up for yesterdays shortfall.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NaNoWriMo 2011: Day 1</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2011/11/02/nanowrimo-2011-day-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2011/11/02/nanowrimo-2011-day-1/</guid>
      <description>I think I&amp;#8217;m going to try blogging as I go &amp;#8212; nothing extensive because I don&amp;#8217;t want to take away from the real writing but I do want to jot down my thoughts. This is a process of learning and experimentation for me. I&amp;#8217;ve been writing short stories seriously for four years but writing something novel-length is a different kind of beast.
One thing talked about on Twitter today was that some people actually start querying their Nano novels shortly after they&amp;#8217;ve finished.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NaNoWriMo 2011</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2011/11/01/nanowrimo-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2011/11/01/nanowrimo-2011/</guid>
      <description>Today is November 1st, the start of a new NaNoWriMo. I&amp;#8217;ve been doing, or trying to do, NaNoWriMo, on and off unsuccessfully since 2002 when my efforts netted about 4,500 words.
Timing is a bitch. After I start writing seriously in 2007, I intended to do Nano that year. That November, a few days into the month, my marriage split up. The following November was the official divorce. A few slim years later, it preceded bankruptcy.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>