<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Nanowrimo on Adam Israel</title>
    <link>http://dev.adamisrael.com/tags/nanowrimo/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Nanowrimo on Adam Israel</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://dev.adamisrael.com/tags/nanowrimo/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Fail. Fail Harder. Fail Better.</title>
      <link>http://dev.adamisrael.com/blog/2011/12/01/fail-fail-harder-fail-better/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://dev.adamisrael.com/blog/2011/12/01/fail-fail-harder-fail-better/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;NaNoWriMo is over. I failed to win. I failed, but there are lessons in failure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I set out to do a few things aside from writing 50k words. I wanted to learn to turn off my internal editor when I needed to, so that I could write first drafts on the computer. I wanted to write something longer than I&amp;#8217;d written before, previously around 6,000 words. I wanted to get a better understanding of novel structure. Those things, I succeeded at.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the end, my efforts stalled around Thanksgiving. I was at 28,264 words and I realized that I would need almost 4,000 words/day in order to hit the 50k mark and that wasn&amp;#8217;t going to happen without some kind of herculean effort that, frankly, wasn&amp;#8217;t worth the payout. I&amp;#8217;d already done what I set out to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I blogged quite a few of my observations through the month. Mostly, they had to do with novel structure. That&amp;#8217;s my biggest takeaway. For all of the novels I&amp;#8217;ve read, the thing I&amp;#8217;ve thought the least about (consciously) is structure. I used to think that the difference between short stories and novels was simply chapters being collections of scenes but it&amp;#8217;s a bit more complicated than that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I wrote was, in many ways, a very detailed outline. It helped me flesh out plot and structure and characters. I figured out flaws in the story I had in my head and discovered some really cool things lurking in the shadows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My next steps are doing a reverse outline of what I wrote. Chapters are out of order, pacing is a jumble, key scenes are missing, and there&amp;#8217;s still 80k words to be written.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I personally find it difficult to write when I know a story isn&amp;#8217;t working. I averaged almost 1,500 words/day, which was better than I do longhand but the quality suffered. It left me with another failed attempt at NaNoWriMo, but I feel better about this effort than any of the previous. Fail or not, I&amp;#8217;m better for having tried.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#NaNoWriMo day 20: Struggling against the event horizon</title>
      <link>http://dev.adamisrael.com/blog/2011/11/21/nanowrimo-day-20-struggling-against-the-event-horizon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://dev.adamisrael.com/blog/2011/11/21/nanowrimo-day-20-struggling-against-the-event-horizon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I feel like I&amp;#8217;ve been at a near standstill the last four days. With one zero day among them, I&amp;#8217;ve barely scratched a thousand words among them. To make up for the shortfall, I need to write roughly 2,400 words/day though the rest of the month in order to hit the Nano goal of 50k. I&amp;#8217;ve hit that number once this month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s going to be a nail biter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;—&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Project: Black Mirror&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;New words written: 600&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reason for stopping: Falling asleep at the wheel&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;1&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;—&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It hasn&amp;#8217;t all been wasted time. I&amp;#8217;ve talked about how my pacing has been a problem. I&amp;#8217;ve been stopping to make notes about missing scenes, characters, and plot arcs that I&amp;#8217;ll need to work on post-Nano (or if I run out of story to write during). I&amp;#8217;ve also been filling out character sheets as I go. I&amp;#8217;ll need to do more of this as I reverse outline in December, making sure I have consistent details on everyone, if they&amp;#8217;re a point of view character, and enough background to know who they really are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m not going to throw in the towel, but I sure wouldn&amp;#8217;t mind a day or two of really good output to give me a little buffer, ya know?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#NaNoWriMo day 16</title>
      <link>http://dev.adamisrael.com/blog/2011/11/17/nanowrimo-day-16/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://dev.adamisrael.com/blog/2011/11/17/nanowrimo-day-16/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I found my stride yesterday, sixteen days in. I didn&amp;#8217;t strictly follow end of day guidelines for Nano, calling it a day somewhere close to 1AM. I drafted a scene and a part of the next and it&amp;#8217;s the best writing I&amp;#8217;ve done all month. It&amp;#8217;s what all others will be held up and compared to, and mocked mercilessly when they fall short.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;—&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Project: Black Mirror&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;New words written: 1,803&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reason for stopping: Tired&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;1&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;—&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ll be scrambling for words tonight. The Day job looms and I have my &lt;a href=&#34;2&#34;&gt;Inkpunks&lt;/a&gt; post to write for tomorrow. Plus, I&amp;#8217;m deep into creating my first eBook, which is a lot more fun than I expected it to be. Certain long-term plans are slowly coming together in a way that make me want to cackle and wring my hands together.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#NaNoWriMo day 15: I can see for miles and miles</title>
      <link>http://dev.adamisrael.com/blog/2011/11/16/nanowrimo-day-15-i-can-see-for-miles-and-miles/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://dev.adamisrael.com/blog/2011/11/16/nanowrimo-day-15-i-can-see-for-miles-and-miles/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello, folks, this is your captain speaking. We&amp;#8217;ve reached the halfway mark in our journey to noveldom. There&amp;#8217;s been some minor turbulence along the way but we&amp;#8217;re in blue skies now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Almost.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;—&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Project: Black Mirror&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;New words written: 2,421&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reason for stopping: End of day&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;1&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;—&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this hot mess of first draft spagetti and a generous serving of cheese, I&amp;#8217;m learning a lot. One being that I&amp;#8217;m frighteningly close to the climax of the story and that the later part of the month will see me going back through and filling in things that I skipped over. Subplots and minor characters left off-screen need care and attention, because they are interesting and still trapped inside my head.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other thing that I&amp;#8217;ve done poorly is setting. I think it&amp;#8217;s true of most stories, but especially so of Urban Fantasy, is that setting is character and, as characters go, I&amp;#8217;ve made mine pretty bland so far. A large part of that was the lack of preparation. I wish I had a nice big map of the city printed out and tiled over my desk, with sticky notes to visualize this world like a giant pastel event wheel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, I&amp;#8217;ll be continuing with the reverse outlining as I go, straightening out my chapters and weaving together my various points of view. I swore off any rewriting or deleting during Nano but there are new scenes I&amp;#8217;ve discovered through this process. I&amp;#8217;ve had that panicked moment realizing that I was nearing the end as far as chapters go, but one saving grace for writing this out of order is that there are still plenty of words left to write.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#NaNoWriMo day 14: Peeking over the hump</title>
      <link>http://dev.adamisrael.com/blog/2011/11/15/nanowrimo-day-14-peeking-over-the-hump/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://dev.adamisrael.com/blog/2011/11/15/nanowrimo-day-14-peeking-over-the-hump/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday was the fourteenth day of Nano and I haven&amp;#8217;t missed a one. I feel pretty good about that, no matter what else happens. I crossed the 20k mark, which feels &lt;em&gt;awesome&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am beginning to grok this pacing thing. Fires are smoldering inside my cranium. You can read about this, talk about this, but there is no substitute for doing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;—&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Project: Black Mirror&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;New words written: 1,150&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reason for stopping: End of day&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;1&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;—&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m facing down the fact that today is the mid-month mark and I should be 5k ahead of where I am by days end to be at parity. That&amp;#8217;s a little sobering, but the marathon continues apace. I procrastinated yesterday by cleaning and reorganizing my workspace a bit. Not strictly necessary but better workspace == better headspace.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#NaNoWriMo day 13, plus some short story pondering</title>
      <link>http://dev.adamisrael.com/blog/2011/11/14/nanowrimo-day-13-plus-some-short-story-pondering/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://dev.adamisrael.com/blog/2011/11/14/nanowrimo-day-13-plus-some-short-story-pondering/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday was another low day, both in mood and writing. My daily target is creeping up slightly, to 1,932 words. Still within reason but I&amp;#8217;m not happy about the lack of progress the last few days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mostly, this comes down to November being November, and my inexperience writing at this length. This shake down cruise is not without its bumps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;—&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Project: Black Mirror&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;New words written: 473&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reason for stopping: End of Day&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;1&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;—&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the same time, short fiction continues, albeit at a slower pace. A rare paper submission came back in the mail today, marking my second to F&amp;amp;SF in four years. I&amp;#8217;m kind of kicking myself for not submitting there more, considering that their response time is quicker than most electronic markets. That story still go back out on submission today, and I have two others that I need to find markets for but I&amp;#8217;ve been procrastinating&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ll likely spend part of my December recuperating from Nano by revising some short stories. I have one new one that I&amp;#8217;d like to get out to market by year end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, the &amp;#8216;t&amp;#8217; key on my keyboard is popping off the hinge, so I may be performing emergency surgery on the laptop soon. Sadness.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#NaNoWriMo day 12 – Climbing back up the hill</title>
      <link>http://dev.adamisrael.com/blog/2011/11/13/nanowrimo-day-12-climbing-back-up-the-hill/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://dev.adamisrael.com/blog/2011/11/13/nanowrimo-day-12-climbing-back-up-the-hill/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Good progress today, making up for last week&amp;#8217;s shortfall. Making bullet point outlines of character/plot has been useful in figuring out some pacing/plot arc issues and giving me things to write that I hadn&amp;#8217;t even realized I needed. I&amp;#8217;ll need to do a massive reverse outline come December, though. Stitching the various plots and subplots together will take some work and much rewriting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8212;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Project: Black Mirror&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;New words written: 2,044&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reason for stopping: End of day&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;1&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8212;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Day 13 begins anew with a writing date with my sweetheart. We&amp;#8217;re off to breakfast, followed by the coffee shop for tea and words.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#NaNoWriMo day 11: Plotting, and a little Scrivener tip</title>
      <link>http://dev.adamisrael.com/blog/2011/11/12/nanowrimo-day-11-plotting-and-a-little-scrivener-tip/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://dev.adamisrael.com/blog/2011/11/12/nanowrimo-day-11-plotting-and-a-little-scrivener-tip/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The last few days haven&amp;#8217;t been the most productive ones. If I were to go by the official NaNoWriMo stats, my current estimated finish date is December 4th and I just won&amp;#8217;t accept that. There are weekends, holidays, and writing sprints between now and then. Anything can happen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I stick to the time zone deadline pretty strictly, so I logged my numbers but kept writing and added another thousand words before bed. I&amp;#8217;ve killed off one minor character, in a pretty epic way, and am reaching the final arch for a second minor but notable character. Sitting down to re-outline character/plot arcs before I write for the day has been tremendously helpful as I get into the thick of the novel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8212;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Project: Black Mirror&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;New words written: 950&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reason for stopping: Midnight&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;1&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8212;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyone who knows me well knows that I&amp;#8217;m a fan of Scrivener. Here&amp;#8217;s another reason why. During the first day or two of Nano, I setup targets to track my progress and goals independently of Nano&amp;#8217;s stats.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Scrivener will track two things: the draft target, which is your overall progress, and the session target, which is your word count for that day (or however you want to track it).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The important things in the target options are to set the deadline you want to finish by, &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; to allow text anywhere in the project, and to automatically calculate from the draft deadline. Allow negatives would probably be fine in most cases, but let&amp;#8217;s face it: this is Nano, you shouldn&amp;#8217;t be deleting. Also, if you&amp;#8217;re nice to yourself, as you might be on a regular, non-Nano project, you take a day off. You could schedule that here and have that calculated into your deadline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I chose not to reset the the session target at midnight automatically because that&amp;#8217;s when I stop to update Nano, my Google Docs spreadsheet, and this blog and I don&amp;#8217;t want to forget where I left off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table style=&#34;align: center;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.adamisrael.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/11/scrivener_targets.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-full wp-image-650&#34; title=&#34;Scrivener Targets&#34; src=&#34;http://www.adamisrael.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/11/scrivener_targets.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Scrivener Targets&#34; width=&#34;301&#34; height=&#34;246&#34; srcset=&#34;//www.adamisrael.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/11/scrivener_targets-300x245.jpg 300w, //www.adamisrael.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/11/scrivener_targets.jpg 301w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 301px) 100vw, 301px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;

    &lt;td&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;
        &lt;div id=&#34;attachment_651&#34; style=&#34;width: 310px&#34; class=&#34;wp-caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
          &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.adamisrael.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/11/scrivener_target_options.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-full wp-image-651 &#34; title=&#34;Scrivener Target Options&#34; src=&#34;http://www.adamisrael.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/11/scrivener_target_options.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Scrivener Target Options&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;360&#34; srcset=&#34;//www.adamisrael.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/11/scrivener_target_options-250x300.jpg 250w, //www.adamisrael.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/11/scrivener_target_options.jpg 300w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

          &lt;p class=&#34;wp-caption-text&#34;&gt;
            Scrivener Target Options
          &lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &lt;/tr&gt; &lt;/tbody&gt; &lt;/table&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#NaNoWriMo day 10</title>
      <link>http://dev.adamisrael.com/blog/2011/11/11/nanowrimo-day-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://dev.adamisrael.com/blog/2011/11/11/nanowrimo-day-10/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Not a great day all around and I was feeling pretty crummy about it, but as a wise man &lt;a href=&#34;1&#34;&gt;reminded me&lt;/a&gt;, 300 words is still 300 words closer to where I need to be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8212;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Project: Black Mirror&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;New words written: 300&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reason for stopping: Hit a wall&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;2&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8212;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back on the saddle today. It&amp;#8217;s the beginning of a long weekend and I intend to mine some words.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#NaNoWriMo day 9: 15k and beyond</title>
      <link>http://dev.adamisrael.com/blog/2011/11/10/nanowrimo-day-9-15k-and-beyond/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://dev.adamisrael.com/blog/2011/11/10/nanowrimo-day-9-15k-and-beyond/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Winter, as they say, is coming and appropriately enough, I celebrated it with a London Fog Latte (Earl Grey tea, a shot of vanilla, and steamed milk).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not my best work here, but I laid out the bones of what needs to be done. A hot mess of potential awesome might be the best way to describe it all. I started organizing my notes for a post-Nano reverse outline. In keeping with the spirit of Nano, no words will be deleted no matter how much my inner editor cringes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8212;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Project: Black Mirror&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;New words written: 1,738&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reason for stopping: Coffee shop closing&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;1&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8212;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When this is all over, I&amp;#8217;ll be curious to read the blogs of/talk to other authors I know doing Nano and see what their experiences are. I know I&amp;#8217;m essentially brute-forcing my way through a very extensive outline, but that was one of my expectations so I&amp;#8217;m okay with it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#NaNoWriMo Day 8: What is this I don’t even</title>
      <link>http://dev.adamisrael.com/blog/2011/11/09/nanowrimo-day-8-what-is-this-i-dont-even/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://dev.adamisrael.com/blog/2011/11/09/nanowrimo-day-8-what-is-this-i-dont-even/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Not everyone realizes that Nanowrimo, and being a writer in general, is a marathon, not a sprint. As such, I&amp;#8217;ve given myself permission for a skip day, should I need one. I haven&amp;#8217;t needed to call a mulligan yet but today was damn close.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went to the local coffee shop early this morning and added a third of my words. Head down and hauling ass on the day job (optimizing database queries, woo!). Early evening, a dog fight broke out over bones and I dove in to separate them all. That and a shot of adrenaline, as it turns out, does a really good job of triggering an asthma attack and has some fun fibro side effects. After regurgitating fluid from my lungs and taking a short nap, I was awake but I really didn&amp;#8217;t think I would get any more writing done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8212;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Project: Black Mirror&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;New words written: 1,772&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reason for stopping: Midnight&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;1&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8212;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One good thing about Nano, for those who aren&amp;#8217;t used to writing and follow through with it, is it helps to build the habit of writing every day. I think it can build some bad habits as well, but that&amp;#8217;s something worthy of a post another day. The thing is, even feeling like shit and wanting to eat ALL THE THINGS, I couldn&amp;#8217;t not write, nor stop even to rummage for a snack because that would mean missing my target.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;#8217;s how I know I&amp;#8217;ve found the beat of this project. I had an excuse to stop. I could have played Xbox for the rest of the night and gone to bed early but it felt wrong. I didn&amp;#8217;t. I didn&amp;#8217;t want to. Now I know I won&amp;#8217;t.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#NaNoWriMo Day 7: Filling in the gaps</title>
      <link>http://dev.adamisrael.com/blog/2011/11/08/nanowrimo-day-7-filling-in-the-gaps/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://dev.adamisrael.com/blog/2011/11/08/nanowrimo-day-7-filling-in-the-gaps/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Doing nano during the week is the most challenging for me. I work a lot, which means I need to be even more disciplined with my time. Thanks to some work issues, I didn&amp;#8217;t even start to think about writing until close to 7PM and I really didn&amp;#8217;t think I was going to make it. Also, I had a bad case of the don&amp;#8217;t wanna&amp;#8217;s. So, I gave myself an hour break and played XBox before I got to writing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8212;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Project: Black Mirror&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;New words written: 1,809&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reason for stopping: End of Chapter&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;1&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8212;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking over what I have done so far, I can see where I have some minor pacing issues. The biggest thing I&amp;#8217;ll need to deal with, later this week, are the things I didn&amp;#8217;t outline for. I planned on thirty chapters. I&amp;#8217;ve drafted thirteen. I&amp;#8217;m not sure it&amp;#8217;s fair to even call them chapters, really, but that&amp;#8217;s what I&amp;#8217;m sticking with. There&amp;#8217;ll probably be more of them, on the shorter end, rather than fewer, bulkier ones. Anyways, I have some gaps to fill in, where the story&amp;#8217;s evolved and stretched a bit more than anticipated. Not a bad problem, just something I need to budget a little more time for.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#NaNoWriMo Day 6: Parity!</title>
      <link>http://dev.adamisrael.com/blog/2011/11/07/nanowrimo-day-6-parity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://dev.adamisrael.com/blog/2011/11/07/nanowrimo-day-6-parity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Not as much writing as I&amp;#8217;d like today, mostly my own fault. When I actually sit down to write, I can knock out the words but today I procrastinated and was easily distracted. Still, I managed to hit parity with the Nano model of 1,667 words/day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8212;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Project: Black Mirror&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;New words written: 1,975&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reason for stopping: Midnight&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;1&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8212;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Almost a week in to this draft, I still feel pretty good about it. I haven&amp;#8217;t had that &amp;#8220;OMG OMG we&amp;#8217;re all going to die&amp;#8221; feeling &lt;em&gt;once&lt;/em&gt;. The ideas are solid and the writing can be fixed. This is a story that I would pick up and read. That&amp;#8217;s probably a good thing, because I&amp;#8217;m going to spend a significant amount of time in this world between now and next summer, getting it ready for someone other than me to read.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#NaNoWriMo day 5: milestones</title>
      <link>http://dev.adamisrael.com/blog/2011/11/06/nanowrimo-day-5-milestones/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://dev.adamisrael.com/blog/2011/11/06/nanowrimo-day-5-milestones/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A mostly solid day of writing. Andrea and I went out to the coffee shop for a morning session. I struggled with the words. Came home and napped.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Woke and procrastinated until the late evening and then&amp;#8230;something broke open. Next thing I knew, I was over 2,000 words and it was almost midnight. I&amp;#8217;m not saying they&amp;#8217;re great words. Hell, some of them ain&amp;#8217;t even good words. They&amp;#8217;re my words, though, and I&amp;#8217;m keeping them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8212;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Project: Black Mirror&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;New words written: 2,184&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reason for stopping: Midnight&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;1&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8212;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Something one of my Clarion teachers said keeps coming back to me as I write, and that was that the first draft of his novels were more detailed outlines than fully fleshed out drafts. When I&amp;#8217;m picking up speed through this draft, I find that I&amp;#8217;ve slipped into more of a detailed draft mode and my tense shifts from past to present.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;#8217;t think that&amp;#8217;s a bad thing. This is a rough draft. It&amp;#8217;s a learning draft, even if I end up throwing everything out and starting over when the month is over (which I doubt will happen).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Milestones, which I alluded to, were broken today. Two of them. First, this is the longest I&amp;#8217;ve stayed in Nanowrimo since I started attempting it. I can hear the voice of Gold Five in my head every morning when I wake up, telling me to stay on target, and I will. Second, I broke 8k words on a single piece of fiction. My longest single story previous is my time traveling Tesla alt. history that clocked in just under 7k in rough draft.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NaNoWriMo Day 4 – Studying structure</title>
      <link>http://dev.adamisrael.com/blog/2011/11/05/nanowrimo-day-4-studying-structure/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://dev.adamisrael.com/blog/2011/11/05/nanowrimo-day-4-studying-structure/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The bad news is I am now fluent in Fluish, having spent a good chunk of the day sleeping away the sickness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I did bother to wake up and shake off the cobwebs, I grabbed 10 books off the shelf and started making notes. A few favorites, a few classics, a few modern contemporaries, SF and F. I looked at point of view and how each was structured. The results were interesting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of the novels were straightforward, chapters with one scene break, if any. A few were broken into larger sub-sections. One was sectioned by day. In other words, the structure was made to fit the story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The number of chapters varied a bit, from 18 to 39 (ignoring the one outlier that had 104), with average lengths between 1,500 and 6,000 words.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8212;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Project: Black Mirror&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;New words written: 1391&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reason for stopping: Midnight&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;1&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8212;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a good study, but what it really did was tell me that every story has it&amp;#8217;s own beat and it&amp;#8217;s up to the author to discover what that is. I did some clean up of what I&amp;#8217;d done so far and I have a better idea of how I&amp;#8217;m structuring this story going forward, at least through this first draft. There are plenty of other things I need to worry about fixing first (like finishing it).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve made it through day four, which counts for something, an while I&amp;#8217;m not exactly where I&amp;#8217;d like to be, I&amp;#8217;m not too far off. We&amp;#8217;re just now upon the first weekend of the month so I&amp;#8217;m planning to push hard and make some good progress. Not just to see word count, but to see how else the story will surprise me as it evolves.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>