<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Stats on Adam Israel</title>
    <link>http://adamisrael.com/tags/stats/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Stats on Adam Israel</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://adamisrael.com/tags/stats/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Finding my footing</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2013/01/16/finding-my-footing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2013/01/16/finding-my-footing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As writers, we fill our toolbox with things that help us in our craft. I&amp;#8217;ve been experimenting with a few new things of late, trying to boost my productivity. Two of them in particular are making a difference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I haven&amp;#8217;t been involved in many word wars &amp;#8212; timed writing sessions with one or more other writers. Set a short time limit, say 15 or 30 minutes, and write until it&amp;#8217;s over. I started doing that last week, with my online writers group, and had one of my most productive days. These sprints are like a mini-deadline and it&amp;#8217;s easier at times to shut out distraction in small increments. To that end, I&amp;#8217;m taking carving out small small blocks of time throughout the day to write, especially on days when I might not be able to dedicate an hour or two contiguously. I&amp;#8217;m going to get an egg timer to give me an external countdown to the process as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I ordered a cute egg timer from the states, but it was broken and I discovered the hard way how expensive custom and duty fees can be when something is shipped via UPS cross-border. I may just find a decent kitchen timer that can do double-duty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second trick is an organizational one. I&amp;#8217;ve seen it &lt;a href=&#34;http://lifehacker.com/5968978/use-the-dash-method-to-become-a-better-writer-developer-or-tackle-any-other-creative-task&#34;&gt;referred to&lt;/a&gt; as the DASH method &amp;#8212; Direction, Acceleration, Strength, and Health.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Direction is knowing what I&amp;#8217;m going to write before I start. I make short lists of every chapter, broken down by scene, of what that writing needs to accomplish, usually no more than four or five bullet points. That mini-outline forces me to think through every chapter before I put down a single word. When I do sit down to write, I know what my end goal is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Acceleration is getting started and finishing things. I&amp;#8217;ve been pretty slow, plodding along and being frustrated with my progress. I would take so long, writing and rewriting, that I made almost no progress. Now, almost as a mantra, I remind myself that the point of a first draft is getting the ideas down on the page. Making the grammar fluid and pretty can wait for revision.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Strength refers to bolstering your mental clarify and physical strength through a better working environment. I am all about that. It&amp;#8217;s been a slow process to make my office a comfortable space but we&amp;#8217;re almost there. We have our bookshelves up and my cork board, filled with quotes that inspire, hands next to my desk. When I do need a change of pace, I switch to the coffee shop up the road.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Health is a reminder to take care of myself. Figuring out what doesn&amp;#8217;t work (and drives up anxiety) and fix it. Get enough sleep. Realize that if I&amp;#8217;m stuck on something, I probably just need to work it through to figure out what I&amp;#8217;m missing &amp;#8212; brainstorming, doodling, talking it through with someone else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last week wasn&amp;#8217;t the most productive, with a funeral, doctors visit, and other distractions, but I had two great days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Project: Black Mirror&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;New words written since last week: 1,980&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Average words/day: 248&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;![][2]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m working through some existing scenes that need at least some work vs. writing new words. It&amp;#8217;s slowed me down a little but it needs doing. I&amp;#8217;m printing off each chapter as it&amp;#8217;s finished and putting it into a binder. When I do finish, I&amp;#8217;ll take that binder and a red pen and go sit somewhere for an afternoon and begin the revision process. Until then, the printed manuscript goes and is another reminder of what I&amp;#8217;ve finished so far.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[2]: &lt;a href=&#34;http://picometer.writertopia.com/words=38371&amp;amp;target=100000&#34;&gt;http://picometer.writertopia.com/words=38371&amp;amp;target=100000&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Back in the saddle, week 1</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2013/01/07/back-in-the-saddle-week-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2013/01/07/back-in-the-saddle-week-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Part of my new and improved resolve to Finish Things is accountability, and to that end I&amp;#8217;ve created a master spreadsheet for the year where I&amp;#8217;m tracking my daily writing, good things that happen (h/t Christie Yant), projects I want to work on, and deadlines I&amp;#8217;m working towards. It&amp;#8217;s not perfect, but it&amp;#8217;s a start.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m trying to work every day while I&amp;#8217;m involved in a project. Writing is, or should be, what I spend the most time on, at least at this stage in my current WIP. The non-writing tasks, like research, outlining, etc, are limited to what&amp;#8217;s necessary to finish the draft. Research is my way to procrastinate. I did a ton before I started writing, I&amp;#8217;ll do more after the first draft is finished, but at some point I actually have to write this thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;#8217;t want to take away time from writing, so I&amp;#8217;m allowing myself to spam the world with statistics once a week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Project: Black Mirror&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;New words written this week: 2,031&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Average words/day: 338&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[&lt;img alt=&#34;Project Targets&#34; src=&#34;http://www.adamisrael.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/01/project_targets-2013-01-07.jpg&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;][1]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s too soon since I started tracking daily stats to say if I&amp;#8217;m going to hit my deadline or not. This first week has sort of been the warm-up, shaking off the rust of not writing at all for a couple months. I started at 364 days, no words one day (but outlining a new chapter), and ended today at 845. I think I&amp;#8217;ll settle at a comfortable, consistent pace. There&amp;#8217;s wiggle room in my deadline, but not much. My end goal, as soon as the first draft is done, is to revise and have a draft ready for submission by my birthday in late July.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[1]: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.adamisrael.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/01/project_targets-2013-01-07.jpg&#34;&gt;http://www.adamisrael.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/01/project_targets-2013-01-07.jpg&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quick Stats – 2010 vs. 2011 submissions</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2012/01/01/quick-stats-2010-vs-2011-submissions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2012/01/01/quick-stats-2010-vs-2011-submissions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I thought it&amp;#8217;d be interesting to look at some rough numbers, based on my Duotrope stats, year over year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;text-decoration: underline;&#34;&gt;2010&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;13 submissions to 10 different markets&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4 stories on submission&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;13 rejections, 5 personal (38%)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;10 markets&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;0 acceptances&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;text-decoration: underline;&#34;&gt;2011&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;43 submissions to 36 different markets&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;11 stories on submission&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;39 rejections, 16 personal (41%)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4 &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.adamisrael.com/blog/2011/12/19/2011-published-short-fiction/&#34; title=&#34;2011 Published Short Fiction&#34;&gt;acceptances&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;text-decoration: underline;&#34;&gt;Misc. Stats&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each year saw one story pulled from circulation after one submission (one was a reprint from 2008)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All four sales this year were made on the first submission (one by invitation)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s clearly a positive trend, and one I hope to continue into 2012. I don&amp;#8217;t make resolutions, but I do set goals. This year, I&amp;#8217;ll be finishing the novel I started last November and writing (and more importantly, finishing) a lot more short stories.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>