<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Moving on Adam Israel</title>
    <link>http://adamisrael.com/tags/moving/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Moving on Adam Israel</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© 2016 Adam Israel</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://adamisrael.com/tags/moving/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Independence</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2012/07/05/independence/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2012/07/05/independence/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday was Independence Day back in the states. We already had our fireworks over the weekend, and I worked through Canada Day on Monday and had yesterday off instead. Among the joys of American/Canada relations are mixed holidays.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our plans were a little more focused. Yesterday we saw an apartment, and made a deposit, and transfered utilities to our name. This was kind of a big deal, because for the first time in more than three years, we&amp;#8217;re in a position to start a new chapter in our lives. We left our house in May 2009 to stay with my Dad and help him recover with his surgery. We came to Ontario the following August and moved in with Andrea&amp;#8217;s Mom. Then there was that six month&amp;#8217;s being kicked out of the country thing. All told, we haven&amp;#8217;t lived together and alone for over three years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s about damn time. We pick up the keys today and I can&amp;#8217;t wait to feel the weight of them in my pocket. It&amp;#8217;s a burden of responsibility I&amp;#8217;ve been missing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;#8217;re going to be close enough to still help out Andrea&amp;#8217;s mom. We&amp;#8217;re in an even smaller town then we&amp;#8217;ve been in, but we still have a 24 hour coffee shop and the library, while tiny, is right across the street. It&amp;#8217;s a three bedroom downstairs apartment with a small fenced-in back yard for the dogs. Internet&amp;#8217;s already ordered. Now we need to get ourselves appliances and furniture. Priorities, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Andrea has some pretty cool ideas about how to arrange things and I can&amp;#8217;t wait to show off the place once we get it all furnished. It&amp;#8217;s going to be an awesome creative space.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>