<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pay It Forward on Adam Israel</title>
    <link>http://adamisrael.com/tags/pay-it-forward/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Pay It Forward on Adam Israel</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© 2016 Adam Israel</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://adamisrael.com/tags/pay-it-forward/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Soup Karma</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2010/05/10/soup-karma/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2010/05/10/soup-karma/</guid>
      <description>I spent the weekend in Ann Arbor, Michigan, where the day job graciously put me up in a hotel in exchange for some long and late work hours. On Saturday I went to the Arbor Brewing Company on the recommendation of a friend, both for a change of scenery and because I have not been eating much of anything since the whole border ordeal went down.
I sat in a window booth, watching the wind blow and the rain drive down on hapless pedestrians as I hacked away at the keyboard.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Help the Robinsons</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2009/12/28/help-the-robinsons/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Dec 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2009/12/28/help-the-robinsons/</guid>
      <description>Jeanne and Spider Robinson need your help.
 Earlier his year a brilliant surgeon, Dr. Andresz Busczowski, helped Jeanne Robinson beat back a rare and virulent form of biliary cancer. But it’s so rare even he can’t say how much time he‘s bought her, how soon it might recur—and her latest blood tests have been so discouraging they’ve now decided she needs to start chemotherapy as soon as possible. Besides the prescription drugs to counteract the chemotherapy, she needs special therapies and supplements, counseling, and extensive diet and lifestyle changes, to reduce her stress level and the strain on her liver to as close to zero as possible.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>