<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Fitness on Adam Israel</title>
    <link>http://dev.adamisrael.com/tags/fitness/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Fitness on Adam Israel</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 30 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://dev.adamisrael.com/tags/fitness/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Off with the Sloth</title>
      <link>http://dev.adamisrael.com/blog/2011/07/30/off-with-the-sloth/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://dev.adamisrael.com/blog/2011/07/30/off-with-the-sloth/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve survived day two of walking myself into a non-round shape. It&amp;#8217;s not an easy task. Fibromyalgia, my version of it, includes bouts of fatigue. I tried doing something as simple as lunges as part of my friend Sandra&amp;#8217;s virtual bootcamp; twenty minutes of that put me into a fatigue crash that had me sleeping 36 out of the next 48 hours and, frankly, weeks of depression just thinking about that failure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Exercise can induce/worsen Fibromyalgia symptoms but exercise also ease symptoms. It&amp;#8217;s a bit of a catch-22, frankly. The other benefits of getting my fat ass in motion is improving my quality of life, extending my lifespan, curtailing my type-2 diabetes and all sorts of other things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m taking small steps to start. Walking, and gradually &amp;#8212; very gradually &amp;#8212; working my way up. &lt;a href=&#34;1&#34;&gt;Two days, five miles&lt;/a&gt;. An hour a day, in the late afternoon when I&amp;#8217;m most tempted to take a nap. Ultimately, this is a lifestyle change and radical changes are less likely to stick. For me, at least.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Walking is good. It&amp;#8217;s a solitary thing for me and it always puts me in a good headspace. Today, for example, I worked out how to fix some problems in a story I want to revise and submit soon. Then I spent the rest of the time listening to what may be the most awesome walking/running song ever created on repeat: The Loneliness of the Long Distance Runner by Iron Maiden.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Settling into a proper schedule between writing, working, and exercise is really doing good things. I&amp;#8217;m already feeling more energetic and I&amp;#8217;ve written more words this week than the whole month combined.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>