<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ubuntu on Adam Israel</title>
    <link>http://adamisrael.com/tags/ubuntu/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ubuntu on Adam Israel</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© 2016 Adam Israel</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 May 2017 13:23:56 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://adamisrael.com/tags/ubuntu/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Nested LXD on Ubuntu 16.04.2 (Xenial)</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/2017/05/30/nested-lxd-on-ubuntu-16.04.2-xenial/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 May 2017 13:23:56 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/2017/05/30/nested-lxd-on-ubuntu-16.04.2-xenial/</guid>
      <description>tl;dr: Nested LXD containers on Ubuntu 16.04.2 (Xenial) are currently broken by default. You need to install the lxd package from backports.
Sometime in the last couple of months, nested lxd containers on Ubuntu 16.04 broke. A fix landed a week later. Unfortunately, the patch hasn&amp;rsquo;t been applied to the version of lxd (2.0.9-0ubuntu1~16.04.2) in xenial-updates, so a new privileged container, by default, won&amp;rsquo;t be able to launch nested containers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu on Mac</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2015/10/15/ubuntu-on-mac/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2015/10/15/ubuntu-on-mac/</guid>
      <description>I recently rebuilt a Mac Mini to work as the forth screen in my workflow. I googled around and pieced together what I needed to do by cherrypicking from various guides, and everything was running well until I updated to a new kernel and rebooted. I spent the better part of two nights trying to get the machine to boot.
Unfortunately, it happened just after I blacklisted a module to work around a USB bug that was causing one of my drives to go haywire occasionally, and it took a while before I finally figured out it wasn&amp;#8217;t a problem with my change but the kernel itself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing Benchmarking with Juju</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2015/06/23/announcing-benchmarking-with-juju/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2015/06/23/announcing-benchmarking-with-juju/</guid>
      <description>Benchmarking and performance are interesting problems, especially in today’s growing cloud-based microservice scene. It used to be a question of “how does this hardware compare to that hardware,” but as computing and service-oriented architectures grow the question has evolved. How does my cloud and application stack handle this? It’s no longer enough to run PTS on your web server and call it a day.
Measuring every microservice in your stack, from backend to frontend, is a complex task.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New job!</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2014/08/25/new-job/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2014/08/25/new-job/</guid>
      <description>I am delighted &amp;#8212; tickled, in fact &amp;#8212; to report that as of last Monday I am employed by Canonical, the company behind Ubuntu Linux.
I&amp;#8217;ve joined the Ecosystem Engineering team, part of Cloud Development and Operations, as a software engineer. More specifically, I&amp;#8217;m working on Juju, the cloud orchestration tool chain. I&amp;#8217;ll be writing charms and documentation, working on optimizations, and helping to make a cool product even cooler.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>