<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Adam Israel</title>
    <link>http://adamisrael.com/tags/ink/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Adam Israel</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© 2016 Adam Israel</copyright>
    <atom:link href="http://adamisrael.com/tags/ink/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Reason #634 why Kyle Cassidy is awesome</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2010/02/11/reason-634-why-kyle-cassidy-is-awesome/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2010/02/11/reason-634-why-kyle-cassidy-is-awesome/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Not only is Kyle Cassidy a heck of a photographer, writer and teacher, he is also one hell of a nice guy. I had a lucky chance to meet and learn a few photography skills some months back. He learned that I was also a writer and offered to send me one of his extra fountain pens. I very nearly squeed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve been interested in fountain pens for as long as I can remember. When I was young I used some cheap, cartridge-filled pens on occasion but fell out of habit as I aged. I always admired fountain pens from afar, and lived vicariously through my friend &lt;a href=&#34;1&#34;&gt;Dierdre&lt;/a&gt; and her pen obsession. That pen from Kyle, an old Arnold sitting on the bladder transplant list, resparked that old passion. This past Christmas I received brethren to join my collection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;2&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignnone size-medium wp-image-199&#34; title=&#34;How I write&#34; src=&#34;http://www.adamisrael.com/wp-content/uploads/2010/02/DSC_7228-300x199.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;199&#34; srcset=&#34;//www.adamisrael.com/wp-content/uploads/2010/02/DSC_7228-300x199.jpg 300w, //www.adamisrael.com/wp-content/uploads/2010/02/DSC_7228.jpg 800w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The awesome Kyle is &lt;a href=&#34;3&#34;&gt;running a contest&lt;/a&gt; on his blog and the lucky winners will also receive a nifty fountain pen that is in need of love and affection. Go there. Make a semi-anonymous post with a picture of your notebooks, assuming you&amp;#8217;re like us and write longhand, as well as a small writing sample &amp;#8211; a poem, a paragraph, a snappy retort, whatever.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>