<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Canada on Adam Israel</title>
    <link>http://adamisrael.com/tags/canada/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Canada on Adam Israel</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© 2016 Adam Israel</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://adamisrael.com/tags/canada/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Two years and pocket change</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2012/11/26/two-years-and-pocket-change/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2012/11/26/two-years-and-pocket-change/</guid>
      <description>Two years and two days ago, I started a journey from Santa Monica, California by foot, bus, train, and plane. Many hours later, I reached Detroit and was met by my friend Katni, who drove me through the Detroit-Windsor tunnel where, six months after being kicked out, I re-entered Canada and was reunited with Andrea.
Being home still feels really good.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Independence</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2012/07/05/independence/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2012/07/05/independence/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday was Independence Day back in the states. We already had our fireworks over the weekend, and I worked through Canada Day on Monday and had yesterday off instead. Among the joys of American/Canada relations are mixed holidays.
Our plans were a little more focused. Yesterday we saw an apartment, and made a deposit, and transfered utilities to our name. This was kind of a big deal, because for the first time in more than three years, we&amp;#8217;re in a position to start a new chapter in our lives.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dipping into Canadian Immigration/Politics</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2012/03/05/dipping-into-canadian-immigrationpolitics/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2012/03/05/dipping-into-canadian-immigrationpolitics/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#8217;ve been following the news regarding Canadian Immigration pretty closely &amp;#8212; not surprising considering my immigrant status. Last week this article in the Globe and Mail talks about the percentage of immigrants who settle in Ontario vs. other provinces, which kind of bored me. What was interesting, though, were two issues in the continued fight against immigration fraud. When Andrea and I filled out our application, most of our time was spent collecting evidence to prove our relationship &amp;#8212; records of emails, phone calls, meetings between us, friends, and family, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Februhuh? The winter that wasn’t.</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2012/02/01/februhuh-the-winter-that-wasnt/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2012/02/01/februhuh-the-winter-that-wasnt/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;#8217;s now my second February living in southwest Ontario, with 50F weather and scattered rain showers. The snow, which didn&amp;#8217;t fall until mid-January, is a memory and it will be at least a week before we have any chance of seeing more.
What the hell, Canada?
When people learned I was moving to Canada, I heard all kinds of jokes. Eh? Eh? One was about seeing moose, which I&amp;#8217;ve seen no trace of here but I have found in northern Wisconsin, where my Dad lives.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>To fight the horde, sing and cry: Valhalla, I am coming!</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2010/05/08/to-fight-the-horde-sing-and-cry-valhalla-i-am-coming/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2010/05/08/to-fight-the-horde-sing-and-cry-valhalla-i-am-coming/</guid>
      <description>There’s so much that’s happened in the last twenty-four hours that I scarcely know where to start. For the uninitiated, I am American and my wife, Andrea, is Canadian. I have a house in Illinois, empty and for sale by court order from a previous marriage. In August of last year, my wife and I moved in with her Mom in Ontario, Canada. Prior that we had been living with my Dad in Wisconsin, in his three bedroom trailer, with our three large dogs and four cats, helping him recover from major back surgery.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>