<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>20spec on Adam Israel</title>
    <link>http://adamisrael.com/tags/20spec/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 20spec on Adam Israel</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://adamisrael.com/tags/20spec/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Hard days</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2010/12/28/hard-days/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2010/12/28/hard-days/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve been slogging away, the last few weeks, trying to string together words that make sense. It&amp;#8217;s been rough. A nameless ennui that I blame on not having a place to personalize yet. That&amp;#8217;s something Andrea and I will be working towards in the new year. Meanwhile, life goes on and the writing must continue so I had to find a way. Deadlines usually help, but I&amp;#8217;ve been staring two or three, maybe four, up the ugly side so much lately that I&amp;#8217;m beginning to go cross-eyed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This past week, I simply used a calendar to block out my time to write or work or even eat. That&amp;#8217;s taken me from fretting over my non-existent progress to putting my butt in the chair and editing for seven and a half hours over the past three days. Not only did I finish a revision of my Tesla&amp;#8217;s Daughter story, but I know just how long I spent working on it and I have a real sense of accomplishment for turning around what was feeling like a serious nose dive in the confidence department.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, if only my beta readers have some kind, constructive words (hint, hint). I have three days to get this polished up and submitted. Nothing like cutting it close to the wire.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Travel ahoy</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2010/10/10/travel-ahoy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2010/10/10/travel-ahoy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s a good feeling to put the word END after the last paragraph of a manuscript. This story was born week five of Clarion but I couldn&amp;#8217;t make it work then. A little bit of time away and with four days of sporadic effort, it&amp;#8217;s a story. Rough around the edges like any first draft but I expect those will be caught when I sent it to beta readers later this week. Shitty first draft or not, I&amp;#8217;m pleased with how it&amp;#8217;s turned out so far.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Project: Sex/magic story, now with more poly love, a plump dominatrix, a Chicago swinger&amp;#8217;s club, and one pissed off magician, tentatively titled &lt;span style=&#34;text-decoration: underline;&#34;&gt;The Way Out is Through&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;New words written: 484&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reason for stopping: End of story&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://picometer.writertopia.com/words=4042&amp;amp;target=4000&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tomorrow is a travel day for me. Back to Santa Monica for a week of work and, with luck, more success in finding a room or apartment for rent. While I&amp;#8217;m galavanting across the country, I&amp;#8217;ll be outlining my story for the [20Spec anthology][2], which is open for submissions on October 11th. The plan is to get &lt;span style=&#34;text-decoration: underline;&#34;&gt;The Way Out is Through&lt;/span&gt; sent off to a couple of beta readers and then work on the first draft of my tale of Romani revenge, Eye of the People.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[2]: &lt;a href=&#34;http://wingsliftingwide.wordpress.com/2010/09/14/advance-notice-20spec-anthology/&#34;&gt;http://wingsliftingwide.wordpress.com/2010/09/14/advance-notice-20spec-anthology/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>