<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ubuntu On Mac on Adam Israel</title>
    <link>http://dev.adamisrael.com/tags/ubuntu-on-mac/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ubuntu On Mac on Adam Israel</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://dev.adamisrael.com/tags/ubuntu-on-mac/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu on Mac</title>
      <link>http://dev.adamisrael.com/blog/2015/10/15/ubuntu-on-mac/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://dev.adamisrael.com/blog/2015/10/15/ubuntu-on-mac/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently rebuilt a Mac Mini to work as the forth screen in my workflow. I googled around and pieced together what I needed to do by cherrypicking from various guides, and everything was running well until I updated to a new kernel and rebooted. I spent the better part of two nights trying to get the machine to boot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, it happened just after I blacklisted a module to work around a USB bug that was causing one of my drives to go haywire occasionally, and it took a while before I finally figured out it wasn&amp;#8217;t a problem with my change but the kernel itself. Mac&amp;#8217;s use EFI for booting &amp;#8212; which requires a cryptographically signed kernel. I was finally able to boot up by following the first half of the instructions on &lt;a href=&#34;1&#34;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; Ask Ubuntu answer. Essentially, do a manual boot via grub and make sure that I pick the secure kernel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I noticed that I only had a signed image for an older version of the Kernel. I dropped by #ubuntu-kernel and was pointed to the &lt;strong&gt;linux-signed-generic&lt;/strong&gt; package. What happened is none of the guides I read had mentioned this package or its significance. Any time the kernel images are updated, the signed version is also updated, except you won&amp;#8217;t get that image by default. The machine was trying to boot off an unsigned kernel, causing the boot sequence to freeze (with no indication as to why).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre class=&#34;lang:sh decode:true &#34; &gt;sudo apt-get update
sudo apt-get install linux-signed-generic
sudo reboot&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A thorn with an easy fix. Install the meta package, which will pull in the current signed image, and reboot.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>