<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Health on Adam Israel</title>
    <link>http://adamisrael.com/tags/health/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Health on Adam Israel</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://adamisrael.com/tags/health/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Designated Driver</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2012/04/06/designated-driver/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2012/04/06/designated-driver/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We spent the better part of this week in Toronto &amp;#8212; an impromptu trip after receiving a call with some concerning medical news on Sunday night. So, for the first half of the week we’ve explored the inner workings of the Toronto hospital system. As someone who more or less grew up inside hospitals, I’ve made some observations:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Whoever is running the parking system is making a killing. We spent as much on parking as we did on food for two.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The profits from parking aren’t being spent on hospital IT, because I’m pretty you’d have to try pretty hard to make a system that failed in its communications that badly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The need for patient advocates is just as great, if not more so, here. I’m undecided if that’s because it’s a large city with a supposedly interconnected system or public health in general.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Out of respect for his privacy, I’m not going to go into too many details publicly. T- is ill (fuck cancer, so say we all). We took him for an outpatient biopsy Tuesday and suffered from a rare complication that landed him in the hospital overnight. That postponed a diagnostic test for an equally serious but unrelated condition scheduled for Thursday. Not the news that T- wanted to hear, but his doctors &amp;#8212; and there are many &amp;#8212; are working hard to get him healthy again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was thinking of heading to Toronto next weekend for [Ad Astra][1]. The last convention I went to was World Fantasy in 2010 and I’d like to start meeting some local-ish writer folk. The doctors rescheduled T-’s next test for the day after Ad Astra so that cleared me for con activity without guilt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[1]: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ad-astra.org/&#34;&gt;http://www.ad-astra.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wither the sickness</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2012/01/04/wither-the-sickness/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2012/01/04/wither-the-sickness/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Life with chronic health conditions and no health insurance is interesting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmedhealth/PMH0001280/&#34;&gt;Celiac&lt;/a&gt; disease is pretty much a condition of maintenance. There’s no cure and the only preventative measure is avoiding eating or drinking gluten (wheat, barley, rye, and oats). Gluten is everywhere. Beer and bread are bad but I’ve found it in foods I would never have suspected, like tomato soup, sausage and lunch meats, and many, many sauces. Flour is a cheap filler and thickener so it’s commonly used, which makes the life of a celiac a royal bitch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was diagnosed with fibromyalgia first, and celiac disease a few months apart, in early 2010. Both came on the heels of a lot of effort on my part to document and self-diagnose, to some degree, my own condition. One of my knees was so inflamed that I limped noticeably for months and at the apex I had to crawl up stairs on hands and knees because of the pain. My rheumatologist diagnosed that as one of the symptoms of my fibromyalgia and that was that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had good doctors then, that supported my efforts to self-diagnose, within reason. I did my own testing with diet changes, for example, that led to discovering my sensitivity to wheat, and they ran medical tests to verify and confirm. &lt;a href=&#34;http://xkcd.com/54/&#34;&gt;Science. It works, bitches.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been gluten-free, aside from the random and mostly rare accidental glutening, for about eighteen months. The first six months or so I felt great; my knee inflammation disappeared completely and many of the other symptoms associated with fibromyalgia had eased up as well. That general sense of well-being began tapering off, though. I was as strict, if not more so, with my diet, but nothing seemed to reverse that trend. Complicating matters were my symptoms of fibromyalgia, which worsened.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My sleeping pattern became erratic, when I could sleep at all. Lethargy was my lonely friend and I constantly worked through a teeth-gnashing mental fog. On two occasions, minimal exercise caused such a crash that I slept for days. We worried about my health, my ability to function, to work. I’d spent my late nights reading through journal articles, medical studies and message forums about fibromyalgia and Celiac symptoms and treatments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A month or so ago, one of my online friends whose been through some medical issues blogged and, in the comments said something about not ruling in fibromyalgia without further testing, especially with celiac. My knee jerk reaction was to get upset (sorry D. &amp;lt;3) but it got me thinking. I realized she was right, especially given the proclivity of doctors, despite their best intentions, to misdiagnose fibro in the presence of celiac.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I woke from sleep one night and in a moment of clarity remembered that, a few months prior to my celiac diagnosis, I nearly had scurvy and other assorted vitamin deficiency-related issues. The doctor put me on a daily regiment of vitamins that, a few months later, put my levels back to normal. When we realized I was celiac, I (or we) thought that must be the cause and &lt;em&gt;I stopped taking the vitamins&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The kicker about celiac: it damages the lining of your small intestine, sometimes permanently, but it can take years for it to fully recover once you&amp;#8217;re gluten-free. This prevents the absorption of nutrients from the foods you eat. Essentially, I was malnourished even though I’d been eating a healthy, gluten-free diet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whoops.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m three weeks back on my vitamins (for the curious: 500mg vitamin C twice/day, 1,000 IU vitamin D twice/day, 50mg zinc once/day) and I feel remarkably different. The mental fog has cleared. I’m back on a regular, consistent sleep schedule and my energy levels are starting to return.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’ll be summer before all the paperwork is done and I can see a doctor regularly again and get regular check-ups. That sucks, more than a little, but this close call reminded me of something I’m a fan of: body hacking. Safely, of course, but we are essentially a biological computer in a wetware exosuit. A biomech, if you will.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Done smartly — scientifically — who knows what you’ll discover. I’ve been doing it out of necessity, in a small way. Humanity has been finding ways to do it since forever (care for a cup of coffee?). Also worth mentioning, &lt;a href=&#34;http://futurefire.net/index.html&#34;&gt;The Future Fire&lt;/a&gt; just announced a call for submissions for their thematically-related anthology, [Outlaw Bodies][4].&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[4]: &lt;a href=&#34;http://futurefire.net/about/outlawbodies.html&#34;&gt;http://futurefire.net/about/outlawbodies.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A follow-up to Spoon! (not the musical)</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2011/11/14/a-follow-up-to-spoon-not-the-musical/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2011/11/14/a-follow-up-to-spoon-not-the-musical/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I can&amp;#8217;t believe it&amp;#8217;s been almost a year and a half since my &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.adamisrael.com/blog/2010/06/21/spoon/&#34;&gt;Spoon!&lt;/a&gt; blog post, where a group of friends conspired to sent me their &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.butyoudontlooksick.com/articles/written-by-christine/the-spoon-theory-written-by-christine-miserandino/&#34;&gt;spoons&lt;/a&gt; to counteract the loss of my own thanks to newly acquired but chronic illness during a time of great life upheaval.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table style=&#34;border: none; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.adamisrael.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/11/spoons.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-664 aligncenter&#34; title=&#34;Spoons&#34; src=&#34;http://www.adamisrael.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/11/spoons-300x199.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;199&#34; srcset=&#34;//www.adamisrael.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/11/spoons-300x199.jpg 300w, //www.adamisrael.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/11/spoons-1024x680.jpg 1024w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I carried this box of carefully wrapped spoons with me everywhere. I received it in Illinois, where I was living with my Mom pre-Clarion. To San Diego it came for six weeks, to follow me to Santa Monica by air, back to Illinois by air, once again to Santa Monica but by post, back to San Diego hand-carried by foot, bus, and train, and then air once again to Illinois where it (and I) rested the night before continuing on to Detroit airport and a brief car ride through the tunnel to Canada.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table style=&#34;border: none; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.adamisrael.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/11/spoons1.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter size-medium wp-image-665&#34; title=&#34;spoons1&#34; src=&#34;http://www.adamisrael.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/11/spoons1-300x199.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;199&#34; srcset=&#34;//www.adamisrael.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/11/spoons1-300x199.jpg 300w, //www.adamisrael.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/11/spoons1-1024x680.jpg 1024w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
    
    &lt;td&gt;
      &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.adamisrael.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/11/spoons2.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter size-medium wp-image-666&#34; title=&#34;spoons2&#34; src=&#34;http://www.adamisrael.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/11/spoons2-300x199.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;199&#34; srcset=&#34;//www.adamisrael.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/11/spoons2-300x199.jpg 300w, //www.adamisrael.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/11/spoons2-1024x680.jpg 1024w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The box has sat for nearly a year, its beloved contents awaiting a proper home. In that time, I&amp;#8217;ve carved out a small office for myself but it took until now to figure out an adequate way to show assemble the spoons with the respect that they deserve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table style=&#34;border: none; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.adamisrael.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/11/spoons_flower.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter size-medium wp-image-663&#34; title=&#34;Spoon Flower&#34; src=&#34;http://www.adamisrael.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/11/spoons_flower-300x199.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;199&#34; srcset=&#34;//www.adamisrael.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/11/spoons_flower-300x199.jpg 300w, //www.adamisrael.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/11/spoons_flower-1024x680.jpg 1024w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the best I can do for now. Better this than in a box, out of sight but never forgotten. As socially introverted as I feel at times, my friends mean more to me than words can do justice. These spoons are just one example of the bonds that tie us together. When this was organized, most of us had never met before. Now, I think we&amp;#8217;ve all met at least once. There&amp;#8217;ve been weddings, the founding of the [Inkpunks][3], and lots of shared love. That makes all of life&amp;#8217;s pains a whole lot easier to bear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[3]: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.inkpunks.com&#34;&gt;http://www.inkpunks.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cognitive Dissidence</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2010/06/07/cognitive-dissidence/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2010/06/07/cognitive-dissidence/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Guess what? I feel better. Better than I have in five years or so. What changed? Interesting, that&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A couple weeks ago, I decided to do a reboot of the diet. My reading on &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fibromyalgia&#34;&gt;Fibromyalgia&lt;/a&gt; led me to discussions of [Celiac disease][2] and how much of an overlap there is between the two. I figured that going back to a basic diet of protein, vegetable, and fruit for a week or two would be a good reset. What I didn’t expect was how much different I would feel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The pain in my knee went away almost entirely. The fatigue went from being a daily battle is now just an occasional struggle. Instead of sleeping six fitful hours I’m now down for nine and feeling well-rested. The cognitive issues &amp;#8212; difficulty concentrating and remembering &amp;#8212; have improved drastically. My GI issues have also made a very welcome change for the better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe it’s not Fibromyalgia after all. Maybe it’s a combination of the two. Lupus still hasn’t officially been ruled out but I should find that out Thursday. In any case, I feel better and that’s what counts. I’ve re-introduced everything but gluten in my diet and I still feel good. The one day I did try eating gluten, well, let’s just say it wasn’t a fun day. I’m relatively sure we’re no longer on speaking terms. The only problem is that diagnosing Celiac usually requires you to be on a gluten-rich diet and, uh, hell no.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that my brain is getting back to normal, I’m finding that I am far behind where I’d like to be in pretty much everything. Clarion’s coming up quickly so I’m finishing what I can now and you can be sure that there will be much ass kicking and fixing of things once I return.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[2]: &lt;a href=&#34;https://health.google.com/health/ref/Celiac+disease+-+sprue&#34;&gt;https://health.google.com/health/ref/Celiac+disease+-+sprue&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This and that</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2010/05/24/this-and-that/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2010/05/24/this-and-that/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This was a good news/bad news kind of week on the medical front. I wish I had more energy to talk about it, but I am running low on [spoons][1] and need to conserve them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good news:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul style=&#34;list-style-type: disc&#34;&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    Kidneys and Thyroid are normal.
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    It’s not Multiple Sclerosis.
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    It’s probably not Lupus.
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bad news:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul style=&#34;list-style-type: disc&#34;&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    There is still a chance it could be Lupus, so I had more blood drawn to confirm/deny.
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    I do have Fibromyalgia. All of the symptoms fit.
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    I need to have a sleep test to determine if I’m suffering from sleep apnea or cataplexy, and to see if it explains the occasional fugue states I sometimes experience.
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will have a lot more to say about Fibromyalgia. Right now I’m still in the acceptance phase, which isn’t always easy. Figuring out my limitations and triggers is going to take some time. I’ve already started re-evaluating my diet, to try and determine what foods may be causing flares. I imagine that this could be a long process of self-discovery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also have just over a month before I leave for Clarion, so I’m going to be busy wrapping up all of the legal and medical stuff, and reading. Lots and lots of reading. Lots of work, too. And when Clarion is over, I can go back home to Canada. If I’m quiet, sullen or manic, well, you know why.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[1]: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.butyoudontlooksick.com/articles/personal-essays/the-spoon-theory-written-by-christine-miserandino/&#34;&gt;http://www.butyoudontlooksick.com/articles/personal-essays/the-spoon-theory-written-by-christine-miserandino/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lemon Lyme</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2010/05/14/lemon-lyme/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2010/05/14/lemon-lyme/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I had hopefully one of the last post-divorce court dates this morning. Nothing terribly surprising came out of it. Judge says I need to pay my ex’s lawyer fees since I didn’t meet the original terms of the agreement (to which my attorney still argues was an impossibility). That’s a hard lesson chalked up to experience. Never be afraid to question your lawyer, or fire them, if you don’t think they have your best interest at heart. This morning boils down to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul style=&#34;list-style-type: disc&#34;&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    I owe a bunch of money I don’t have
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    I don’t have a lot of time to pay it
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll be figuring out a plan of action over the next week, but I’ll find a way of pulling it off and put that bill behind me. It may be time to say goodbye to my desktop computer and monitors, though. Anything I can do without, I will. I’m pretty accustomed to life on the laptop now anyways. Frankly, the more I can get rid of, the less I have to move and the sooner I can do it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Health-wise, it’s been an odd week. I had a theory about all of the symptoms I’m having. Between the autoimmune and similarities between Fibromyalgia, Chronic Fatigue, and Lyme Disease, I decided to get re-tested for Lyme. I spent last summer taking care of Dad in Wisconsin and had more than a few tick bites for my efforts. The good news is that test came back negative. The bad means we’re no closure to figuring out what’s wrong. Next week, I hope, will start bringing some answers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve also had three nights this week where I’ve been in bed before 10pm and slept more than 8 hours. That’s highly unusual for me. It felt good while it lasted. The insomnia and restlessness seems to be back tonight, but hey, I also wrote 300 words of a new story so I won’t complain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tomorrow I’m off by train to Chicago for the day. I have a meeting for the day job that will hopefully lead to bigger and brighter things for the company. More resources means more time I can spend doing the things that make money, which takes care of many of our current worries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My friends and family, you are all awesome. I miss being home with Andrea and the menagerie dearly but this is turning into a life lesson about getting things done that need doing and not procrastinating. Summer will fly by, debts will be settled, and life will move on together.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It’s never Lupus.</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2010/04/20/its-never-lupus/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2010/04/20/its-never-lupus/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Earlier this month I &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.adamisrael.com/blog/2010/04/10/the-state-of-adam/&#34;&gt;mentioned&lt;/a&gt; that I was heading in for some long overdue checkup with the doctor. Many of you have been following my progress on [Twitter][2]. I’m a firm believer in paying it forward and that includes being open and honest about sensitive topics. Forewarned is forearmed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went to my primary care physician (PCP) on Monday to have a few persistent issues looked at. What started as a simple checkup turned into a week long ordeal in which I was poked, prodded, and gently cupped by the warm hands of two upstanding gentleman.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first issue was a lump on my right testicle, now affectionally know as the double-yolk. It has been there for fifteen years or so. I saw a Urologist when it was first discovered and he deemed it benign. When I noticed blood in my ejaculate recently, I knew it was time to get it looked at again. Gentlemen, be sure to perform regular self-exams.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second issue was for continued, persistent nerve pain. It started with a bang last July and was diagnosed as a pinched nerve in my shoulder by an ER doctor. That pain comes and goes, but the nerve pain has spread across my upper back, lower back, and from my hips to my knees. Additionally, I have some confirmed but not identified nerve damage causing the left side of my left foot to be numb. A history of balance issues and ringing in the ears going on two years now, both concentrated on the left side of my body, with chronic nerve pain, sets off some red flags.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, I’ve been having issues with temperature control. For a several weeks my normally warm feet were freezing. I took to wearing socks around the house, even if I was wearing shorts. I was also breaking out into a sweat just sitting and watching TV, no exertion required. The doctor was concerned that something autoimmune was at foot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I peed in a cup, gave up a few vials of precious blood and got referrals for a Urologist and Neurologist. On my last appointment, my PCP told me to make an appointment with a Neurologist but the one I wanted to see was booked solid for two months. I called him late Monday morning and lucked into an open spot the next day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tuesday morning I head to court to find out how much of my ex-wife’s lawyer I have to pay. There end up being scheduling issues and the hearing is postponed til next month. From there I head to the Neurologist, Dr. Echiverri. He looks over the medical records I brought with me, tested my reflexes and eyes and listened to my symptom history. This is where things get interesting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Four years ago I went through a period of six or nine months where I randomly lost my balance, but only to the left side. My doctor at the time suggested a handful of possibilities, including allergies and Multiple Sclerosis (MS). After lots of trial and error with allergy medicine, my balance improved. The doctor chalked this up to successful treatment and sent me on my merry way. For my part, I was just happy that I wasn’t listing like the Titanic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dr. Echiverri stopped me and said that I should have an MRI as soon as I had balance issues without dizziness. He agreed that there was some concern about the possibility of MS and literally escorted me to the scheduling department and told them to get me in that day. Ninety minutes later I was a human tampon wedged into an electromagnetic vagina.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wednesday I went to the Urologist, who agreed that the lump doesn’t seem to be an immediate concern and that the blood I saw can happen occasionally. Because of my family history of kidney problems and my Diabetes, he ordered some tests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had an ultrasound and X-ray of my kidneys Thursday morning, and on the fifth day I rested.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yesterday I called my primary doctor to check on the results of my blood work and ask them to fax me a copy. An hour or so later I get a call back from his nurse, a very nice lady named Cookie. Whenever a nurse starts off a conversation with “Now don’t panic when you read this” you know your day is about to take a left turn. The “Anachoice &amp;reg; Screen” and “RNP Antibody” tests came back positive. From the diagnostics lab:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RNP antibody is found in patiences with mixed connective tissue disease in high titer. This antibody may also be seen in systemic lupus erythematosus and other connective tissue diseases. A positive result at this stage of testing stops further testing, and does not preclude additional positive antibodies. Clinical correlation is required to access the need for testing other analytes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first time I read this I stopped when I saw Lupus. Some armchair research shows that these positive tests can also be an indicator for MS. So now I have an appointment with Rheumatologists, who will continue the diagnose why my body is being emo, and a follow-up with the Neurologist to see what my brain looks like. I have to wait a month for both appointments, though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This morning, I went to the Cardiac Clinic for a nuclear stress test. The nurse injected me with saline and a tracer, ran me through a machine to take pictures of my heart, forced me to hustle on a treadmill at needlepoint while injecting more tracer and stuck me back into the machine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As they were explaining the procedure to me, I asked how long the radioactive dye would stay in my system. I was planning to head home to Canada afterwards. I got a wide-eyed stare, and she called the nurse who would make my roll for gaining a superpower. She told me that Friday would be the earliest I should go. The radioactive tracer is externally detectable and she had a patient that was stopped and had their truck torn apart, including the seats removed, at the border and that with a note from the clinic detailing the procedure and elements used.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Look &amp;#8212; crossing the border is already a stressful experience. The very last thing I want to do is trip someone’s geiger counter and get flagged as suspicious or turned away. As eager as I am to get home and see my better half, our pets, John, and Mom R., I want to do so with the least chance of being jellyfingered by a burly guard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of things are running through my mind these days. I am blessed that none of my symptoms point to anything immediately life threatening. Still, it does make one reevaluate their priorities in life. I’ve already spent weeks apart from my loved ones this year with more on the horizon, and too much of the time we have spent together has found me wasting time online. Priorities need to be adjusted from time to time and this is one of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m cutting out games that can’t simply be put down or away. If I can’t logout and pick back up where I left off another time, I’m sorry but we can no longer see each other. I’m going to force myself to get away from the laptop every day. Andrea and I will walk the dogs or go to the park; disconnecting will be good for us. It’ll help me focus on losing the excess weight that, while not the cause of all of my problems, certainly doesn’t help them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of my friends asked if this was going to impact my plans of going to Clarion this summer and I didn’t have an immediate answer to that. Clarion is a unique opportunity. One thing I’ve asked myself is if I could put it off a year. Sure, it’s possible, but next years instructors might not be ones that I feel a connection with. Or work might be different, living situations changed, etc. Putting it off is a slippery slope that can lead to a lifetime of regret. I guess the long answer is no, this is’t going to impact my going to Clarion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have very few answers to the medical puzzle that is my body. I should have more test results this week, and several follow-up appointments next month. I don’t know if I have MS or Lupus (Dr. House says that it’s never Lupus) or something else unconsidered. I’d rather know what is causing this rather than treating symptoms at random and I think I finally have the right doctors for that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My tribe is awesome. The outpouring of support has been overwhelming. If you’ve tweeted or emailed me, thank you. I’ve often felt like an outsider in this wonderful extended family of ours but this week has shown me that is not the case.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[2]: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/AdamIsrael&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/AdamIsrael&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The State of Adam</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2010/04/10/the-state-of-adam/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2010/04/10/the-state-of-adam/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I used to think I was a superhero. A rotund, pasty, privileged superhero, but superhero none the less. I’ve held jobs more or less consistently since the time I was twelve. How much I work became a running joke among my friends. I abused my body with unhealthy amounts of caffeine to squeeze more work hours out of each day, and I did this for years without much of a break.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last year when my Dad needed surgery, we packed up our dog and cat show and headed north to take care of him. I worked my forty plus, ran errands, made sure doctors appointments were made and kept, and did the occasional shuffle from Tomahawk, WI to Minneapolis, MN for check-ups with the surgeons. Three months later, Dad was healed up and I was falling apart, freshly diagnosed with at least one pinched nerve and Diabetes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My body had been trying to tell me something and I finally had to stop and listen. “Only human.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tomorrow I’m heading back to Illinois. There’s one more post-divorce court date to attend to. More importantly, I’m *cough* getting to that age when it’s prudent to get ones pipes cleaned and tubes checked. I can’t ignore the aches, pains and lumps any longer. The doctor awaits my arrival Monday morning and there I’ll stay until we get things fixed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a lot of things to look forward to: an awesome wife and best friend, adventures living in a new country, writing. Who knows, maybe kids will be in our cards, too. I need to be as healthy as I can so I can enjoy that life.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Not dead yet.</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2010/02/18/not-dead-yet/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2010/02/18/not-dead-yet/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My mom had reconstructive ankle surgery to correct some of long-term damage caused by polio so I spent the last few weeks with her, doing laundry and cooking and whatnot. I also took the opportunity to wear down my annual deductible and get a few lingering medical issues looked at. And while in Illinois, I picked up a rather nasty flu that has wiped me out completely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of the effects of the flu are gone, knock on wood. My energy seems to be the last thing to return. I&amp;#8217;ve been regularly sleeping 10-12 hours/day, which is a far cry from my usual 6-7. It&amp;#8217;s cut into my writing time severely, including updates here and on twitter. I suspect I&amp;#8217;ll be back to normal in a few more days and will be back to work on things. End of month deadlines that must be met, flu or no flu.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This glass ceiling also has a floor and four walls</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2010/01/27/this-glass-ceiling-also-has-a-floor-and-four-walls/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2010/01/27/this-glass-ceiling-also-has-a-floor-and-four-walls/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;From time to time I talk about things of an extremely personal nature. Talking is cathartic and healthier than the alternative. Herein I ramble about depression, anxiety, and other foibles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Six and a half years ago I had a pretty good bout with depression. I recognized it and, most importantly, sought help for it. One of the unintended side effects of anti-depression medicine is that it&amp;#8217;s used to treat a number of afflictions. When the depression had been treated I was weaned off of the medication and things were fine &amp;#8212; for a while. I was pretty sure that the old blues were back again and a trip to the doctor today confirmed those fears.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;#8217;s more to how I&amp;#8217;ve been feeling than just depression, and it&amp;#8217;s probably my bigger concern. I&amp;#8217;ve suspected it for a while but it&amp;#8217;s been all but confirmed now. I have social anxiety disorder. I imagine there will be two types of reaction from people that know me &amp;#8212; disbelief and confirmation. With some people I am more or less at complete ease but in other situations I fall all over myself. When the anxiety kicks in, I either stutter or start talking fast and can&amp;#8217;t stop myself, or stop talking all together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imagine living inside of a glass box with a one-way speaker, so you can see and hear everything going on around but no one can year you no matter how loud you scream or shout. That&amp;#8217;s a little bit what it&amp;#8217;s been like dealing with this anxiety. I try to talk, I &lt;em&gt;want&lt;/em&gt; to talk, but the words won&amp;#8217;t come out. It&amp;#8217;s frustrating. It&amp;#8217;s embarrassing. It&amp;#8217;s demoralizing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve had this for a long time. Probably before the first bout of depression. I remember the first time I had a panic attack, close to a decade ago and the anxiety I feel every time I go to a convention or to any place where I have to interact with people. Trying to talk to a well-respected writer at a convention, only to end up mumbling and walking away? I&amp;#8217;ve been that guy, on more than one occasion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the reasons why I suspected there was something more than shyness or nervousness happening is that I want to interact. I want to walk up and talk to people, to ask questions, participate in conversation, and be normal. On rare and special occasion I meet someone that I feel so at ease with that I can talk and talk and talk. Online conversations are also something that comes easier than face-to-face but even those I sometimes struggle with because my lack of social experience makes it difficult to how to respond to some things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some people don&amp;#8217;t like social interaction. I do. I want to be a part of the conversation and not just a witness to it. I have a voice but cannot speak. The words fail to materialize, a spell broken before its even cast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s been a long and stressful day and I&amp;#8217;m rambling a bit. Treating the depression also treats the anxiety. The roots of the anxiety need to be exposed so they can be chopped away so that I can be free of it once and for all. I need this for me, and I need it for my family. They deserve me at my best so we can enjoy life together instead of watching it pass us by.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>