<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Adam Israel</title>
    <link>http://adamisrael.com/tags/toronto/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Adam Israel</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© 2016 Adam Israel</copyright>
    <atom:link href="http://adamisrael.com/tags/toronto/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Con report: World Fantasy 2012</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2012/11/05/con-report-world-fantasy-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2012/11/05/con-report-world-fantasy-2012/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Andrea and I drove up  to Toronto &amp;#8212; or Richmond Hill, one of its northern suburbs &amp;#8212; for World Fantasy 2012 on Friday. This was my second World Fantasy (the first being Columbus two years ago) and Andrea&amp;#8217;s first.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hotel(s):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We stayed at the Holiday Inn Express, one of the overflow hotels. That hotel itself was pleasant, albiet slightly incompetent. One elevator was out of order the entire stay. Andrea was trapped between floors in the second elevator on Saturday and had to be rescued by the fire department. I heard the same thing happened on Sunday, leaving guests to trundle down the stairs with their luggage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second overflow hotel was separated by a six lane highway under construction, and it looked like the sidewalks were torn up. Add to that the steep ramps  between the panel rooms and this spoonie fears there were some serious accessibility issues for those worse off than I.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The panels I attended:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Faith and Fantasy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Defining Urban Fantasy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They Call Me The Wanderer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bibliofantasies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Lexicon of Horror&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reality Made Fantastic, or Fantasy Made Real&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
  By and large, the panels were well-moderated (although there were frustrating exceptions). One thing I enjoy about the panels universally is the cross-pollination of ideas. I figured out how to fix three stories during panels, and gave me a new way of approaching stories that I&amp;#8217;m stuck on.
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
  The readings:
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Readings from EPIC, edited by John Joseph Adams: Aliette de Bodard,  Brandon Sanderson, Mary Robinette Kowal, and Patrick Rothfuss.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Readings from The _Mad Scientist&amp;#8217;s Guide_ to World Domination: David D. Levine and Genevieve Valentine&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
  All of the readings were well-done but the standout here is David Levine, who&amp;#8217;s reading of &amp;#8220;Letter to the Editor&amp;#8221; was absolutely stunning.
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
  The people:
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
  Ultimately, going to the con was about seeing friends, new and old. It was a gathering of half of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.inkpunks.com/&#34;&gt;Inkpunks&lt;/a&gt;. My Clarion classmates John Chu and Karin Tidbeck were in attendance, where we celebrated the launch of Karin&amp;#8217;s short story collection &lt;em&gt;Jagannath&lt;/em&gt;. There are so many other people I met, was reacquainted with, or caught up with. I couldn&amp;#8217;t begin to name names without leaving someone out. There were more that I missed, only saw in in passing, or didn&amp;#8217;t spend nearly enough time talking to.
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;#8217;s a certain buzz one feels on the heels of a con. Like a battery, warm and slightly overcharged, ready to be put to work.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ad Astra Wrapup</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2012/04/16/ad-astra-wrapup/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2012/04/16/ad-astra-wrapup/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My first Ad Astra is over, and I didn&amp;#8217;t completely embarrass myself. Huzzah!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ll admit to being intimidated at first, not knowing anyone. It&amp;#8217;s a good-sized local convention with a lot of history and people know already each other. What I finally realized, though, is that I just needed to _politely_ join in the conversation. Everyone was welcoming and, even better, assumed I was Canadian. I swear, I am in all but name.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I saw there was a writing contest &amp;#8212; 250 words based on a handful of prompts &amp;#8212; and I pounced on that. It let me meet a nice group of writers and editors that I wouldn&amp;#8217;t have had the opportunity to interact with at that level otherwise. I wrote the story Friday night (longhand first, then transcribed and edited), printed it out Saturday, and we received the results on Sunday. As these things happen, as I was sitting in the room waiting to talk to one of the judges, I had a breakthrough regarding flash that was soon confirmed by more than one of the judges. Flash fiction is like a single breath of air, and I&amp;#8217;d forced the reader to stop and gulp in the middle of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Harry Turtledove was one of the Guests of Honor. I sat in one of his panels, on creating viable cultures in world-building. Fascinating stuff. It evolved into conversation about historical research and alternate history between him and Ed Greenwood, which was awesome and worth the price of admission alone. My two favorite quotes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;That feeling of depth, that the world keeps going when the author stops looking.&amp;#8221; Harry Turtledove, talking about Lord of the Rings&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;The harder you make your reader work, the smaller your audience.&amp;#8221; Ed Greenwood&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s always great to meet people I&amp;#8217;ve only known online. After a previous near-miss, I finally got to spend a few minutes chatting with &lt;a href=&#34;1&#34;&gt;Shay Darrach&lt;/a&gt;. I also got to spend some time with &lt;a href=&#34;2&#34;&gt;Gabrielle Harbowy&lt;/a&gt;, who I met through a mutual friend. That lead me to the launch party for Dragon Moon Press, which was a blast. Debut author &lt;a href=&#34;3&#34;&gt;Leah Petersen&lt;/a&gt; read from her novel and did a fabulous job, as did &lt;a href=&#34;4&#34;&gt;Marie Bilodeau&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sunday, I went to a panel on &amp;#8216;Revising and The Pitch&amp;#8217;. At least, I thought it was a panel but it was really an interactive two-hour workshop led by &lt;a href=&#34;5&#34;&gt;Julie Czerneda&lt;/a&gt; and it was awesome. In groups of three, we were given prompts and created &amp;#8212; and then revised &amp;#8212; a pitch for a story. Again, some good quotes came out of the panel, these regarding revision:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;As perfect as time permits.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;You have to learn to write to deadline; you may as well start by giving yourself one.&amp;#8221; Julie Czerneda&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Conventions have always left me with renewed spirits. Now, as I&amp;#8217;m gearing up to finish this novel, I feel like I have even more clarity. Not necessarily about the writing itself, but about in believing it can be done. It&amp;#8217;s easy to escape into short stories, because I&amp;#8217;ve written those, had those published. They&amp;#8217;re my safe place. A novel is a big, scary thing. That unknown feels less scary and more manageable right now, though, and that makes me very happy.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Going to Ad Astra 2012</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2012/04/09/going-to-ad-astra-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2012/04/09/going-to-ad-astra-2012/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So, due to timing of &lt;a href=&#34;1&#34;&gt;unfortunate circumstances&lt;/a&gt;, it&amp;#8217;s become rather convenient for me to go to &lt;a href=&#34;2&#34;&gt;Ad Astra&lt;/a&gt;, April 13-15th. This will, notably, be my first convention since moving to Canada.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m relatively new to both country and the local genre community. I know there are a few members of Codex going and I recognize a few names from the panelist list (including Ed Greenwood, who was very kind towards a 19-year old me at Gen Con Milwaukee some years ago) but I&amp;#8217;m otherwise winging this. I&amp;#8217;m not exactly shy, but I&amp;#8217;m not going to impose myself on people I don&amp;#8217;t know, either.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are you going? Please, say hi!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Designated Driver</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2012/04/06/designated-driver/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2012/04/06/designated-driver/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We spent the better part of this week in Toronto &amp;#8212; an impromptu trip after receiving a call with some concerning medical news on Sunday night. So, for the first half of the week we’ve explored the inner workings of the Toronto hospital system. As someone who more or less grew up inside hospitals, I’ve made some observations:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Whoever is running the parking system is making a killing. We spent as much on parking as we did on food for two.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The profits from parking aren’t being spent on hospital IT, because I’m pretty you’d have to try pretty hard to make a system that failed in its communications that badly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The need for patient advocates is just as great, if not more so, here. I’m undecided if that’s because it’s a large city with a supposedly interconnected system or public health in general.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Out of respect for his privacy, I’m not going to go into too many details publicly. T- is ill (fuck cancer, so say we all). We took him for an outpatient biopsy Tuesday and suffered from a rare complication that landed him in the hospital overnight. That postponed a diagnostic test for an equally serious but unrelated condition scheduled for Thursday. Not the news that T- wanted to hear, but his doctors &amp;#8212; and there are many &amp;#8212; are working hard to get him healthy again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was thinking of heading to Toronto next weekend for &lt;a href=&#34;1&#34;&gt;Ad Astra&lt;/a&gt;. The last convention I went to was World Fantasy in 2010 and I’d like to start meeting some local-ish writer folk. The doctors rescheduled T-’s next test for the day after Ad Astra so that cleared me for con activity without guilt.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recapping Toronto</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2011/09/23/recapping-toronto/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2011/09/23/recapping-toronto/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We went to Toronto last week. Sort of a mini-vacation. We planned the trip around a few events and winged the rest. We didn&amp;#8217;t realize the Toronto International Film Festival (TIFF) was happening, which sort of made finding last minute hotel rooms an adventure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We headed up Sunday, with an all too brief stopover along the way to meet up with twitter pal &lt;a href=&#34;1&#34;&gt;SheikYurbouti&lt;/a&gt;, followed by a mad rush to make it downtown in time for the first of our first of three Pearl Jam concerts. Yes, three. I&amp;#8217;d taken Andrea to see Eddie Vedder &amp;#8212; the lead singer &amp;#8212; perform solo a few times but this was my first time seeing them as a group. This trip made Andrea&amp;#8217;s tenth, eleventh, and twelfth shows. We booked tickets months ago through Andrea&amp;#8217;s fan club connection and our seats were great. Aisle seats at all three shows, and I was able to sit for two of the shows and still see the stage. Even the view from at the third show, where we were center row floor, wasn&amp;#8217;t so bad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I noticed an interesting behavior (and by interesting, I mean HULK SMASH RAWR) by some of the men standing at the end of a row. When a woman would tap on their arm/shoulder to get past, it was used as an opportunity to stroke, touch, or otherwise make inappropriate physical contact in a confined space. It seemed to get worse as the night (and the drinking) continued. I didn&amp;#8217;t see anything obvious enough to intervene or call security but clearly someone&amp;#8217;s best judgement was not in play.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Monday started off with &lt;a href=&#34;2&#34;&gt;Bakka Phoenix&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;#8217;d been looking forward to that trip for ages. We spent at least an hour browsing and talking to the staff (it wasn&amp;#8217;t Chris, but I can&amp;#8217;t remember what her name was). I picked up quite a few books and only gossiped a little, I swear. Later that night, more Pearl Jam. By this time, I&amp;#8217;ve become fairly efficient at navigating both freeway and surface streets despite the grinding sound coming from the rear end of the car, which turn out to be the brake pads. Metal on metal never sounds pretty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tuesday was my day, to a tv taping for some professional wrestling (yes, I know it&amp;#8217;s scripted). I&amp;#8217;ve been to a few taping over the last twenty years but this one was special. One of the performers, Adam Copeland aka Edge, officially retired due to injury and had a nice send off in his home town. Love or hate wrestling, life is about doing what you love no matter what someone else tells you and this was a bittersweet moment to celebrate the career of someone who did that and now, due to circumstances beyond their control, must move on to the next chapter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had a free day Wednesday so we decided to go to the Toronto Zoo. I took nearly 500 picture, which will take me half a year to sort through, and walked a dozen miles or so it felt. Zoos are oddly pleasant, if tiring, experiences. Going mid-week during the school year meant there was very little crowd. It was peaceful. Someone would make a killing renting scooters or segways, though, especially with the hills. Since it was our first early night of the week, we stayed with Andrea&amp;#8217;s sister and enjoyed a relaxing evening.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our first real complication came on Thursday. We were heading to Hamilton, an hour away, for the last Pearl Jam show of our trip. As it turns out, Hamilton was hosting the Canadian Country Music Awards or some such. It ended up being cheaper, and not much further to drive, to stay the night in Niagara Falls, than to find somewhere in Hamilton or Toronto.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We spent a few hours in Niagara that afternoon, before commuting to Hamilton for the show that night. It&amp;#8217;s a total tourist trap, but still a lovely place to visit. We napped, then walked to the falls, which are spectacular.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Friday morning, we drove through wine country and met up with an old friend of mine that I&amp;#8217;ve known online for a decade but never met. After that, back to Toronto for a Blue Jays game, where the beat the Yankees (sorry Matthias) at the bottom of the 9th.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All in all, a pretty nice and mostly unplanned vacation. We had specific points in time set but otherwise we picked a direction and drove. It&amp;#8217;s a little risky not planning on where to sleep in advance but it worked out and we had nice bit of sightseeing for the detour that went with it. This was the best kind of trip I could have not planned.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>