<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Politics on Adam Israel</title>
    <link>http://adamisrael.com/tags/politics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Politics on Adam Israel</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://adamisrael.com/tags/politics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Dipping into Canadian Immigration/Politics</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2012/03/05/dipping-into-canadian-immigrationpolitics/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2012/03/05/dipping-into-canadian-immigrationpolitics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve been following the news regarding Canadian Immigration pretty closely &amp;#8212; not surprising considering my immigrant status. Last week &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.theglobeandmail.com/news/politics/ontario-goes-it-alone-on-immigration-says-ottawas-policy-hurts-province/article2357522/&#34;&gt;this article in the Globe and Mail&lt;/a&gt; talks about the percentage of immigrants who settle in Ontario vs. other provinces, which kind of bored me. What was interesting, though, were two issues in the continued fight against immigration fraud. When Andrea and I filled out our application, most of our time was spent collecting evidence to prove our relationship &amp;#8212; records of emails, phone calls, meetings between us, friends, and family, etc. It&amp;#8217;s extensive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Citizenship and Immigration Minister Jason Kenney &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cic.gc.ca/english/department/media/releases/2012/2012-03-02.asp&#34;&gt;announced&lt;/a&gt; Friday a government crackdown on marriage fraudsters: people who marry and enter Canada under spousal sponsorship, only to abandon their partners shortly thereafter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[..]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sponsored spouses will also be restricted from sponsoring others for five years – a change effective immediately. This is meant to put an end to the “revolving door” of serial marriage, sponsorship and divorce, Mr. Kenney said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basically, foreigners have been wooing Canadians into marriage in order to get permanent residence and absconding once they have it. Some unscrupulous folk, in turn, see this as an opportunity and have been marrying for profit, in exchange for legal status. Good that they&amp;#8217;re fixing this loophole. Surprised it&amp;#8217;s taken this long. Saddened that it&amp;#8217;s necessary in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last realization might have led to a discussion of &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alignment_(Dungeons_%26_Dragons)#Chaotic_Good&#34;&gt;Dungeons &amp;amp; Dragons character alignments&lt;/a&gt;. I am totally &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alignment_(Dungeons_%26_Dragons)#Lawful_Good&#34;&gt;Lawful Good&lt;/a&gt;, btw. If I stop and think about it, I know people can be dicks and do horrible, horrible things but on an individual level its hard for me to fathom this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;#8217;s another pending change to immigration law:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Starting this summer, those who are sponsored by their spouses to come to Canada will only be given temporary resident status for two years before they can gain permanent residency. If, during that period, the government discovers the marriage was one of convenience, the individual will be denied permanent residency. The new policy will include a provision to protect spousal abuse victims, who may be reluctant to end their marriages out of fear of jeopardizing their chances at gaining permanent resident status.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gazette.gc.ca/rp-pr/p1/2011/2011-03-26/html/notice-avis-eng.html#d114&#34;&gt;fine print&lt;/a&gt; clarifies that the temporary resident status would only applies to couples who&amp;#8217;ve been in a relationship less than two years when they file for sponsorship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
  This change wouldn&amp;#8217;t apply to us because we&amp;#8217;d been married for two and a half year when we filed, and as long as there are no complications with our application, I think we&amp;#8217;ll have our approval sometime around May. It does raise some questions, though.
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you&amp;#8217;re going applying for permanent residence in-country, you can&amp;#8217;t help but feel like a non-entity. I was able to get on [Ontario Reciprocal ][6][Drivers][6][ License]&lt;a href=&#34;eventually&#34;&gt;6&lt;/a&gt;, but I can&amp;#8217;t work so I can&amp;#8217;t pay taxes. Without paying taxes here, I get no benefits, like health insurance and I can&amp;#8217;t buy it, either. Supplemental insurance is for visitors with fixed times of entry and exit, and even if I could finagle that, they only a) cover emergency room visits and b) are cost-prohibitive when you&amp;#8217;re on a very tight budget.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My visitor visa doesn&amp;#8217;t cover me going to school, either, so that excludes any formal continued education; I&amp;#8217;m mostly self-taught, but it would be nice to take some classes. You know, maybe something like French to help me better integrate? There isn&amp;#8217;t a huge French population in our part of Ontario, but I have a maybe, possible job offer waiting for me when I do have my permanent residence in Ottawa, a stone&amp;#8217;s throw from Quebec and it would sure be nice to get more of a leg up on top of the other stuff I&amp;#8217;m teaching myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;#8217;s a lot of putting life on hold. We want to find a place of our own. Take some classes together. Have kids. It&amp;#8217;s next to impossible to do any of that, though, until I can do my part.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the time our application is approved, I&amp;#8217;ll have been living in Canada for almost 18 months. I may have to wait another two years before I can apply for citizenship and you can be damn sure I will be as soon as I&amp;#8217;m eligible. Under the new plan, an applicant may have to wait a year to get a temporary residence permit, two years to earn their permanent residence permit, and then another two years to be able to apply for citizenship &amp;#8212; effectively five years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You could argue that having a residence permit is not much different than having citizenship and I&amp;#8217;m not sure all of the differences but it includes the ability to vote, which is kind of a big deal, at least for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;#8217;t think there are any easy solutions. Fraud is fraud and I&amp;#8217;d like to flay the soles of anyone caught red-handed. I would like to see, though, a better solution for those of us who are trying to make a new life here. Make it easier to obtain a work permit &amp;#8212; and pay taxes &amp;#8212; while I&amp;#8217;m waiting. Let me volunteer, or study, and integrate better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[6]: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.drivetest.ca/en/license/exchangeReciprocal.aspx&#34;&gt;http://www.drivetest.ca/en/license/exchangeReciprocal.aspx&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why insider trading by members of Congress is worse than it sounds</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2011/12/01/why-insider-trading-by-members-of-congress-is-worse-than-it-sounds/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2011/12/01/why-insider-trading-by-members-of-congress-is-worse-than-it-sounds/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you had asked me if members of Congress were exempt from &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Insider_trading&#34;&gt;insider trading&lt;/a&gt; before today, I would have said yes, of course. I would have argued that, with the kinds of information that our congressmen and -woman are privy to, they especially should not be allowed to use non-public information to trade stock for financial gain. Knowing when to buy or sell a stock when a company is about to have a contract terminated, or is about to come under congressional investigation, for example, is privileged, sometimes even classified information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would have been wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I caught footage from a 60 Minutes reporter grilling Nancy Pelosi over her &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.csmonitor.com/USA/Latest-News-Wires/2011/1115/Did-Nancy-Pelosi-profit-from-Visa-stock-purchases&#34;&gt;questionable access to Visa&amp;#8217;s IPO&lt;/a&gt;. Joe Lieberman, who I have a mixed reaction to, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.marketwatch.com/story/bipartisan-criticism-of-insider-trading-laws-2011-12-01&#34;&gt;wants to pass an explicit ban on the act&lt;/a&gt;. There&amp;#8217;s more than a bunch of congresspeople using inside knowledge to their financial gain. There&amp;#8217;s a trickle-down effect, mentioned briefly in the footage I saw but something I can explain in better detail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the late 90&amp;#8217;s, I worked as a software consultant for an [Investor Relations][4] (IR) firm. I wrote what was essentially a big tracking system. These IR firms are able to get bank account numbers and balance information from major banks. This information is updated on a regular basis. They also have a steady stream of data on stock trades &amp;#8212; who&amp;#8217;s buying and who&amp;#8217;s selling, and how much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As part of their intelligence process, they are able to figure out the names of the people who own these bank accounts. This is meta-information, acquired any number of ways. There were very strict rules I had to follow about keeping this specially acquired information separate from the rest. It allows them to figure out if Company A has just bought a lot of stock or if Hedge Fund Manager X has just dumped half of his portfolio. They sell this data to their clients, investors and/or competitors of Company A or Hedge Fund Manager X.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, circle the wagon. Target your data scraping tools at the people who are exempt from insider trading, i.e., members of Congress. As they profit from non-public information, you glean the trades they are making and package that information up and sell it to your clients, who include hedge funds and other investors who can act on that second-hand knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I was writing this clunky software a decade ago, there&amp;#8217;s no doubt it&amp;#8217;s grown more sophisticated and the above kind of tracking was being routinely done then. I can only presume, backed up by the comments from the 60 Minute reporter, that not only is it still in operation, but now it&amp;#8217;s targeting those with an unfair advantage, spreading that advantage into the private sector. It&amp;#8217;s the worst kind of trickle-down effect, rot spreading from the core. My fingers are crossed that this ban passes quickly, with strong support from both sides of the idle, as a sign that this congress is serious about plugging the holes in the economy, even if it&amp;#8217;s themselves that are leaking the bathwater.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[4]: &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Investor_relations&#34;&gt;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Investor_relations&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An occupied mind can never be evicted</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2011/11/30/an-occupied-mind-can-never-be-evicted/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2011/11/30/an-occupied-mind-can-never-be-evicted/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I wrote this in the middle of the night as news of the raid on the #occulyla camp was breaking on twitter, half asleep but compelled to get some of my thoughts written down before I fell asleep:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The police are within their duties to do remove occupiers as occupiers are within theirs to commit acts of peaceful civil disobedience. Where law breaks down, in my mind, is when those in the upper echelons of authority usurp the power of the press by controlling who can report when, and by what media, which by extension raises the question of the accuracy and lens through which the truth is filtered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The people have a right to protest. The land owners have right to evict. Acts of civil disobedience are excellent demonstrations against a show of force. A heavily armed police force moving in to remove resolved protestors is inevitable. What really strikes me, though, and shames me as an American, is that those in power, presumably the mayor of Los Angeles and the LAPD chief of police authorized the communications blanket last night. Restricting the freedom of press, saying who is and isn&amp;#8217;t allowed to report, and by what medium, seems to me to be a direct violation of the freedom of press &amp;#8212; in spirit and intent if not letter of the law.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m sure someone will claim that this was an issue of safety; journalists risk their lives every day in warzones to report the truth. Are these politicians saying that downtown Los Angeles was more dangerous than the battlefields of the world where journalists have lived, reported, and yes, sometimes died? No. They were trying to prevent a potential media disaster should events get out of hand, to act without the accountability of independent observer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Funny, we&amp;#8217;ve damned foreign nations for doing the same to its people but we turn around and do it to our own. Too big to fail. That&amp;#8217;s what we thought about the banks, until we had to step in and bail them out. I kind of wonder if the next big thing to fail will be you, the 1%, and who will you turn to to bail you out?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>