<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Process on Adam Israel</title>
    <link>http://adamisrael.com/tags/process/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Process on Adam Israel</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© 2016 Adam Israel</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://adamisrael.com/tags/process/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Loneliness of the Long Distance Runner</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2012/02/27/the-loneliness-of-the-long-distance-runner/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2012/02/27/the-loneliness-of-the-long-distance-runner/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes, when I sit down and stare at a white blank page, my heart races. I fear the mistakes I’m about to make, at the same time I’m in awe of the creation about to spring forth the tip of my pen. I’ve done it before. I’ll do it again. I am not a fast writer, but I am a sprinter.
Sprinting is this — pen to paper, writing around 500 words/day until a story is done.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Storylife — A process of wrangling submissions</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2011/10/28/storylife-a-process-of-wrangling-submissions/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2011/10/28/storylife-a-process-of-wrangling-submissions/</guid>
      <description>I just mailed off my first story submission since 2009. Most of my submissions are electronic but, dating back to my first submissions circa 2007, I think I&amp;#8217;ve mailed off 5 or 6 stories or about 5% of my total submissions.
Some writers don&amp;#8217;t even own printers (John Scalzi comes to mind). Markets are evolving &amp;#8212; not quite matching pace, but at least trailing the pack. Analog and Asimov both use the electronic submissions system developed by Neil Clarke.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Less talk, more word count</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2011/08/10/less-talk-more-word-count/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2011/08/10/less-talk-more-word-count/</guid>
      <description>I need to post a full recap of my Clarion write-a-thon efforts and a thank you to the donors. In the meantime, a little bit about accountability.
I&amp;#8217;ve been bad about writing consistently lately (blogging seems to be a chronic problem). I&amp;#8217;d write sporadically, finishing stories here and there, revising and evening submitting a few of them with some success. Mostly, though, I&amp;#8217;ve been draft stories and that&amp;#8217;s it. I still have some sitting in my moleskines waiting to be typed up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hard days</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2010/12/28/hard-days/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2010/12/28/hard-days/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#8217;ve been slogging away, the last few weeks, trying to string together words that make sense. It&amp;#8217;s been rough. A nameless ennui that I blame on not having a place to personalize yet. That&amp;#8217;s something Andrea and I will be working towards in the new year. Meanwhile, life goes on and the writing must continue so I had to find a way. Deadlines usually help, but I&amp;#8217;ve been staring two or three, maybe four, up the ugly side so much lately that I&amp;#8217;m beginning to go cross-eyed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 3: Practice Stories</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2010/01/22/week-3-practice-stories/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2010/01/22/week-3-practice-stories/</guid>
      <description>Another kind of successful week &amp;#8212; 3,237 new words, bringing the years total to 10,404.
I&amp;#8217;m still struggling with revisions. I got critiques back on two of my stories this week. The crits were brutally honest, the way I like them, and resonated with things I&amp;#8217;d been trying to figure out myself. One thing I&amp;#8217;m uncovering is that I don&amp;#8217;t read critically enough. Having a third party point out an issue is great.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The best laid intentions, felled by a lack of 3×5″ notecards</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2010/01/11/the-best-laid-intentions-felled-by-a-lack-of-3x5-notecards/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2010/01/11/the-best-laid-intentions-felled-by-a-lack-of-3x5-notecards/</guid>
      <description>When I kicked off the year writing 250 new words a day, I had a plan. A story. An outline, man. I finished that story yesterday. Plus an impromptu flash fiction piece. Today? I have no plan.
I have a theme (thank you, upcoming anthology). I have the kernel of a plot and main character. Tonight, I write without my safety net. I&amp;#8217;m curious to see what this change in process produces.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Achievements and goals</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2010/01/03/achievements-and-goals/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2010/01/03/achievements-and-goals/</guid>
      <description>On the heels of yesterdays post about Booklife and my personal mission statement, I have added My Booklife to the sidebar. From here, I have posted and will keep updated my public weekly, monthly, 1 year and 5 year goals. I&amp;#8217;ve also included my list of career achievements.
I&amp;#8217;m feeling pretty good about how things are shaping. I&amp;#8217;m starting the year with a more or less clean slate; new domain, new blog, and new goals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In the beginning, there was the Mission Statement</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2010/01/03/in-the-beginning-there-was-the-mission-statement/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2010/01/03/in-the-beginning-there-was-the-mission-statement/</guid>
      <description>I am horrible with deadlines. In high school I was forced to take a special class on time management because I never turned anything in on time. It&amp;#8217;s one of those things that I struggle with on a daily basis. Occasionally I discover something useful that helps, like Things, that help me keep track of the things I need to be doing. The most recent one was Jeff VanderMeer&amp;#8216;s Booklife.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>