<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Submission on Adam Israel</title>
    <link>http://dev.adamisrael.com/tags/submission/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Submission on Adam Israel</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://dev.adamisrael.com/tags/submission/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Storylife — A process of wrangling submissions</title>
      <link>http://dev.adamisrael.com/blog/2011/10/28/storylife-a-process-of-wrangling-submissions/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://dev.adamisrael.com/blog/2011/10/28/storylife-a-process-of-wrangling-submissions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I just mailed off my first story submission since 2009. Most of my submissions are electronic but, dating back to my first submissions circa 2007, I think I&amp;#8217;ve mailed off 5 or 6 stories or about 5% of my total submissions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some writers don&amp;#8217;t even own printers (&lt;a href=&#34;1&#34;&gt;John Scalzi&lt;/a&gt; comes to mind). Markets are evolving &amp;#8212; not quite matching pace, but at least trailing the pack. Analog and Asimov both use the electronic submissions system developed by Neil Clarke. I&amp;#8217;ve always had a printer &amp;#8212; usually one, a trusty laser dedicated to printing manuscripts &amp;#8212; because I like marking up hard copy but I&amp;#8217;m economical when it comes to submissions and response time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every story has a life. Literally, in my case. Recently, I built a spreadsheet called Storylife where every story has a sheet of its own. In it, I track the where the story is gone and where the story is going next. Every new sheet is seeded with a list of pro markets that I&amp;#8217;ve created based on an analysis of my own submission records, SFWA qualifying markets, and my own reading. It&amp;#8217;s a who&amp;#8217;s who of where I&amp;#8217;d like to be published. That initial list gets culled of markets that don&amp;#8217;t fit the story and sorted by best fit and response time. Non-pro markets get added to that list as I near the end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of the markets take electronic subs, but there are a few that don&amp;#8217;t. Fantasy &amp;amp; Science Fiction. Interzone. Black Static. Black Gate. Lady Churchill&amp;#8217;s Rosebud Wristlet. With Storylife, I&amp;#8217;m making myself submit to those markets even though it&amp;#8217;s a little less convenient than usual. F&amp;amp;SF is the outlier in terms of response time; they&amp;#8217;re faster than most of their electronic counterparts. With the rest, factoring in transit time, you&amp;#8217;re looking at maybe two or three months, if you&amp;#8217;re lucky.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me, the decision to submit by mail comes down to measuring the odds, which involves a little bit of rejectomancy. I don&amp;#8217;t submit a story until I&amp;#8217;m reasonably confident in it and the first few markets I send it out to are electronic with a quick turnaround time. If I get straight up form rejections in the average response time, I might take another look to see what might be keeping me in the slush pile before sending it back out. If I get a string of &amp;#8220;close, but not quite&amp;#8221; rejections then I feel as reasonably sure as any doubting writer can that the story just needs to find the right editor and I&amp;#8217;ll make the investment to submit by mail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are financial logistics involved in deciding to submit by mail. Mailing from Canada to the US cost me $8.57 today, just in postage. It would have been cheaper if I&amp;#8217;d had US postage &amp;#8212; $0.88 for two stamps vs. $4.50 for an International Relay Coupon &amp;#8212; but getting stamps takes a little maneuvering. Add in the cost of the 9&amp;#215;12 and business size envelope, printing, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaking of story life, I also need to make a decision about shelf life. I&amp;#8217;m considering following Ferrett&amp;#8217;s lead where he called a mulligan on his pre-Clarion writing life. I still have some of those stories in circulation and while they&amp;#8217;re good stories, I am running out of places to send them despite mostly positive feedback. Maybe harvest the ideas in future stories, because when you compare that to what I&amp;#8217;ve written since Clarion, nine first drafts, five polished stories sent out on submission and three sold (60%), all on their first date, that tells me I should be expending my energy on the new things. I have a feeling that there&amp;#8217;s a diminishing point of return on old stories, where they might do more harm than good in the eyes of an editor. I&amp;#8217;m just not sure where to draw that line.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>