<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Adam Israel</title>
    <link>http://adamisrael.com/tags/administration/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Adam Israel</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© 2016 Adam Israel</copyright>
    <atom:link href="http://adamisrael.com/tags/administration/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>You can take the grey out of his beard, but Unix stays in a man’s blood.</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2012/02/26/you-can-take-the-grey-out-of-his-beard-but-unix-stays-in-a-mans-blood/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2012/02/26/you-can-take-the-grey-out-of-his-beard-but-unix-stays-in-a-mans-blood/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I sat down this morning, meaning to write a blog post about focus and patience, with OCD tendencies. It would have been my first substantial post since the beginning of the month, but when I logged in to WordPress I found my site unresponsive. Temperamental, even. Other sites I host on the same server, but different accounts, were fine. I was about to blame my half-full cup of coffee when Google interceded and warned me that my site was being suspicious as all fuck. Fuck.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, instead of talking about how I&amp;#8217;ve been making progress on most of the things and what else I&amp;#8217;ve been doing, I lost the morning to the Unix mines. My old friends &lt;em&gt;sed&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;grep&lt;/em&gt; were happy to see me as we strolled down the old familiar path of forensic analysis and recovery (or, as much as can be done with limited privileges). I don&amp;#8217;t know if my password was compromised or not, but it&amp;#8217;s been changed. One of my WordPress plugins was manually installed and severely out-of-date. It had known XSS vulnerabilities and some of the infected files originated in its folder. It has appropriately been nuked from orbit and installed to current.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dreamhost&amp;#8217;s been notified, in case this was part of a larger attack on the machine itself. For the time being, all is as it was, or should be at any rate (I&amp;#8217;ll be keeping a close watch for any recurrences).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>