<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Progress on Adam Israel</title>
    <link>http://adamisrael.com/tags/progress/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Progress on Adam Israel</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© 2016 Adam Israel</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://adamisrael.com/tags/progress/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Clarion Write-a-thon: Day 1</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2012/06/25/clarion-write-a-thon-day-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2012/06/25/clarion-write-a-thon-day-1/</guid>
      <description>The Clarion Write-a-thon began yesterday. I got some decent writing time in, despite a late start to the day and having to confront a would-be pervert attempting to flash his private bits at my favorite writing spot. I expect the first several days of writing to go slow as I revise the first chapter of the novel, trying to set the right tone and pace. The 25k words I wrote during last year&amp;#8217;s Nanowrimo are, I realize, mostly outline but do span the length of the novel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Draft Zero</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2011/04/28/draft-zero/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2011/04/28/draft-zero/</guid>
      <description>I didn&amp;#8217;t reach my original estimate of 5,000 words but this draft is done.
Project: Motown Blues (tentative)
New words written: 811
Reason for stopping: End of story
No matter how much I outline and plan, these stories tend to take on a life of their own once I get started. The voice fluctuates until it finds its pace and pitch. Tangents emerge, sidetrack, and must be wrestled into submission. I like what this is shaping up to be.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What do you mean, fifteen minutes *each*?</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2011/04/24/what-do-you-mean-fifteen-minutes-each/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2011/04/24/what-do-you-mean-fifteen-minutes-each/</guid>
      <description>I missed a couple days of writing last week, which included a day spent trying to get fingerprints taken for immigration and ended up with an appointment one week out. Who knew that fingerprint technology had advanced beyond ink pads? One set for Ontario, and a set each for the FBI and State of Illinois to request my records. The saga, she continues.
My Illinois driving records have been received by Mom and will soon be on their way here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Armed with a palm full of spit and vigor</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2010/10/10/armed-with-a-palm-full-of-spit-and-vigor/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2010/10/10/armed-with-a-palm-full-of-spit-and-vigor/</guid>
      <description>Project: Sex/magic story, now with more poly love, a plump dominatrix, a Chicago swinger&amp;#8217;s club, and one pissed off magician.
New words written: 1,210
Reason for stopping: End of scene
One more scene left before I can make draft, so I&amp;#8217;m on target to wrap this up by the end of the weekend. Today&amp;#8217;s been upside down thanks to insomnia but I don&amp;#8217;t mind the word count. It&amp;#8217;ll be nice to get back to regular sleep schedule, though.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 4 coughs up a lung</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2010/02/02/week-4-coughs-up-a-lung/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2010/02/02/week-4-coughs-up-a-lung/</guid>
      <description>Week 4 ended on a bit of a downer. I&amp;#8217;d been doing well, writing a bit each day but the streak came to an end. I drafted two short stories and three flash fiction. I started a fourth but it wasn&amp;#8217;t ready to be told. Instead of forcing it, I skipped a day.
Somewhere along the way, I caught a nice little cold/flu, was diagnosed with some vitamin deficiencies (insert scurvy joke here, matey) and started a few new prescribed drugs.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>