<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Novel on Adam Israel</title>
    <link>http://adamisrael.com/tags/novel/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Novel on Adam Israel</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://adamisrael.com/tags/novel/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Brainjuice</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2011/08/23/brainjuice/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2011/08/23/brainjuice/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Can you believe I managed to blog three whole days in a row &lt;del&gt;last week&lt;/del&gt; two weeks ago? Yeah.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apparently I&amp;#8217;m running in low power mode right now. New meds, a heavy work schedule, and two short story deadlines. Oh, and I&amp;#8217;m outlining NOVEL.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve got around twenty unfinished short stories in inventory. My plan is to revise a short story every month or so while drafting novel. I don&amp;#8217;t plan to draft any new short stories until I&amp;#8217;ve finished this novel draft, unless something new like &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.shanghai-steam.com/&#34;&gt;Shanghai Steam&lt;/a&gt; comes along or a specific invite comes along that catches my interest. Shiny is shiny, after all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How long will this take? Fuck if I know. I&amp;#8217;ve never finished a novel before. When I&amp;#8217;m drafting short stories I average 500 words/day with relative ease. I suspect I can double that but I&amp;#8217;ll be conservative and give myself until my birthday next summer &amp;#8212; almost exactly 11 months away. If I don&amp;#8217;t have a complete draft by then, something is seriously wrong and the [Inkpunks][2] are formally invited to visit a beatdown on my ass.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Expect regular status updates complete with word widget and maybe even tiny extracts of out of context words that I&amp;#8217;m not totally horrified by.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[2]: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.inkpunks.com/&#34;&gt;http://www.inkpunks.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>