<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Signal Boost on Adam Israel</title>
    <link>http://adamisrael.com/tags/signal-boost/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Signal Boost on Adam Israel</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© 2016 Adam Israel</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://adamisrael.com/tags/signal-boost/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Free fiction in support of making Crossed Genres a pro-paying magazine</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2012/06/15/free-fiction-in-support-of-making-crossed-genres-a-pro-paying-magazine/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2012/06/15/free-fiction-in-support-of-making-crossed-genres-a-pro-paying-magazine/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#8217;ve been a fan of Crossed Genres for a long time &amp;#8212; just shy of three years, which is forever in Internet time. As a small press, they&amp;#8217;ve done a massive amount of good work publishing hundreds of authors (including myself) but Bart and Kay, proprietors, fell on hard times and were forced to turn to Kickstarter to keep CG alive. And made their goal of $4,000 in just 22 hours.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Calls for Submissions</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2012/03/30/calls-for-submissions/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2012/03/30/calls-for-submissions/</guid>
      <description>Urban Green Man: An Archetype of Renewal, edited by Adria Laycraft &amp;amp; Janice Blaine, and to be published by EDGE Science Fiction &amp;amp; Fantasy.
 The Green Man has haunted our churches and buildings and global subconscious for countless generations, becoming just another forgotten mythology that is relegated to garden statuary and English pub signs.
No longer. Witness as the Green Man rises to capture our imagination in this anthology of original new fiction, the Urban Green Man.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wither the sickness</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2012/01/04/wither-the-sickness/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2012/01/04/wither-the-sickness/</guid>
      <description>Life with chronic health conditions and no health insurance is interesting.
Celiac disease is pretty much a condition of maintenance. There’s no cure and the only preventative measure is avoiding eating or drinking gluten (wheat, barley, rye, and oats). Gluten is everywhere. Beer and bread are bad but I’ve found it in foods I would never have suspected, like tomato soup, sausage and lunch meats, and many, many sauces. Flour is a cheap filler and thickener so it’s commonly used, which makes the life of a celiac a royal bitch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crimson Pact 2 Unleashed</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2011/09/09/crimson-pact-2-unleashed/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2011/09/09/crimson-pact-2-unleashed/</guid>
      <description>The Crimson Pact 2, which includes my flash fiction &amp;#8220;History of the Flesh&amp;#8220;, is now available from Amazon.com, Barnes &amp;amp; Noble, and probably other places that sell ebooks. Five bucks for twenty-eight stories and over 500 pages worth of fiction is a steal. There&amp;#8217;s even a Youtube channel filled with book trailers if you need convincing.
This little story is set in the same world as the novel I&amp;#8217;m working and I&amp;#8217;m very happy to see it in print, so to speak.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Signal boost: Broken Time Blues</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2011/08/12/signal-boost-broken-time-blues/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2011/08/12/signal-boost-broken-time-blues/</guid>
      <description>Broken Time Blues: Fantastic Tales in the Roaring &amp;#8217;20s, or as some of you folks may remember it from it&amp;#8217;s twitter hashtag, #20spec, is now available for sale on Amazon. From the publisher&amp;#8217;s description:
 No blind tigers or poisonous coffin varnish here! Broken Time Blues is a classy establishment, see? The cat&amp;#8217;s meow. So toss on your glad rags and get a wiggle on! Make sure no one&amp;#8217;s following you, then take a right down the alley and knock three times on the brown door.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Signal Boost: Finnish Science Fiction/Fantasy</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2011/05/13/signal-boost-finnish-science-fictionfantasy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2011/05/13/signal-boost-finnish-science-fictionfantasy/</guid>
      <description>Diversity is something often on my mind. I&amp;#8217;ve been thrilled to see translated Science Fiction becoming available in bookstores recently. It&amp;#8217;s easy to forget that we &amp;#8212; the white, english speakers of the world &amp;#8212; aren&amp;#8217;t the only ones with fantastic imaginations.
My Clarion instructors Jeff and Ann VanderMeer have an almost encyclopedia-like knowledge of foreign fiction. They recently spent some time in Finland, meeting with many of the Finnish SF/F community.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extinct Doesn’t Mean Forever</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2011/04/06/extinct-doesnt-mean-forever/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2011/04/06/extinct-doesnt-mean-forever/</guid>
      <description>&amp;nbsp;

I realize that I neglected to mention that the anthology Extinct Doesn&amp;#8217;t Mean Forever, containing my story Indigo&amp;#8217;s Gambit, is now available on Amazon.
 Three, two, one, bang — the Drifting Star skipped on the wave of a collapsing micro-sun, soaring through the void between the stars. The astronautical library contained surveys and charts on hundreds of thousands of star systems within the alliance of civilized worlds the Fringe called Sing Xu.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Friday is for Friends who are Awesome</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2010/10/01/friday-is-for-friends-who-are-awesome/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2010/10/01/friday-is-for-friends-who-are-awesome/</guid>
      <description>Happy fifth birthday to Hadley Rille Books, who published my first in print story. They publish many fine books and anthologies, so please consider supporting this great small press.
Today is release day for Rigor Amortis, edited by Jaym Gates and Erika Holt, and containing stories by R. Schuyler Devin, Kaolin Imago Fire, Kay T. Holt, John Nakamura Remy, Andrew Penn Romine, Wendy N. Wagner, and many others.
This first of October 2010 also marks the launch of Inkpunks, a group blog by some of the brightest up and coming writers and editors in speculative fiction.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>