<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Signal Boost on Adam Israel</title>
    <link>http://adamisrael.com/tags/signal-boost/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Signal Boost on Adam Israel</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© 2016 Adam Israel</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://adamisrael.com/tags/signal-boost/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Free fiction in support of making Crossed Genres a pro-paying magazine</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2012/06/15/free-fiction-in-support-of-making-crossed-genres-a-pro-paying-magazine/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2012/06/15/free-fiction-in-support-of-making-crossed-genres-a-pro-paying-magazine/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve been a fan of Crossed Genres for a long time &amp;#8212; just shy of three years, which is &lt;em&gt;forever&lt;/em&gt; in Internet time. As a small press, they&amp;#8217;ve done a massive amount of good work publishing hundreds of authors (including myself) but Bart and Kay, proprietors, fell on hard times and were forced to turn to Kickstarter to keep CG alive. And made their goal of $4,000 in just 22 hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That says something, not just about the power of Kickstarter but about the reputation of Crossed Genres, and Bart and Kay. These are people worth supporting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With a week to go, they are trying to reach a second stretch goal of $14,000 (they are over $8,600 as I write this). If they reach this, not only will Crossed Genres the magazine be relaunched but it will become a professionally-paying venue and that is a significant thing. Bart and Kay already ran CG as such, but they will be able to compensate authors equally well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can already find plenty of examples of their work in the &lt;a href=&#34;1&#34;&gt;Cross Genre archives&lt;/a&gt;. In addition, I&amp;#8217;ve posted my story &amp;#8220;&lt;a href=&#34;2&#34;&gt;Dog Days&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#8220;, originally published in the April 2011 issue, online as a show of support. Go kick in a few bucks to show &amp;#8217;em that you care.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Calls for Submissions</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2012/03/30/calls-for-submissions/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2012/03/30/calls-for-submissions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;1&#34;&gt;Urban Green Man: An Archetype of Renewal&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, edited by Adria Laycraft &amp;amp; Janice Blaine, and to be published by &lt;a href=&#34;2&#34;&gt;EDGE Science Fiction &amp;amp; Fantasy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Green Man has haunted our churches and buildings and global subconscious for countless generations, becoming just another forgotten mythology that is relegated to garden statuary and English pub signs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No longer. Witness as the Green Man rises to capture our imagination in this anthology of original new fiction, the Urban Green Man.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m pretty excited by this anthology. I&amp;#8217;m a huge fan of the Green Man mythos; I&amp;#8217;m only sad that this own&amp;#8217;t be my chance to rewrite my Green Man-on-a-generation-ship story. Still, I&amp;#8217;m sure I will come up with something that keeps me awake at night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;3&#34;&gt;Demeter’s Spicebox&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; is opening for their third issue. There are so many things that I love about their guidelines. They are inclusive, seeking diversity and setting out to explore lesser-known fairy tales from underutilized regions of the world, and that those stories must be done with some attempt at authenticity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Third Issue of _Demeter’s Spicebox_ will continue the journey for the items from Mari Ness’s and Shveta Thakrar’s stories, but will also incorporate elements from &lt;a href=&#34;4&#34;&gt;Joshua Gage&lt;/a&gt;’s and &lt;a href=&#34;5&#34;&gt;Mae Empson&lt;/a&gt;’s stories from Issue Two. We invite brave writers who are willing to join this storytelling experiment and dialogue between tales. We would also like to encourage writers from diverse backgrounds to submit; _Demeter’s Spicebox_ is and always will remain a diversity-​​friendly venue. Our goal is to highlight voices that are strong, unique and brave. We pay attention to the strength of the story and to the strength of your voice as a writer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are additional requirements for issue three (see the guidelines for the full list) in order to connect these stories with the previously published ones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Crossed Genres announced &lt;a href=&#34;6&#34;&gt;Winter Well&lt;/a&gt;: an upcoming anthology of novellas featuring older women.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’re looking for speculative stories featuring women of advancing age (late middle age and older). They’re smart, they’re tough, and they have wills of their own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They may be warriors, politicians, adventurers, etc. Even if they are also wives, mothers, wise women or healers, those archetypes must not be their defining characteristics. Their motivations, their driving force, must be their own. Whatever was in their past, they’re not interested in being in the background now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We want stories about women breaking free of suppression; we also want stories of women who’ve been empowered all their lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CG does awesome work. They&amp;#8217;ve published me before, and I support them whenever I can.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wither the sickness</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2012/01/04/wither-the-sickness/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2012/01/04/wither-the-sickness/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Life with chronic health conditions and no health insurance is interesting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;1&#34;&gt;Celiac&lt;/a&gt; disease is pretty much a condition of maintenance. There’s no cure and the only preventative measure is avoiding eating or drinking gluten (wheat, barley, rye, and oats). Gluten is everywhere. Beer and bread are bad but I’ve found it in foods I would never have suspected, like tomato soup, sausage and lunch meats, and many, many sauces. Flour is a cheap filler and thickener so it’s commonly used, which makes the life of a celiac a royal bitch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was diagnosed with fibromyalgia first, and celiac disease a few months apart, in early 2010. Both came on the heels of a lot of effort on my part to document and self-diagnose, to some degree, my own condition. One of my knees was so inflamed that I limped noticeably for months and at the apex I had to crawl up stairs on hands and knees because of the pain. My rheumatologist diagnosed that as one of the symptoms of my fibromyalgia and that was that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had good doctors then, that supported my efforts to self-diagnose, within reason. I did my own testing with diet changes, for example, that led to discovering my sensitivity to wheat, and they ran medical tests to verify and confirm. &lt;a href=&#34;2&#34;&gt;Science. It works, bitches.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been gluten-free, aside from the random and mostly rare accidental glutening, for about eighteen months. The first six months or so I felt great; my knee inflammation disappeared completely and many of the other symptoms associated with fibromyalgia had eased up as well. That general sense of well-being began tapering off, though. I was as strict, if not more so, with my diet, but nothing seemed to reverse that trend. Complicating matters were my symptoms of fibromyalgia, which worsened.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My sleeping pattern became erratic, when I could sleep at all. Lethargy was my lonely friend and I constantly worked through a teeth-gnashing mental fog. On two occasions, minimal exercise caused such a crash that I slept for days. We worried about my health, my ability to function, to work. I’d spent my late nights reading through journal articles, medical studies and message forums about fibromyalgia and Celiac symptoms and treatments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A month or so ago, one of my online friends whose been through some medical issues blogged and, in the comments said something about not ruling in fibromyalgia without further testing, especially with celiac. My knee jerk reaction was to get upset (sorry D. &amp;lt;3) but it got me thinking. I realized she was right, especially given the proclivity of doctors, despite their best intentions, to misdiagnose fibro in the presence of celiac.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I woke from sleep one night and in a moment of clarity remembered that, a few months prior to my celiac diagnosis, I nearly had scurvy and other assorted vitamin deficiency-related issues. The doctor put me on a daily regiment of vitamins that, a few months later, put my levels back to normal. When we realized I was celiac, I (or we) thought that must be the cause and &lt;em&gt;I stopped taking the vitamins&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The kicker about celiac: it damages the lining of your small intestine, sometimes permanently, but it can take years for it to fully recover once you&amp;#8217;re gluten-free. This prevents the absorption of nutrients from the foods you eat. Essentially, I was malnourished even though I’d been eating a healthy, gluten-free diet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whoops.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m three weeks back on my vitamins (for the curious: 500mg vitamin C twice/day, 1,000 IU vitamin D twice/day, 50mg zinc once/day) and I feel remarkably different. The mental fog has cleared. I’m back on a regular, consistent sleep schedule and my energy levels are starting to return.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’ll be summer before all the paperwork is done and I can see a doctor regularly again and get regular check-ups. That sucks, more than a little, but this close call reminded me of something I’m a fan of: body hacking. Safely, of course, but we are essentially a biological computer in a wetware exosuit. A biomech, if you will.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Done smartly — scientifically — who knows what you’ll discover. I’ve been doing it out of necessity, in a small way. Humanity has been finding ways to do it since forever (care for a cup of coffee?). Also worth mentioning, &lt;a href=&#34;3&#34;&gt;The Future Fire&lt;/a&gt; just announced a call for submissions for their thematically-related anthology, &lt;a href=&#34;4&#34;&gt;Outlaw Bodies&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crimson Pact 2 Unleashed</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2011/09/09/crimson-pact-2-unleashed/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2011/09/09/crimson-pact-2-unleashed/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;1&#34;&gt;Crimson Pact&lt;/a&gt; 2, which includes my flash fiction &amp;#8220;&lt;a href=&#34;2&#34;&gt;History of the Flesh&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#8220;, is now available from &lt;a href=&#34;3&#34;&gt;Amazon.com&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;4&#34;&gt;Barnes &amp;amp; Noble&lt;/a&gt;, and probably other places that sell ebooks. Five bucks for twenty-eight stories and over 500 pages worth of fiction is a steal. There&amp;#8217;s even a &lt;a href=&#34;5&#34;&gt;Youtube channel&lt;/a&gt; filled with book trailers if you need convincing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This little story is set in the same world as the novel I&amp;#8217;m working and I&amp;#8217;m very happy to see it in print, so to speak. Also,if you enjoy it, you&amp;#8217;ll have a very small taste for what I&amp;#8217;ll working on for the next year or more of my life.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Signal boost: Broken Time Blues</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2011/08/12/signal-boost-broken-time-blues/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2011/08/12/signal-boost-broken-time-blues/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Broken Time Blues: Fantastic Tales in the Roaring &amp;#8217;20s, or as some of you folks may remember it from it&amp;#8217;s twitter hashtag, #20spec, is now available &lt;a href=&#34;1&#34;&gt;for sale on Amazon&lt;/a&gt;. From the publisher&amp;#8217;s description:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No blind tigers or poisonous coffin varnish here! Broken Time Blues is a classy establishment, see? The cat&amp;#8217;s meow. So toss on your glad rags and get a wiggle on! Make sure no one&amp;#8217;s following you, then take a right down the alley and knock three times on the brown door. There won&amp;#8217;t be a sign. Code word&amp;#8217;s &amp;#8220;applesauce.&amp;#8221; It&amp;#8217;s okay to get your friends hip to the jive, but hush—speakeasy. Bulls and Mrs. Grundys are always listening. Inside you&amp;#8217;ll be entertained by twelve hotsy-totsy tales. An alien burlesque dancer; a monstrous, people eating goddess, a buried city of automatons; Picasso as a villainous, flesh-sculpting wizard; ; a fae detective; a bootlegging chicken; and more. Broken Time Blues: the 1920s as you&amp;#8217;ve never seen them before. You&amp;#8217;ll go goofy for it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This anthology is going to be amazing. From the braaaaains that brought you zombie erotica via &lt;a href=&#34;2&#34;&gt;Rigor Amortis&lt;/a&gt;, this features speculative stories set in the roaring 20&amp;#8217;s that are sure to blow away any preconceptions you had of the prohibition era. The  table of contents nothing short of brilliant:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: left; padding-left: 30px;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;The Sharing&lt;/em&gt; by James Sutter&lt;br /&gt; &lt;em&gt;Chickadee&lt;/em&gt; by Frank Ard&lt;br /&gt; &lt;em&gt;Semele’s Daughter&lt;/em&gt; by John Dewey Nakamura Remy&lt;br /&gt; &lt;em&gt;The Automatic City&lt;/em&gt; By Sarah Hendrix&lt;br /&gt; &lt;em&gt;Button Up Your Overcoat&lt;/em&gt; by Barbara Krasnoff&lt;br /&gt; &lt;em&gt;Nor the Moonlight&lt;/em&gt; by Andrew Romine&lt;br /&gt; &lt;em&gt;Jack and the Wise Birds&lt;/em&gt; by Lucia Starkey&lt;br /&gt; &lt;em&gt;Madonna and Child, In Jade&lt;/em&gt; by Amanda C. Davis&lt;br /&gt; &lt;em&gt;Der Graue Engel&lt;/em&gt; by Jack Graham&lt;br /&gt; &lt;em&gt;The Purloined Ledger&lt;/em&gt; by Ari Marmell&lt;br /&gt; &lt;em&gt;Fight Night&lt;/em&gt; by Ryan McFadden&lt;br /&gt; &lt;em&gt;A Drink for Teddy Ford&lt;/em&gt; by Robert Jackson Bennett
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: left; padding-left: 30px;&#34;&gt;
  Art by Galen Smith and Evan Jensen
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: left; padding-left: 30px;&#34;&gt;
  Edited by Jaym Gates and Erika Holt
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;#8217;re going to WorldCon, be sure to stop by the launch party and shake a leg. Saturday, August 20th at 2pm. There will be readings by many of the author&amp;#8217;s and who knows, maybe even some prohibited spirits, if you know the right people.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Signal Boost: Finnish Science Fiction/Fantasy</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2011/05/13/signal-boost-finnish-science-fictionfantasy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2011/05/13/signal-boost-finnish-science-fictionfantasy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Diversity is something often on my mind. I&amp;#8217;ve been thrilled to see translated Science Fiction becoming available in bookstores recently. It&amp;#8217;s easy to forget that we &amp;#8212; the white, english speakers of the world &amp;#8212; aren&amp;#8217;t the only ones with fantastic imaginations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My Clarion instructors Jeff and Ann VanderMeer have an almost encyclopedia-like knowledge of foreign fiction. They recently spent some time in Finland, meeting with many of the Finnish SF/F community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;1&#34;&gt;Finnish Science Fiction and Fantasy: Johanna Sinisalo, Hannu Rajaniemi, and Moomins&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;2&#34;&gt;Finnish SF and Fantasy: An Established Community, a Surge of Talent&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;3&#34;&gt;Finnish Weird–and Finnish SF/F Links Round-Up&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It grows ever obvious that we are becoming a global community. I sincerely hope that we see more and more international fiction translated for a wider audience (that, or the discovery of the &lt;a href=&#34;4&#34;&gt;babel fish&lt;/a&gt;) so that everyone can enjoy these talented authors.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extinct Doesn’t Mean Forever</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2011/04/06/extinct-doesnt-mean-forever/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2011/04/06/extinct-doesnt-mean-forever/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;1&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-396 alignright&#34; title=&#34;Exinct-cover&#34; src=&#34;http://www.adamisrael.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/04/Exinct-cover-300x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; srcset=&#34;//www.adamisrael.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/04/Exinct-cover-150x150.jpg 150w, //www.adamisrael.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/04/Exinct-cover-300x300.jpg 300w, //www.adamisrael.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/04/Exinct-cover.jpg 500w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I realize that I neglected to mention that the anthology &lt;a href=&#34;2&#34;&gt;Extinct Doesn&amp;#8217;t Mean Forever&lt;/a&gt;, containing my story Indigo&amp;#8217;s Gambit, is now available on Amazon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Three, two, one, bang — the &lt;em&gt;Drifting Star&lt;/em&gt; skipped on the wave of a collapsing micro-sun, soaring through the void between the stars. The astronautical library contained surveys and charts on hundreds of thousands of star systems within the alliance of civilized worlds the Fringe called Sing Xu. This would be the thirty-eighth Indigo had visited since his journey toward the core planets began. So far none contained a world suitable to revive the Oshen race.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m happy that this story found a home. I wrote it several years ago for a different anthology but didn&amp;#8217;t get accepted. Themed anthologies can be tricky beasts &amp;#8212; the market is flooded with stories that didn&amp;#8217;t make the cut. Patience paid off, though, and this anthology came along.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Friday is for Friends who are Awesome</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2010/10/01/friday-is-for-friends-who-are-awesome/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2010/10/01/friday-is-for-friends-who-are-awesome/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Happy fifth birthday to &lt;a href=&#34;1&#34;&gt;Hadley Rille Books&lt;/a&gt;, who published my first &lt;a href=&#34;2&#34;&gt;in print&lt;/a&gt; story. They publish many fine books and anthologies, so please consider supporting this great small press.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today is release day for &lt;a href=&#34;3&#34;&gt;Rigor Amortis&lt;/a&gt;, edited by &lt;a href=&#34;4&#34;&gt;Jaym Gates&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;5&#34;&gt;Erika Holt&lt;/a&gt;, and containing stories by &lt;a href=&#34;6&#34;&gt;R. Schuyler Devin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;7&#34;&gt;Kaolin Imago Fire&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;8&#34;&gt;Kay T. Holt&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;9&#34;&gt;John Nakamura Remy&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;10&#34;&gt;Andrew Penn Romine&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;11&#34;&gt;Wendy N. Wagner&lt;/a&gt;, and many others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This first of October 2010 also marks the launch of &lt;a href=&#34;12&#34;&gt;Inkpunks&lt;/a&gt;, a group blog by some of the brightest up and coming writers and editors in speculative fiction. Every Tuesday and Friday there will be a post related to the writing. Disclaimer: I am one of the contributors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Congratulations to my friend &lt;a href=&#34;13&#34;&gt;John&lt;/a&gt;, who just completed &lt;a href=&#34;14&#34;&gt;30 days as a Vegan&lt;/a&gt;. Changing diet and lifestyle is harder than you might expect. Kudos to him for seeing it through. I&amp;#8217;m looking forward to his final thoughts on the experiment.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>