<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Conventions on Adam Israel</title>
    <link>http://adamisrael.com/tags/conventions/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Conventions on Adam Israel</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://adamisrael.com/tags/conventions/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Con report: World Fantasy 2012</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2012/11/05/con-report-world-fantasy-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2012/11/05/con-report-world-fantasy-2012/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Andrea and I drove up  to Toronto &amp;#8212; or Richmond Hill, one of its northern suburbs &amp;#8212; for World Fantasy 2012 on Friday. This was my second World Fantasy (the first being Columbus two years ago) and Andrea&amp;#8217;s first.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hotel(s):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We stayed at the Holiday Inn Express, one of the overflow hotels. That hotel itself was pleasant, albiet slightly incompetent. One elevator was out of order the entire stay. Andrea was trapped between floors in the second elevator on Saturday and had to be rescued by the fire department. I heard the same thing happened on Sunday, leaving guests to trundle down the stairs with their luggage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second overflow hotel was separated by a six lane highway under construction, and it looked like the sidewalks were torn up. Add to that the steep ramps  between the panel rooms and this spoonie fears there were some serious accessibility issues for those worse off than I.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The panels I attended:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Faith and Fantasy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Defining Urban Fantasy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They Call Me The Wanderer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bibliofantasies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Lexicon of Horror&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reality Made Fantastic, or Fantasy Made Real&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
  By and large, the panels were well-moderated (although there were frustrating exceptions). One thing I enjoy about the panels universally is the cross-pollination of ideas. I figured out how to fix three stories during panels, and gave me a new way of approaching stories that I&amp;#8217;m stuck on.
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
  The readings:
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Readings from EPIC, edited by John Joseph Adams: Aliette de Bodard,  Brandon Sanderson, Mary Robinette Kowal, and Patrick Rothfuss.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Readings from The _Mad Scientist&amp;#8217;s Guide_ to World Domination: David D. Levine and Genevieve Valentine&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
  All of the readings were well-done but the standout here is David Levine, who&amp;#8217;s reading of &amp;#8220;Letter to the Editor&amp;#8221; was absolutely stunning.
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
  The people:
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
  Ultimately, going to the con was about seeing friends, new and old. It was a gathering of half of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.inkpunks.com/&#34;&gt;Inkpunks&lt;/a&gt;. My Clarion classmates John Chu and Karin Tidbeck were in attendance, where we celebrated the launch of Karin&amp;#8217;s short story collection &lt;em&gt;Jagannath&lt;/em&gt;. There are so many other people I met, was reacquainted with, or caught up with. I couldn&amp;#8217;t begin to name names without leaving someone out. There were more that I missed, only saw in in passing, or didn&amp;#8217;t spend nearly enough time talking to.
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;#8217;s a certain buzz one feels on the heels of a con. Like a battery, warm and slightly overcharged, ready to be put to work.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ad Astra Wrapup</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2012/04/16/ad-astra-wrapup/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2012/04/16/ad-astra-wrapup/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My first Ad Astra is over, and I didn&amp;#8217;t completely embarrass myself. Huzzah!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ll admit to being intimidated at first, not knowing anyone. It&amp;#8217;s a good-sized local convention with a lot of history and people know already each other. What I finally realized, though, is that I just needed to _politely_ join in the conversation. Everyone was welcoming and, even better, assumed I was Canadian. I swear, I am in all but name.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I saw there was a writing contest &amp;#8212; 250 words based on a handful of prompts &amp;#8212; and I pounced on that. It let me meet a nice group of writers and editors that I wouldn&amp;#8217;t have had the opportunity to interact with at that level otherwise. I wrote the story Friday night (longhand first, then transcribed and edited), printed it out Saturday, and we received the results on Sunday. As these things happen, as I was sitting in the room waiting to talk to one of the judges, I had a breakthrough regarding flash that was soon confirmed by more than one of the judges. Flash fiction is like a single breath of air, and I&amp;#8217;d forced the reader to stop and gulp in the middle of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Harry Turtledove was one of the Guests of Honor. I sat in one of his panels, on creating viable cultures in world-building. Fascinating stuff. It evolved into conversation about historical research and alternate history between him and Ed Greenwood, which was awesome and worth the price of admission alone. My two favorite quotes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;That feeling of depth, that the world keeps going when the author stops looking.&amp;#8221; Harry Turtledove, talking about Lord of the Rings&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;The harder you make your reader work, the smaller your audience.&amp;#8221; Ed Greenwood&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s always great to meet people I&amp;#8217;ve only known online. After a previous near-miss, I finally got to spend a few minutes chatting with &lt;a href=&#34;http://shaydchara.dreamwidth.org/&#34;&gt;Shay Darrach&lt;/a&gt;. I also got to spend some time with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gabrielle-edits.com/&#34;&gt;Gabrielle Harbowy&lt;/a&gt;, who I met through a mutual friend. That lead me to the launch party for Dragon Moon Press, which was a blast. Debut author &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.leahpetersen.com/&#34;&gt;Leah Petersen&lt;/a&gt; read from her novel and did a fabulous job, as did &lt;a href=&#34;http://mariebilodeau.blogspot.ca/&#34;&gt;Marie Bilodeau&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sunday, I went to a panel on &amp;#8216;Revising and The Pitch&amp;#8217;. At least, I thought it was a panel but it was really an interactive two-hour workshop led by [Julie Czerneda][5] and it was awesome. In groups of three, we were given prompts and created &amp;#8212; and then revised &amp;#8212; a pitch for a story. Again, some good quotes came out of the panel, these regarding revision:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;As perfect as time permits.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;You have to learn to write to deadline; you may as well start by giving yourself one.&amp;#8221; Julie Czerneda&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Conventions have always left me with renewed spirits. Now, as I&amp;#8217;m gearing up to finish this novel, I feel like I have even more clarity. Not necessarily about the writing itself, but about in believing it can be done. It&amp;#8217;s easy to escape into short stories, because I&amp;#8217;ve written those, had those published. They&amp;#8217;re my safe place. A novel is a big, scary thing. That unknown feels less scary and more manageable right now, though, and that makes me very happy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[5]: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.czerneda.com/&#34;&gt;http://www.czerneda.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Going to Ad Astra 2012</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2012/04/09/going-to-ad-astra-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2012/04/09/going-to-ad-astra-2012/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So, due to timing of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.adamisrael.com/blog/2012/04/06/designated-driver/&#34; title=&#34;Designated Driver&#34;&gt;unfortunate circumstances&lt;/a&gt;, it&amp;#8217;s become rather convenient for me to go to [Ad Astra][2], April 13-15th. This will, notably, be my first convention since moving to Canada.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m relatively new to both country and the local genre community. I know there are a few members of Codex going and I recognize a few names from the panelist list (including Ed Greenwood, who was very kind towards a 19-year old me at Gen Con Milwaukee some years ago) but I&amp;#8217;m otherwise winging this. I&amp;#8217;m not exactly shy, but I&amp;#8217;m not going to impose myself on people I don&amp;#8217;t know, either.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are you going? Please, say hi!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[2]: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ad-astra.org/&#34;&gt;http://www.ad-astra.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Designated Driver</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2012/04/06/designated-driver/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2012/04/06/designated-driver/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We spent the better part of this week in Toronto &amp;#8212; an impromptu trip after receiving a call with some concerning medical news on Sunday night. So, for the first half of the week we’ve explored the inner workings of the Toronto hospital system. As someone who more or less grew up inside hospitals, I’ve made some observations:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Whoever is running the parking system is making a killing. We spent as much on parking as we did on food for two.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The profits from parking aren’t being spent on hospital IT, because I’m pretty you’d have to try pretty hard to make a system that failed in its communications that badly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The need for patient advocates is just as great, if not more so, here. I’m undecided if that’s because it’s a large city with a supposedly interconnected system or public health in general.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Out of respect for his privacy, I’m not going to go into too many details publicly. T- is ill (fuck cancer, so say we all). We took him for an outpatient biopsy Tuesday and suffered from a rare complication that landed him in the hospital overnight. That postponed a diagnostic test for an equally serious but unrelated condition scheduled for Thursday. Not the news that T- wanted to hear, but his doctors &amp;#8212; and there are many &amp;#8212; are working hard to get him healthy again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was thinking of heading to Toronto next weekend for [Ad Astra][1]. The last convention I went to was World Fantasy in 2010 and I’d like to start meeting some local-ish writer folk. The doctors rescheduled T-’s next test for the day after Ad Astra so that cleared me for con activity without guilt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[1]: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ad-astra.org/&#34;&gt;http://www.ad-astra.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brief World Fantasy wrap-up</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2010/11/04/brief-world-fantasy-wrap-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2010/11/04/brief-world-fantasy-wrap-up/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I went to my first World Fantasy Convention last weekend. I&amp;#8217;ve been to other conventions &amp;#8212; mostly smaller, regional conventions like &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.penguicon.org/&#34;&gt;Penguicon&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.windycon.org/&#34;&gt;Windycon&lt;/a&gt;, and a one-day stop at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wiscon.info/&#34;&gt;WisCon&lt;/a&gt; last year. I thought I knew what to expect. Boy was I wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, the new friends. So many of my friends converged upon Columbus that World Fantasy was, for many of us, our first face-to-face meeting. I met what seemed like half of my &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.clarionwest.org/&#34;&gt;rival Clarion&lt;/a&gt; class, all but one of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.inkpunks.com/&#34;&gt;Inkpunks&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&#34;http://operabuffo.blogspot.com/&#34;&gt;Wendy&lt;/a&gt;, we missed you dearly), and so many others from Facebook, Twitter, and LiveJournal. There were a handful of people that I&amp;#8217;ve admired from a distance and hoped to meet, and did, but will refrain from naming to save some face but I think you know who you are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were many that I already knew from previous conventions or workshops and I was lucky to catch up with some of them but not nearly enough of them. If I got pulled away during a conversation with you, sorry!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn&amp;#8217;t attend any panels but I did go to several readings, by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jimchines.com/&#34;&gt;Jim Hines&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.elizabethbear.com/&#34;&gt;Elizabeth Bear&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.kijjohnson.com/&#34;&gt;Kij Johnson&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.demimonde.com/&#34;&gt;M.K. Hobson&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.saladinahmed.com/&#34;&gt;Saladin Ahmed&lt;/a&gt;. I am super excited to read M.K. Hobson&amp;#8217;s debut novel &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0553592653?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=demimonde-20&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;creativeASIN=0553592653&#34;&gt;The Native Star&lt;/a&gt; (which I ran out of time to buy and get signed), and Saladin Ahmed&amp;#8217;s upcoming Throne of the Crescent Moon, which he read from (and the plot to borrow and clone his Kindle failed).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;#8217;t know if my experience mirrors anyone else&amp;#8217;s, if this is a certain stage that a writer reaches in their career, but one thing that happened to me on more than one occasion through the course of the convention was having a slush reader or editor recognize my name and introduce themselves, or comment on something I&amp;#8217;d submitted to them. I suspect, between a small but steady stream of submissions before and after Clarion that I&amp;#8217;ve leveled up and reached a new &lt;a href=&#34;http://jaylake.livejournal.com/2033417.html&#34;&gt;larval stage&lt;/a&gt;. Thank you especially to the person who took me around the bar and introduced me to a few folks. That meant the world to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was also business to be done. I put on my shiny new Creative Director hat and met with John Klima and Anne Zanoni for an Electric Velocipede business meeting. We have good things coming down the road, but right now you can get this awesome t-shirt, modeled by my friend Sandra Wickham for only $20:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; title=&#34;Short Fiction is Dead! Long Live Short Fiction!&#34; src=&#34;http://www.electricvelocipede.com/images/WICKHAM_small.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Short Fiction is Dead! Long Live Short Fiction!&#34; width=&#34;250&#34; height=&#34;336&#34; /&gt;][14]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What struck me about World Fantasy, in comparison with other conventions I&amp;#8217;ve attended, is how author-centric it is. At most conventions I&amp;#8217;ve been to the ratio of fan to author seems to run &lt;sup&gt;80&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;20&lt;/sub&gt;. I would guess that the numbers are reversed in this case. Everywhere I turned I was faced with a recognizable author. Almost everyone I spoke to was friendly and welcoming and hopefully none of the authors that I committed con faux pas with will remember (or hold it against me)!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Great weekend, great convention, great friends, great people. I can&amp;#8217;t wait for the next one. See you all next year in San Diego.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[14]: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.electricvelocipede.com/htm/tshirts.htm&#34;&gt;http://www.electricvelocipede.com/htm/tshirts.htm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>