<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Uncategorized on Adam Israel</title>
    <link>http://adamisrael.com/categories/uncategorized/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Uncategorized on Adam Israel</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© 2016 Adam Israel</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://adamisrael.com/categories/uncategorized/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>SFWA, Accessiblity and Diversity</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2014/02/19/sfwa-accessiblity-and-diversity/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2014/02/19/sfwa-accessiblity-and-diversity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There’s have been many kerfluffles involving the &lt;a href=&#34;1&#34;&gt;Science Fiction &amp;amp; Fantasy Writers Association&lt;/a&gt; (SFWA). The latest one begin when a former member began a petition over recent changes to the staff and policy of the organization’s flagship publication, the Bulletin. As a result of the current back and forth between factions, one member — a vocal minority — made the suggestion that the bar for membership should be raised. There’s a lot I could say about the current debate(s) going on, but I want to specifically address the idea of accessibility and diversity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Membership requirements, in general, are a good thing for an organization but should be recognized for what they are: exclusion. To what degree they exclude depends on the type of organization, its goals, philosophies, etc. Billing itself as a :&amp;#8221;professional organization for authors of science fiction, fantasy, and related genres”, one would assume the requirements are imposed to limit membership to anyone who has a professional interest in writing science fiction, fantasy, and related genres. Seems simple, but there’s always fine print.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The argument made by &lt;a href=&#34;2&#34;&gt;Brad R. Torgersen&lt;/a&gt; is that to be a more professional organization, SFWA needs to be more exclusionary, with the goal of eliminating “non-professional” writers, thereby raising rates enough money through dues that the organization can then use to hire administration staff and increase benefits to its members.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8230;impose an annual fiction writing income floor, below which members cannot fall without being placed on the inactive list, and therefore losing the ability to vote and/or participate in the org.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyone capable and willing to contributing $500 or even $1,000 U.S. dollars (or more) per year, is unlikely to be an amateur, or a pro-am.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will say, flat out, this is a bad idea. It&amp;#8217;s too exclusionary, and would decrease diversity. In fact, I would argue that SFWA should _lower_ its membership requirements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For active writers, there are two &lt;a href=&#34;3&#34;&gt;membership&lt;/a&gt; tiers: Active and Associate, both of which require prose sales at a minimum rate of $0.05/word. I would like to see a third tier, for writers who have not yet made a sale to a market able to pay those rates but have demonstrated a commitment to their craft, such as 3 sales at a semi-pro rate, or a cumulative revenue total. Give this tier some limited benefits, such as access to the forum and the bulletin, but not all of the benefits of the higher tiers. Perhaps offer it at a lower yearly rate to adjust for the different benefits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or, as has been pointed out to me on Twitter (thanks &lt;a href=&#34;4&#34;&gt;John&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;5&#34;&gt;Tim&lt;/a&gt;), use the Romance Writers Association (RWA) as a model or inspiration for how to include “non-professional” writers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By being less exclusionary, the organization will become more accessible to a diverse group of people across income levels, gender, orientation, social classes, etc. The organization would gain new, interesting, and previously under-represented voices in building a future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many writers toiling in the semi-pro ranks treat their work with the same professionalism, if not more so, than those currently qualified by SFWA definitions to call themselves such. The previous SFWA administration, under John Scalzi, and the new helmed by Steven Gould, have made great strides in improving the organization as a whole. It should be recognized just how much work it is to retrofit a monolithic steam engine with maglev. I expect the diversification will continue, but I would love to see a bigger change to allow.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hark, an update!</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2013/12/10/hark-an-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2013/12/10/hark-an-update/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hark! Inconsistent blogger has returned with news!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am pleased to announce that I&amp;#8217;ve sold &amp;#8220;Aye of the Hagfish&amp;#8221; to &lt;a href=&#34;1&#34;&gt;Goldfish Grimm&amp;#8217;s Spicy Fiction Sushi&lt;/a&gt;. It should be appearing online early 2014. This will be my second appearance in the magazine (the first being &lt;a href=&#34;2&#34;&gt;Control&lt;/a&gt;, in their debut issue).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m down to one story in circulation, and no new short stories finished this year, but for good reason! I finished the first draft, first read-through, and have begun developmental edits on the novel tentatively titled (but almost guaranteed to be renamed) &amp;#8220;Black Mirror&amp;#8221;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;#8217;re settling in for a long winter here at casa de Israel-Redman. The cupboards are stocked with tea, coffee, and non-perishable foodstuffs. Candles are lit, the fireplace channel is giving us the proper ambiance, and we&amp;#8217;re getting busy with the making of art and stuff. Come spring, we&amp;#8217;ll come out of our self-imposed hibernation with some fun new things to show off.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>111 Weeks</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2013/09/19/111-weeks/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2013/09/19/111-weeks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;To be exact, it&amp;#8217;s been 783 days since we filed for my Canadian Permanent Residence and I am happy to announce that it is official done. We have just walked out of the Immigration Centre in Windsor, Ontario, Social Insurance Number in hand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess this makes me an expatriate; an American Citizen permanently living abroad, which is kind of cool. I&amp;#8217;ve been thinking a lot about getting a tattoo to commemorate the experience. More on that later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;#8217;s been a lot of stress involved around this process, most notably the difficulty traveling back to the US. In a few weeks, when I have the official card in hand, I&amp;#8217;ll be free to cross the border without fear of being turned away and having to restart the immigration process. That&amp;#8217;s going to be a cathartic experience, finally going back to visit my family and friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that I&amp;#8217;m all official, we can start thinking about normal, grown-up things like buying a house, and getting all of our stuff out of storage back in Illinois.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clarion Write-a-thon</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2013/06/21/clarion-write-a-thon-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2013/06/21/clarion-write-a-thon-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It should be no surprise to anyone who knows me that the Clarion Writers Workshop is a thing near and dear to me. Attending the six-week workshop in 2010 was a milestone in my writing career. The annual &lt;a href=&#34;1&#34;&gt;write-a-thon&lt;/a&gt;, where writers commit to writing goals and ask friends, family,and strangers to pledge money to go towards funding the workshop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Saying &amp;#8220;please give money&amp;#8221; is something I do on very rare occasion, but this is something worthwhile. The Clarion Workshop is one of very few programs in the world for writers of genre fiction. Hundreds of students apply every year but only a handful get in. The instructors are among the most experienced authors in the field. Donations go to keeping the workshop running and supplying scholarships for students in need.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The write-a-thon runs for six weeks, along side the workshop in San Diego. It&amp;#8217;s an act of solidarity with this years class of writers and, as extra motivation, a public accountability of my goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year, I will spend the write-a-thon finishing my first novel. I&amp;#8217;ll be writing, by hand, 30,000 or so words, and transcribing the results into Scrivener along with the first 50,000. By the end, I will have a complete draft ready to be ripped apart, revised and rewritten. I&amp;#8217;ll even blog regular progress updates, which is more than I normally manage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you can &lt;a href=&#34;2&#34;&gt;sponsor me&lt;/a&gt;, one dollar or ten, you will have my gratitude and the satisfaction of knowing you&amp;#8217;re making a difference in the life of up and coming writers of science fiction and fantasy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Long Hidden: Speculative Fiction From the Margins of History</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2013/03/18/long-hidden-speculative-fiction-from-the-margins-of-history/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2013/03/18/long-hidden-speculative-fiction-from-the-margins-of-history/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve always liked stories about mundane things. Everyday people who might be ignored or worse, shunned &amp;#8212; garbage men, teachers, farmers, butchers, prostitutes, factory workers &amp;#8212; who find themselves in extraordinary circumstance and rise up to the challenge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The annals of history are filled with stories of the famous, the successful, the victors. Finding tales about those broke their backs to make a living is harder. It&amp;#8217;s not glamorous work. No one does it to become rich or powerful. They&amp;#8217;re born into it, forced into it, marginalized into it. Their stories deserve to be told, too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;1&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-903&#34; alt=&#34;dustbowl&#34; src=&#34;http://www.adamisrael.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/dustbowl.jpg&#34; width=&#34;640&#34; height=&#34;360&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;#8217;s a reason why &lt;a href=&#34;2&#34;&gt;Crossed Genres&lt;/a&gt; is of my favorite small presses. They have a long history of supporting diversity in it&amp;#8217;s many forms. Their latest project is &lt;a href=&#34;3&#34;&gt;Long Hidden: Speculative Fiction From the Margins of History&lt;/a&gt;, and it could use your help. They&amp;#8217;ve made their initial Kickstarter goal so the anthology, edited by Rose Fox (who I have tons and tons of respect for) and Daniel José Older (who I&amp;#8217;m sure is equally awesome), but still have a bit to go for their stretch goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They are nearing the next goal, to add another 10 stories/50,000 words to the anthology. The bigger the book, the more diverse it will be. A no-brainer, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think we can push it further. The third stretch goal will add original black &amp;amp; white art to every story, and if they make it to $50,000, the last stretch goal, they will produce a professional quality audio book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m all too familiar with Kickstarter fatigue. I feel it myself. This one is from an established publisher; &lt;a href=&#34;4&#34;&gt;Bart and Kay&lt;/a&gt; have been around for a while and have a proven track record behind them. If you&amp;#8217;re interested in the kind of stories they&amp;#8217;re telling, please give them a look.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>9</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2013/03/13/9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2013/03/13/9/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For months, we kept the animated film &amp;#8220;9&amp;#8221; (2009) on the DVR. I kept telling myself that I&amp;#8217;d sit down and watch it on the weekend, and inevitably being too distracted to do so. We came home a few nights ago and discovered the DVR had deleted several of the oldest recordings, including 9. That made me sad, because I really did intend on watching it soon. Kind of mad, I fired up Netflix and watched it that night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A rag doll that awakens in a post-apocalyptic future holds the key to humanity&amp;#8217;s salvation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;1&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter size-large wp-image-893&#34; alt=&#34;9characters-3208&#34; src=&#34;http://www.adamisrael.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/9characters-3208-1024x576.jpeg&#34; width=&#34;660&#34; height=&#34;371&#34; srcset=&#34;//www.adamisrael.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/9characters-3208-1024x576.jpeg 1024w, //www.adamisrael.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/9characters-3208-700x393.jpeg 700w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 660px) 100vw, 660px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Warning: spoilers ahead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;9 is a visually beautiful film with a haunting story of survival and redemption but at only 79 minutes, I don&amp;#8217;t know if it had enough time to fully develop the characters to their full potential.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My first reaction after watching was that I wanted to see it again. I want to get to know the characters more. Especially the ones that had the least screen time, like 2, who first discovers 9, but it whisked away in the jaws of the cat monster a short time later. Most of the story focuses on 9, the last of the dolls to awaken.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;#8217;s a subtlety to the storytelling, I think, that I hope will come through more in rewatching. The story of humanity&amp;#8217;s last chance of redemption, through the journey of its destroyer&amp;#8217;s soul, split into tiny rag doll representations, is a delightful example of my favorite kind of genre story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s not a perfect movie but it was enjoyable and made me think. I set out to Twitter immediately afterwards to find someone to talk to about it. That&amp;#8217;s a win in my book, at least.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A look back, and two steps forward</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2013/01/02/a-look-back-and-two-steps-forward/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2013/01/02/a-look-back-and-two-steps-forward/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The calendar has been replaced. Sins of the past tallied and new resolutions made. As far as years go, 2012 was mediocre on many fronts but there were a few bright moments that give me hope for what&amp;#8217;s to come.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Home:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we moved out of our house to help my Dad after surgery in May of 2009, I could never have foreseen the journey ahead of us. Alone or apart, we&amp;#8217;ve been staying with other people ever since. This past July, we moved into our first apartment together. Piece by piece, we&amp;#8217;ve made it feel like us. And hey, it&amp;#8217;s great to have a washer and dryer again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;#8217;re pretty content here. We&amp;#8217;ve begun building a small coffee shop where our dining room might have been, giving us a nice ambiance to write and create in. Our bookshelves are here (although half our books are still in storage in the US). Even the pets are cozy despite the smaller yard to roam in. We want to get a house, to build an even better space to do our thing in, but that will probably wait til next year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Immigration:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;#8217;re still waiting for my Permanent Residence to come through. We&amp;#8217;ve been expecting it &amp;#8220;any day now&amp;#8221; for several months, but the Immigration system here has been getting overhauled due to fraud and that&amp;#8217;s delayed everyone. Based on current estimates, we could hear something within the next two months. I have a renewed Visitor Record, my drivers license, a health card, and now an open work permit. It&amp;#8217;s comfortable, but it&amp;#8217;ll be better when the paperwork is done and I can cross the border again. I can&amp;#8217;t now for fear of being turned away trying to come back, which would cancel our application and send us back to the beginning of the line.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Friends:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I MISS YOU ALL. This was another year of not being able to travel far due to the above immigration issue. I got to see quite a few friends at World Fantasy in Toronto this year, which was awesome, but not enough. I expect that we&amp;#8217;ll be doing some travelling this year and hopefully that brings us closer to distant friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Health:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I&amp;#8217;m not completely out of the long, dark woods on the health front, I feel substantially better than I did a year ago thanks to a daily regiment of vitamins. Now that I have health care, I&amp;#8217;m getting all of the tests I need to rule out/verify various things and that will help with the feeling better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Family:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps the best news of the year came a few days after Christmas. We got the call that a kidney had been found for my little brother, who&amp;#8217;d been on dialysis for two or so years. He had the transplant last Friday (his third) and it went so well that we were Skyping the next morning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Writing:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sales-wise, 2012 was a light year. I sold &amp;#8220;&lt;a href=&#34;1&#34;&gt;Control&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#8220;, a revised version of one of my Clarion 2012 stories, to the nascent Goldfish Grimm&amp;#8217;s Spicy Fiction Sushi, and &amp;#8220;&lt;a href=&#34;2&#34;&gt;Man Out of Time&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#8220;, my Tesla story (and Clarion application story) to the Mad Scientist Journal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wrote a handful of new short stories and rewrote a few others. I meandered a lot and that shows with the lack of finished new work but I feel like the new words I do have are some of the best I&amp;#8217;ve written to date. The mantra for the new year is Finish Things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I slacked off on the submissions, especially in the last half of the year. I only have one story out now but it&amp;#8217;s a good one. I have high hopes that it will find a home eventually.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was also the year I started focusing on writing long. I restructured my first novel draft and am focusing on finishing that during the first half of the new year. &amp;#8220;Black Mirror&amp;#8221; now stands at 35k words.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Duotrope has gone paid as of this year. I have many feelings about that, which probably deserve a post of their own. I will not be subscribing, though, so this year will serve as an experiment in record keeping, among other things.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Con report: World Fantasy 2012</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2012/11/05/con-report-world-fantasy-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2012/11/05/con-report-world-fantasy-2012/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Andrea and I drove up  to Toronto &amp;#8212; or Richmond Hill, one of its northern suburbs &amp;#8212; for World Fantasy 2012 on Friday. This was my second World Fantasy (the first being Columbus two years ago) and Andrea&amp;#8217;s first.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hotel(s):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We stayed at the Holiday Inn Express, one of the overflow hotels. That hotel itself was pleasant, albiet slightly incompetent. One elevator was out of order the entire stay. Andrea was trapped between floors in the second elevator on Saturday and had to be rescued by the fire department. I heard the same thing happened on Sunday, leaving guests to trundle down the stairs with their luggage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second overflow hotel was separated by a six lane highway under construction, and it looked like the sidewalks were torn up. Add to that the steep ramps  between the panel rooms and this spoonie fears there were some serious accessibility issues for those worse off than I.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The panels I attended:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Faith and Fantasy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Defining Urban Fantasy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They Call Me The Wanderer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bibliofantasies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Lexicon of Horror&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reality Made Fantastic, or Fantasy Made Real&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
  By and large, the panels were well-moderated (although there were frustrating exceptions). One thing I enjoy about the panels universally is the cross-pollination of ideas. I figured out how to fix three stories during panels, and gave me a new way of approaching stories that I&amp;#8217;m stuck on.
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
  The readings:
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Readings from EPIC, edited by John Joseph Adams: Aliette de Bodard,  Brandon Sanderson, Mary Robinette Kowal, and Patrick Rothfuss.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Readings from The _Mad Scientist&amp;#8217;s Guide_ to World Domination: David D. Levine and Genevieve Valentine&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
  All of the readings were well-done but the standout here is David Levine, who&amp;#8217;s reading of &amp;#8220;Letter to the Editor&amp;#8221; was absolutely stunning.
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
  The people:
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
  Ultimately, going to the con was about seeing friends, new and old. It was a gathering of half of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.inkpunks.com/&#34;&gt;Inkpunks&lt;/a&gt;. My Clarion classmates John Chu and Karin Tidbeck were in attendance, where we celebrated the launch of Karin&amp;#8217;s short story collection &lt;em&gt;Jagannath&lt;/em&gt;. There are so many other people I met, was reacquainted with, or caught up with. I couldn&amp;#8217;t begin to name names without leaving someone out. There were more that I missed, only saw in in passing, or didn&amp;#8217;t spend nearly enough time talking to.
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;#8217;s a certain buzz one feels on the heels of a con. Like a battery, warm and slightly overcharged, ready to be put to work.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publication – “Man Out of Time”</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2012/07/09/publication-man-out-of-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2012/07/09/publication-man-out-of-time/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I may burst with glee. Tomorrow is &lt;a href=&#34;1&#34;&gt;Nikola Tesla day&lt;/a&gt;. Today, the &lt;a href=&#34;2&#34;&gt;Mad Scientist Journal&lt;/a&gt; published my secret history of Tesla, &amp;#8220;&lt;a href=&#34;3&#34;&gt;Man Out of Time&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#8220;. I even have word that someone on Facebook commented that they thought the story was a &amp;#8220;great idea to run a game/one-shot on&amp;#8221;. &lt;a href=&#34;4&#34;&gt;Katie Nyborg&lt;/a&gt; did the fabulous illustration for the interior.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How much does this mean to me? Well, Tesla is my hero more so than any other historical figure ever. While other kids my age were dreaming of cars and getting lucky, I spent my high school years in the electronics lab building things and wishing one of them were a Tesla Coil. To research this particular story, I bought both poetry that Tesla had translated and his transcribed journals from the time periods covered at Colorado Springs, where part of this story takes place. It was important to try to place the events as close to historical fact as possible before veering off, as well as understanding how Tesla might have handled himself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This story was also one of my Clarion application stories, if you&amp;#8217;re curious about that sort of thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clarion Write-a-thon Week 1</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2012/07/02/clarion-write-a-thon-week-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2012/07/02/clarion-write-a-thon-week-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;table width=&#34;95%&#34; cellspacing=&#34;0&#34; cellpadding=&#34;0&#34;&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td valign=&#34;top&#34;&gt;
      &lt;strong&gt;Sun&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;

    &lt;td valign=&#34;top&#34;&gt;
      &lt;strong&gt;Mon&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;

    &lt;td valign=&#34;top&#34;&gt;
      &lt;strong&gt;Tue&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;

    &lt;td valign=&#34;middle&#34;&gt;
      &lt;strong&gt;Wed&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;

    &lt;td valign=&#34;middle&#34;&gt;
      &lt;strong&gt;Thu&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;

    &lt;td valign=&#34;middle&#34;&gt;
      &lt;strong&gt;Fri&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;

    &lt;td valign=&#34;middle&#34;&gt;
      &lt;strong&gt;Sat&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;

    &lt;td valign=&#34;middle&#34;&gt;
      &lt;strong&gt;Total&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;

    &lt;td valign=&#34;middle&#34;&gt;
      &lt;strong&gt;Avg&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;

  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td valign=&#34;top&#34;&gt;
      582
    &lt;/td&gt;

    &lt;td valign=&#34;top&#34;&gt;
      171
    &lt;/td&gt;

    &lt;td valign=&#34;top&#34;&gt;
      309
    &lt;/td&gt;

    &lt;td valign=&#34;middle&#34;&gt;
      473
    &lt;/td&gt;

    &lt;td valign=&#34;middle&#34;&gt;
      91
    &lt;/td&gt;

    &lt;td valign=&#34;middle&#34;&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;

    &lt;td valign=&#34;middle&#34;&gt;
      783
    &lt;/td&gt;

    &lt;td valign=&#34;middle&#34;&gt;
      2,409
    &lt;/td&gt;

    &lt;td valign=&#34;middle&#34;&gt;
      344
    &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A little bit of a rocky week, especially Friday. Ideally, I&amp;#8217;d like to average 1,000 words/day. That&amp;#8217;d be awesome. Life creeps up, with unavoidable things like responsibility and sleep but I have a secret that I&amp;#8217;ll share with you. Lean a little close. That&amp;#8217;s it, just a little closer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s a little maddening to miss your goals. I live by my TODO list and I hate leaving things unfinished at the end of the day. You can&amp;#8217;t beat yourself up over it, though. Make adjustments, if it&amp;#8217;s a chronic problem (like overcommitment). In the end, though, it comes down to one thing:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#39;embed-youtube&#39; style=&#39;text-align:center; display: block;&#39;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sponsors&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you, thank you, thank you. Several of you have made &lt;a href=&#34;1&#34;&gt;donations&lt;/a&gt; totaling $175 dollars, blowing away my personal expectations for fundraising for Clarion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Statistics&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know Scrivener Fu. And I use Project Targets like a boss. I fell short on my word count last week but I know exactly what I need to do to stay on target. Week two is already ahead of schedule:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table border=&#34;0&#34;&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      Yesterday
    &lt;/td&gt;

    &lt;td&gt;
      Today
    &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;

  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.adamisrael.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/07/Scrivener-07012012.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-807&#34; title=&#34;Scrivener-07012012&#34; src=&#34;http://www.adamisrael.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/07/Scrivener-07012012.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;314&#34; height=&#34;260&#34; srcset=&#34;//www.adamisrael.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/07/Scrivener-07012012-300x248.jpg 300w, //www.adamisrael.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/07/Scrivener-07012012.jpg 314w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 314px) 100vw, 314px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;

    &lt;td&gt;
      &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.adamisrael.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/07/Scrivener-annotated.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-812&#34; title=&#34;Scrivener-annotated&#34; src=&#34;http://www.adamisrael.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/07/Scrivener-annotated.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;314&#34; height=&#34;260&#34; srcset=&#34;//www.adamisrael.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/07/Scrivener-annotated-300x248.jpg 300w, //www.adamisrael.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/07/Scrivener-annotated.jpg 314w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 314px) 100vw, 314px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;

  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td colspan=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
      Resetting my Session Target each morning, I know the minimum I need to write to maintain my pace, and any overage will work in my favor the next day.
    &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, I&amp;#8217;m quite happy with the way things are going. I&amp;#8217;ve been doing a fair amount of revising, which is slowing things down a little bit but it needs to be done, especially if I want to start tormenting beta readers with a draft of this monster later this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;text-decoration: underline;&#34;&gt;Write-a-thon goal:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img title=&#34;Clarion Write-a-thon goal&#34; src=&#34;http://picometer.writertopia.com/words=3354&amp;target=30000&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;162&#34; height=&#34;35&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clarion Write-a-thon: Day 1</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2012/06/25/clarion-write-a-thon-day-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2012/06/25/clarion-write-a-thon-day-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;1&#34;&gt;Clarion Write-a-thon&lt;/a&gt; began yesterday. I got some decent writing time in, despite a late start to the day and having to confront a would-be pervert attempting to flash his private bits at my favorite writing spot. I expect the first several days of writing to go slow as I revise the first chapter of the novel, trying to set the right tone and pace. The 25k words I wrote during last year&amp;#8217;s Nanowrimo are, I realize, mostly outline but do span the length of the novel. My task now is to fill in the gaps where I rush through sections I was unsure of and take my time getting through the rest. Also, sub-plot. I have it and now I need to make it work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My pre write-a-thon novel stats:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;2&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the first day&amp;#8217;s session, which saw me revise most of chapter one, scene one:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;3&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A good start. I don&amp;#8217;t feel at all nervous about my goals like I did during Nanowrimo. 30k words over six weeks is a little more reasonable for me, yes, but I&amp;#8217;ve also spent more time thinking through this story and figuring out its structure. I&amp;#8217;m definitely more of an outliner when it comes to novels, and the extra time I&amp;#8217;ve spent in planning is paying off now.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Around my desk</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2012/06/20/around-my-desk/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2012/06/20/around-my-desk/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There are now four days until the Clarion write-a-thon begins on June 24th, where I will continue work on my novel-in-progress and attempt to add 30k new words over the course of six weeks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s been a busy lead up to the write-a-thon because, frankly, I&amp;#8217;ve been unfucking a few things structurally. Writing a novel feels a bit like building an engine from scratch when your only previous experience is with watching someone else do it. Sure, you know the processes and what&amp;#8217;s important but putting all the pieces together in the right order is daunting. I&amp;#8217;ve finally worked out what this novel needs, though, and started reorganizing what I have&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s important that I have my workspace cluttered appropriately. Since I work and write in the same space, having familiar things around helps me slip into a creative mindset when I&amp;#8217;ve spent a day doing other things. Among them are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Books:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On Craft, Structure, and Career

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Steering the Craft, by Ursula K. Le Guin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Writing the Breakout Novel, by Donald Maass&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Booklife, by Jeff VanderMeer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Research, inspiration, or interesting and relevant:

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mistress of the Vatican: The True Story of Olimpia Maidalchini: The Secret Female Pope, by Eleanor Herman&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Complete Book of Baby Names, by Lesley Bolton&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Magick of Aleister Crowley by Lon Milo Duquette&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A Field Guide to Demons, Fairies, Fallen Angels and Other Subversive Spirits, by Carol and Dinah Mack&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dark History of the Popes, by Brenda Ralph Lewis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Book of Lies, edited by Richard Metzger&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Dictionary of Mythology, by J.A. Coleman&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Random things:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My favorite dice:

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 d4&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 d6&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 d10&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 d20&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A mostly empty package of chocolate-covered coffee beans&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pens, pencils, highlighters, and various art supplies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A bunch of notebooks filled with various notes and ideas.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A desktop-sized scratchpad&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Graph paper&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dueling &lt;a href=&#34;1&#34;&gt;Eleventh Doctor&lt;/a&gt; figures w/TARDIS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Headphones&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An empty bottle of &lt;a href=&#34;2&#34;&gt;Hakutsuru draft sake&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A lot of 3&amp;#215;5 index cards&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A cork board with notes from friends, inspirational quotes, and the &lt;a href=&#34;3&#34;&gt;Norse Crisis Flowchart&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A map of Chicago&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A map of the neighborhoods of Chicago&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You might pick up on a few things about what I&amp;#8217;m writing, based on what&amp;#8217;s around my desk. If you like dark urban fantasy, tattoos and magic, secret histories of the church, angels, demons, and a good story, all I can say is, maybe you and I should be friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;#8217;re thinking of participating in the write-a-thon, we have nifty teams this year to &lt;del&gt;egg you on&lt;/del&gt; encourage you when you&amp;#8217;re feeling crestfallen. Also, and alternatively, you can &lt;a href=&#34;4&#34;&gt;sponsor me&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;5&#34;&gt;one of the many&lt;/a&gt; writers. All the money goes to the Clarion Foundation, which uses the tax-deductible donations for things like student scholarships. It&amp;#8217;s not too late!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Free fiction in support of making Crossed Genres a pro-paying magazine</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2012/06/15/free-fiction-in-support-of-making-crossed-genres-a-pro-paying-magazine/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2012/06/15/free-fiction-in-support-of-making-crossed-genres-a-pro-paying-magazine/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve been a fan of Crossed Genres for a long time &amp;#8212; just shy of three years, which is &lt;em&gt;forever&lt;/em&gt; in Internet time. As a small press, they&amp;#8217;ve done a massive amount of good work publishing hundreds of authors (including myself) but Bart and Kay, proprietors, fell on hard times and were forced to turn to Kickstarter to keep CG alive. And made their goal of $4,000 in just 22 hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That says something, not just about the power of Kickstarter but about the reputation of Crossed Genres, and Bart and Kay. These are people worth supporting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With a week to go, they are trying to reach a second stretch goal of $14,000 (they are over $8,600 as I write this). If they reach this, not only will Crossed Genres the magazine be relaunched but it will become a professionally-paying venue and that is a significant thing. Bart and Kay already ran CG as such, but they will be able to compensate authors equally well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can already find plenty of examples of their work in the &lt;a href=&#34;1&#34;&gt;Cross Genre archives&lt;/a&gt;. In addition, I&amp;#8217;ve posted my story &amp;#8220;&lt;a href=&#34;2&#34;&gt;Dog Days&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#8220;, originally published in the April 2011 issue, online as a show of support. Go kick in a few bucks to show &amp;#8217;em that you care.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clarion Write-a-Thon</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2012/06/13/clarion-write-a-thon/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2012/06/13/clarion-write-a-thon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Clarion Write-a-thon starts on June 24&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt;, running parallel to the six week workshop I attended in 2010. While this summers workshop students toil away in San Diego, I’ll be one of many writers helping to raise awareness and solicit donations to a cause we believe in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is a write-a-thon, anyway? It&amp;#8217;s just like a walk-a-thon. But instead of walking, we&amp;#8217;re writing, and instead of making pledges per mile, we&amp;#8217;re making pledges per word, chapter, or story. Writers get support, encouragement and motivation, and the option of joining a team with a writing mentor! Those who care about the writers in their life get a way to show their support. And money is raised for a literally fantastic cause &amp;#8212; the Clarion Science Fiction &amp;amp; Fantasy Writers&amp;#8217; Workshop. All donations are made through The Clarion Foundation, a 501&amp;copy;(3) non-profit organization, EIN #20-3114945.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll also be one of the aforementioned mentors this year, as part of Team Weaveworld. The teams are a new thing with the write-a-thon this year, as a way to provide support and motivation for those who want it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During this years write-a-thon, I’ll be continuing work on my novel-in-progress. My challenge is to write at least 1,000 words/day, 5 days/week, with an ultimate goal of 30,0000 words over the six weeks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;d love to raise tons and tons of money for Clarion, because I passionately believe in what they do (and did for me). This is a no pressure pitch on my part, though. &lt;a href=&#34;1&#34;&gt;Pledge&lt;/a&gt; what you feel comfortable with, knowing that you have my utmost thanks and appreciation for donating to something dear to my heart.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Love affair with a house</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2012/06/10/love-affair-with-a-house/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2012/06/10/love-affair-with-a-house/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We built the house, my ex-wife and I, a decade ago. We poured our love into her foundations as we watched her bones rise over the snowy plains of Illinois. Vein and sinew were strung throughout and were covered by skin. A miraculous thing, to witness for the first time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A house is a thing but things have feelings, too. Ask any little girl who’s every owned a doll. My house took care of us, and I took care of her the best I could, clumsy hands and all. I never expected a thing would come to mean so much, even outlasting the love that created it, for a time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TIme passed and many things changed. I divorced and remarried. House starts to feel more like a home, as we finally paint walls that had been primer white since birth. Small touches, since our budget was limited, that made house feel warm and cozy and ours despite once being hers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Divorce eventually put house and I into an intangible position, though. The economy was tanking and the real estate market was leading the charge. We were being forced to part with house. I couldn’t afford to refinance and my options for selling were being stifled by the opposition. Swimming in debt not entirely my own and facing a raging storm of guilt, I chose the only option left: bankruptcy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This culminated a long, painful journey that saw us making the move to Canada to start anew. In the year and half since we walked away, I’ve heard whispers of gossip since then. I knew the bank was formally foreclosing, for example, even though my role in things was over. Their process server called me one January, first about the paperwork he needed to hand me and again when he visited the property, to warn me that he’d just called the fire department because water was gushing through the ceiling. Of drywall hanging off the walls. “If the bank tried to make a deal with you to take the house back,” he said, “run away.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like the scent of a old lover, she is forgotten until she is not. A year ago, I was back in town visiting my mom, and she came up in conversation. Of the tragedy of her loss, and the things that could have been. I knew I had to see her. I was so close, and I had to see for myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I stared through the front door, aghast at what she had become. The sign I purposely left hanging in the living room, “Welcome to the Israel’s”, was still there. Of the rest of the room, mold covered wall where drywall still clung to joist. Part of the ceiling was collapsed. The carpet was ruined. I circled the house with trepidation and climbed the back patio steps with dread. The kitchen and family rooms looked like a scenes from a nightmare. The light fixtures hung by wires and mold, mold, everywhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My next door neighbor was outside, with her children, enjoying the summer day. Curiosity, and something else, glimmered in her eyes as I approached. The story of the house that love built unfolded, still second hand, but the closest account I’m likely to ever get.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometime in December, after I’d officially moved to Canada, there was a mysterious incident. Someone broke into the house, stuffed the tub in the second floor bathroom with towels or rags, and turned the water on. The water overflowed, spilling down the stairs, saturating the walls, and eventually filling the basement. By the time the fire department arrived in January, the house I knew been drowned for some time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The story continued, of repeated break-ins, of fires being set, and of responders having to wear full hazmat suits to enter the house because of the epic amount of mold covering everything. The city was called out multiple times to deal with the unruly eyesore of a lawn. A group of neighbors had been trying to get the house condemned, to no success. The neighborhood feared what would happen if the house continued to sit, and contemplated if it would be better to let it burn and be done with it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In retrospect, I can only imagine what it must have looked like for my neighbors in the cul-de-sac, me returning after so much had happened. I apologized profusely, knowing that I didn’t cause this horrid corruption but unable to sever my feelings of guilty by association.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Love dies but is also reborn. I got a call from my mom this morning. She had breakfast with a family friend and, as they were catching up, an interesting discovery was made. J- had recently finished a painting job for a friend, for a house they bought and remodeled. They’d had to tear out her guts, replacing things like carpets and drywall. The kind of work that is a labor of love; an act of creation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, someone sees her cast in their own light, but I will always remember her the way she was.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>