<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Write A Thon on Adam Israel</title>
    <link>http://adamisrael.com/tags/write-a-thon/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Write A Thon on Adam Israel</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© 2016 Adam Israel</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://adamisrael.com/tags/write-a-thon/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Clarion Write-a-thon</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2013/06/21/clarion-write-a-thon-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2013/06/21/clarion-write-a-thon-2/</guid>
      <description>It should be no surprise to anyone who knows me that the Clarion Writers Workshop is a thing near and dear to me. Attending the six-week workshop in 2010 was a milestone in my writing career. The annual write-a-thon, where writers commit to writing goals and ask friends, family,and strangers to pledge money to go towards funding the workshop.
Saying &amp;#8220;please give money&amp;#8221; is something I do on very rare occasion, but this is something worthwhile.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clarion Write-a-thon Week 1</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2012/07/02/clarion-write-a-thon-week-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2012/07/02/clarion-write-a-thon-week-1/</guid>
      <description>Sun  Mon  Tue  Wed  Thu  Fri  Sat  Total  Avg    582  171  309  473  91   783  2,409  344    A little bit of a rocky week, especially Friday. Ideally, I&amp;#8217;d like to average 1,000 words/day. That&amp;#8217;d be awesome. Life creeps up, with unavoidable things like responsibility and sleep but I have a secret that I&amp;#8217;ll share with you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clarion Write-a-thon: Day 1</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2012/06/25/clarion-write-a-thon-day-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2012/06/25/clarion-write-a-thon-day-1/</guid>
      <description>The Clarion Write-a-thon began yesterday. I got some decent writing time in, despite a late start to the day and having to confront a would-be pervert attempting to flash his private bits at my favorite writing spot. I expect the first several days of writing to go slow as I revise the first chapter of the novel, trying to set the right tone and pace. The 25k words I wrote during last year&amp;#8217;s Nanowrimo are, I realize, mostly outline but do span the length of the novel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Around my desk</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2012/06/20/around-my-desk/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2012/06/20/around-my-desk/</guid>
      <description>There are now four days until the Clarion write-a-thon begins on June 24th, where I will continue work on my novel-in-progress and attempt to add 30k new words over the course of six weeks.
It&amp;#8217;s been a busy lead up to the write-a-thon because, frankly, I&amp;#8217;ve been unfucking a few things structurally. Writing a novel feels a bit like building an engine from scratch when your only previous experience is with watching someone else do it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clarion Diego Write-a-thon</title>
      <link>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2011/06/25/clarion-diego-write-a-thon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamisrael.com/blog/2011/06/25/clarion-diego-write-a-thon/</guid>
      <description>Two things make this upcoming Monday special: it marks the beginning of the Clarion (San Diego) Write-a-thon, and my one year anniversary of attending the Clarion Workshop. Clarion was a significant event in my life. One way I can give back is by participating in the write-a-thon and raising money to help the program that helped me.
For six weeks, we learned to write better (but still shitty!) first drafts. I wrote three new stories at Clarion, and revised two previously written ones.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>