<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Write A Thon on Adam Israel</title>
    <link>http://dev.adamisrael.com/tags/write-a-thon/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Write A Thon on Adam Israel</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://dev.adamisrael.com/tags/write-a-thon/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Clarion Write-a-thon</title>
      <link>http://dev.adamisrael.com/blog/2013/06/21/clarion-write-a-thon-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://dev.adamisrael.com/blog/2013/06/21/clarion-write-a-thon-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It should be no surprise to anyone who knows me that the Clarion Writers Workshop is a thing near and dear to me. Attending the six-week workshop in 2010 was a milestone in my writing career. The annual &lt;a href=&#34;1&#34;&gt;write-a-thon&lt;/a&gt;, where writers commit to writing goals and ask friends, family,and strangers to pledge money to go towards funding the workshop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Saying &amp;#8220;please give money&amp;#8221; is something I do on very rare occasion, but this is something worthwhile. The Clarion Workshop is one of very few programs in the world for writers of genre fiction. Hundreds of students apply every year but only a handful get in. The instructors are among the most experienced authors in the field. Donations go to keeping the workshop running and supplying scholarships for students in need.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The write-a-thon runs for six weeks, along side the workshop in San Diego. It&amp;#8217;s an act of solidarity with this years class of writers and, as extra motivation, a public accountability of my goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year, I will spend the write-a-thon finishing my first novel. I&amp;#8217;ll be writing, by hand, 30,000 or so words, and transcribing the results into Scrivener along with the first 50,000. By the end, I will have a complete draft ready to be ripped apart, revised and rewritten. I&amp;#8217;ll even blog regular progress updates, which is more than I normally manage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you can &lt;a href=&#34;2&#34;&gt;sponsor me&lt;/a&gt;, one dollar or ten, you will have my gratitude and the satisfaction of knowing you&amp;#8217;re making a difference in the life of up and coming writers of science fiction and fantasy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clarion Write-a-thon Week 1</title>
      <link>http://dev.adamisrael.com/blog/2012/07/02/clarion-write-a-thon-week-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://dev.adamisrael.com/blog/2012/07/02/clarion-write-a-thon-week-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;table width=&#34;95%&#34; cellspacing=&#34;0&#34; cellpadding=&#34;0&#34;&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td valign=&#34;top&#34;&gt;
      &lt;strong&gt;Sun&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;

    &lt;td valign=&#34;top&#34;&gt;
      &lt;strong&gt;Mon&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;

    &lt;td valign=&#34;top&#34;&gt;
      &lt;strong&gt;Tue&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;

    &lt;td valign=&#34;middle&#34;&gt;
      &lt;strong&gt;Wed&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;

    &lt;td valign=&#34;middle&#34;&gt;
      &lt;strong&gt;Thu&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;

    &lt;td valign=&#34;middle&#34;&gt;
      &lt;strong&gt;Fri&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;

    &lt;td valign=&#34;middle&#34;&gt;
      &lt;strong&gt;Sat&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;

    &lt;td valign=&#34;middle&#34;&gt;
      &lt;strong&gt;Total&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;

    &lt;td valign=&#34;middle&#34;&gt;
      &lt;strong&gt;Avg&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;

  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td valign=&#34;top&#34;&gt;
      582
    &lt;/td&gt;

    &lt;td valign=&#34;top&#34;&gt;
      171
    &lt;/td&gt;

    &lt;td valign=&#34;top&#34;&gt;
      309
    &lt;/td&gt;

    &lt;td valign=&#34;middle&#34;&gt;
      473
    &lt;/td&gt;

    &lt;td valign=&#34;middle&#34;&gt;
      91
    &lt;/td&gt;

    &lt;td valign=&#34;middle&#34;&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;

    &lt;td valign=&#34;middle&#34;&gt;
      783
    &lt;/td&gt;

    &lt;td valign=&#34;middle&#34;&gt;
      2,409
    &lt;/td&gt;

    &lt;td valign=&#34;middle&#34;&gt;
      344
    &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A little bit of a rocky week, especially Friday. Ideally, I&amp;#8217;d like to average 1,000 words/day. That&amp;#8217;d be awesome. Life creeps up, with unavoidable things like responsibility and sleep but I have a secret that I&amp;#8217;ll share with you. Lean a little close. That&amp;#8217;s it, just a little closer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s a little maddening to miss your goals. I live by my TODO list and I hate leaving things unfinished at the end of the day. You can&amp;#8217;t beat yourself up over it, though. Make adjustments, if it&amp;#8217;s a chronic problem (like overcommitment). In the end, though, it comes down to one thing:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#39;embed-youtube&#39; style=&#39;text-align:center; display: block;&#39;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sponsors&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you, thank you, thank you. Several of you have made &lt;a href=&#34;1&#34;&gt;donations&lt;/a&gt; totaling $175 dollars, blowing away my personal expectations for fundraising for Clarion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Statistics&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know Scrivener Fu. And I use Project Targets like a boss. I fell short on my word count last week but I know exactly what I need to do to stay on target. Week two is already ahead of schedule:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table border=&#34;0&#34;&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      Yesterday
    &lt;/td&gt;

    &lt;td&gt;
      Today
    &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;

  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.adamisrael.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/07/Scrivener-07012012.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-807&#34; title=&#34;Scrivener-07012012&#34; src=&#34;http://www.adamisrael.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/07/Scrivener-07012012.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;314&#34; height=&#34;260&#34; srcset=&#34;//www.adamisrael.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/07/Scrivener-07012012-300x248.jpg 300w, //www.adamisrael.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/07/Scrivener-07012012.jpg 314w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 314px) 100vw, 314px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;

    &lt;td&gt;
      &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.adamisrael.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/07/Scrivener-annotated.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-812&#34; title=&#34;Scrivener-annotated&#34; src=&#34;http://www.adamisrael.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/07/Scrivener-annotated.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;314&#34; height=&#34;260&#34; srcset=&#34;//www.adamisrael.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/07/Scrivener-annotated-300x248.jpg 300w, //www.adamisrael.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/07/Scrivener-annotated.jpg 314w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 314px) 100vw, 314px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;

  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td colspan=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
      Resetting my Session Target each morning, I know the minimum I need to write to maintain my pace, and any overage will work in my favor the next day.
    &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, I&amp;#8217;m quite happy with the way things are going. I&amp;#8217;ve been doing a fair amount of revising, which is slowing things down a little bit but it needs to be done, especially if I want to start tormenting beta readers with a draft of this monster later this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;text-decoration: underline;&#34;&gt;Write-a-thon goal:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img title=&#34;Clarion Write-a-thon goal&#34; src=&#34;http://picometer.writertopia.com/words=3354&amp;target=30000&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;162&#34; height=&#34;35&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clarion Write-a-thon: Day 1</title>
      <link>http://dev.adamisrael.com/blog/2012/06/25/clarion-write-a-thon-day-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://dev.adamisrael.com/blog/2012/06/25/clarion-write-a-thon-day-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;1&#34;&gt;Clarion Write-a-thon&lt;/a&gt; began yesterday. I got some decent writing time in, despite a late start to the day and having to confront a would-be pervert attempting to flash his private bits at my favorite writing spot. I expect the first several days of writing to go slow as I revise the first chapter of the novel, trying to set the right tone and pace. The 25k words I wrote during last year&amp;#8217;s Nanowrimo are, I realize, mostly outline but do span the length of the novel. My task now is to fill in the gaps where I rush through sections I was unsure of and take my time getting through the rest. Also, sub-plot. I have it and now I need to make it work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My pre write-a-thon novel stats:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;2&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the first day&amp;#8217;s session, which saw me revise most of chapter one, scene one:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;3&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A good start. I don&amp;#8217;t feel at all nervous about my goals like I did during Nanowrimo. 30k words over six weeks is a little more reasonable for me, yes, but I&amp;#8217;ve also spent more time thinking through this story and figuring out its structure. I&amp;#8217;m definitely more of an outliner when it comes to novels, and the extra time I&amp;#8217;ve spent in planning is paying off now.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Around my desk</title>
      <link>http://dev.adamisrael.com/blog/2012/06/20/around-my-desk/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://dev.adamisrael.com/blog/2012/06/20/around-my-desk/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There are now four days until the Clarion write-a-thon begins on June 24th, where I will continue work on my novel-in-progress and attempt to add 30k new words over the course of six weeks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s been a busy lead up to the write-a-thon because, frankly, I&amp;#8217;ve been unfucking a few things structurally. Writing a novel feels a bit like building an engine from scratch when your only previous experience is with watching someone else do it. Sure, you know the processes and what&amp;#8217;s important but putting all the pieces together in the right order is daunting. I&amp;#8217;ve finally worked out what this novel needs, though, and started reorganizing what I have&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s important that I have my workspace cluttered appropriately. Since I work and write in the same space, having familiar things around helps me slip into a creative mindset when I&amp;#8217;ve spent a day doing other things. Among them are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Books:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On Craft, Structure, and Career

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Steering the Craft, by Ursula K. Le Guin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Writing the Breakout Novel, by Donald Maass&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Booklife, by Jeff VanderMeer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Research, inspiration, or interesting and relevant:

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mistress of the Vatican: The True Story of Olimpia Maidalchini: The Secret Female Pope, by Eleanor Herman&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Complete Book of Baby Names, by Lesley Bolton&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Magick of Aleister Crowley by Lon Milo Duquette&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A Field Guide to Demons, Fairies, Fallen Angels and Other Subversive Spirits, by Carol and Dinah Mack&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dark History of the Popes, by Brenda Ralph Lewis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Book of Lies, edited by Richard Metzger&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Dictionary of Mythology, by J.A. Coleman&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Random things:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My favorite dice:

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 d4&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 d6&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 d10&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 d20&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A mostly empty package of chocolate-covered coffee beans&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pens, pencils, highlighters, and various art supplies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A bunch of notebooks filled with various notes and ideas.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A desktop-sized scratchpad&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Graph paper&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dueling &lt;a href=&#34;1&#34;&gt;Eleventh Doctor&lt;/a&gt; figures w/TARDIS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Headphones&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An empty bottle of &lt;a href=&#34;2&#34;&gt;Hakutsuru draft sake&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A lot of 3&amp;#215;5 index cards&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A cork board with notes from friends, inspirational quotes, and the &lt;a href=&#34;3&#34;&gt;Norse Crisis Flowchart&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A map of Chicago&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A map of the neighborhoods of Chicago&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You might pick up on a few things about what I&amp;#8217;m writing, based on what&amp;#8217;s around my desk. If you like dark urban fantasy, tattoos and magic, secret histories of the church, angels, demons, and a good story, all I can say is, maybe you and I should be friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;#8217;re thinking of participating in the write-a-thon, we have nifty teams this year to &lt;del&gt;egg you on&lt;/del&gt; encourage you when you&amp;#8217;re feeling crestfallen. Also, and alternatively, you can &lt;a href=&#34;4&#34;&gt;sponsor me&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;5&#34;&gt;one of the many&lt;/a&gt; writers. All the money goes to the Clarion Foundation, which uses the tax-deductible donations for things like student scholarships. It&amp;#8217;s not too late!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clarion Diego Write-a-thon</title>
      <link>http://dev.adamisrael.com/blog/2011/06/25/clarion-diego-write-a-thon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://dev.adamisrael.com/blog/2011/06/25/clarion-diego-write-a-thon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Two things make this upcoming Monday special: it marks the beginning of the &lt;a href=&#34;1&#34;&gt;Clarion (San Diego) Write-a-thon&lt;/a&gt;, and my one year anniversary of attending the Clarion Workshop. Clarion was a significant event in my life. One way I can give back is by participating in the write-a-thon and raising money to help the program that helped me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For six weeks, we learned to write better (but still shitty!) first drafts. I wrote three new stories at Clarion, and revised two previously written ones. I think it only appropriate that, for my inaugural write-a-thon, I rewrite and/or revise those stories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“Longwalkers”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“A Murder of Crows”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“Control”, was “I Love You, Good Bye, I’ll See You Soon” *****&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“Recycled Dreams”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“Cradle of Hope”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One or two additional stories TBD&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everyone who donates, if they so choose, will receive a postcard with story bits, doodles, or whatever I feel like adding to it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your name will also be listed in the acknowledgements of a limited edition ebook (see below).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;$10&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For ten dollars or more, you’ll receive the above, plus a limited edition ebook containing:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My application essay&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My application stories&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The handwritten, first and revised versions of my Clarion stories&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A one year retrospective, post-Clarion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Extra bonus material&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;$25&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyone who pledges $25 or more will receive, in addition to the ebook, &lt;a href=&#34;2&#34;&gt;tuckerization&lt;/a&gt; in a future story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;$50&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For $50 or more, donors will receive the ebook, tuckerization, and I will give you a detailed critique of a story, up to 7,500 words.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;$100&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are able to donate $100 or more dollars, you&amp;#8217;ll receive all of the above, my never-ending gratitude, and I will write a story based on prompts that you provide.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not only am I dedicating the next six weeks to raising money for Clarion, I will also put matching funds towards a scholarship for a 2012 Clarion student of my choosing. Please visit my &lt;a href=&#34;3&#34;&gt;write-a-thon&lt;/a&gt; page to make your pledge and drop a note &lt;a href=&#34;4&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; to let me know where to send your postcard. I&amp;#8217;ll be in touch for any other details for your reward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Already rewritten and in circulation, but you&amp;#8217;ll still get both versions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>